[
  {
    "title": "4.1",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "HASTEN to the store.",
          "answers": [
            "walk",
            "return",
            "wander",
            "drive slowly",
            "go quickly"
          ],
          "word": "HASTEN",
          "correct": "go quickly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The FAMINE began.",
          "answers": [
            "problem",
            "disease",
            "food shortage",
            "feast",
            "dust storm"
          ],
          "word": "FAMINE",
          "correct": "food shortage"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Fine EXCURSION.",
          "answers": [
            "visit",
            "holiday",
            "car",
            "journey",
            "recreation"
          ],
          "word": "EXCURSION",
          "correct": "journey"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was DERANGED.",
          "answers": [
            "crazy",
            "dirty",
            "clever",
            "unhappy",
            "late"
          ],
          "word": "DERANGED",
          "correct": "crazy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The expected DECREE.",
          "answers": [
            "understanding",
            "diploma",
            "shout",
            "order",
            "weather"
          ],
          "word": "DECREE",
          "correct": "order"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was LEGIBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "readable",
            "unclear",
            "clean",
            "sensible",
            "well-written"
          ],
          "word": "LEGIBLE",
          "correct": "readable"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The GRANDEUR of ancient Rome.",
          "answers": [
            "buildings",
            "heroes",
            "greatness",
            "legal system",
            "evil"
          ],
          "word": "GRANDEUR",
          "correct": "greatness"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She ENUNCIATES well.",
          "answers": [
            "dresses",
            "speaks",
            "hears",
            "draws",
            "writes"
          ],
          "word": "ENUNCIATE",
          "correct": "speaks"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They DECIPHERED the message.",
          "answers": [
            "decoded",
            "removed",
            "demanded",
            "discovered",
            "sent off"
          ],
          "word": "DECIPHER",
          "correct": "decoded"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MERCILESS men.",
          "answers": [
            "greedy",
            "brave",
            "powerful",
            "cruel",
            "kind"
          ],
          "word": "MERCILESS",
          "correct": "cruel"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were GLUTTONS.",
          "answers": [
            "dieters",
            "comics",
            "cowards",
            "overeaters",
            "drunks"
          ],
          "word": "GLUTTON",
          "correct": "overeaters"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Strange ESCAPADE.",
          "answers": [
            "crime",
            "adventure",
            "silence",
            "comedy",
            "trip"
          ],
          "word": "ESCAPADE",
          "correct": "adventure"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RANSACK the desk.",
          "answers": [
            "destroy",
            "replace",
            "thoroughly search",
            "clean",
            "throw away"
          ],
          "word": "RANSACK",
          "correct": "thoroughly search"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Made him FALTER.",
          "answers": [
            "jump",
            "wonder",
            "change",
            "hesitate",
            "retreat"
          ],
          "word": "FALTER",
          "correct": "hesitate"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISPEL their fears.",
          "answers": [
            "list",
            "cause",
            "disagree with",
            "fight",
            "drive away"
          ],
          "word": "DISPEL",
          "correct": "drive away"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do HASTY decisions take a lot of thought?",
          "word": "HASTEN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would people die during a FAMINE?",
          "word": "FAMINE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you moved to Japan, would that be an EXCURSION?",
          "word": "EXCURSION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are DERANGED people sometimes dangerous?",
          "word": "DERANGED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are DECREES usually funny?",
          "word": "DECREE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is this sentence LEGIBLE?",
          "word": "LEGIBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would GRANDEUR usually be a quality of a king's palace?",
          "word": "GRANDEUR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should an actor be able to ENUNCIATE clearly?",
          "word": "ENUNCIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it possible to DECIPHER a message sent in a simple code?",
          "word": "DECIPHER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a MERCILESS person take pity on others?",
          "word": "MERCILESS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are GLUTTONS usually overweight?",
          "word": "GLUTTON",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an ESCAPADE usually boring?",
          "word": "ESCAPADE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you fix a wobbly chair by RANSACKING it?",
          "word": "RANSACK",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If something FALTERS, does it go straight to the end without stopping?",
          "word": "FALTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can doubts be DISPELLED?",
          "word": "DISPEL",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "George HASTENED to his mother's bedside when he heard that she was dying.",
          "word": "HASTEN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was such a pleasant FAMINE that they decided to do it every week.",
          "word": "FAMINE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They went on a brief EXCURSION into the city one morning.",
          "word": "EXCURSION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He claimed he was DERANGED when he committed the crime and therefore wasn't responsible for his actions.",
          "word": "DERANGED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The principal DECREED that there would be no running in the school corridors.",
          "word": "DECREE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The teacher refused to accept homework which was not LEGIBLE.",
          "word": "LEGIBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He felt that nothing could compare with the GRANDEUR of the Rocky Mountains.",
          "word": "GRANDEUR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The founder ENUNCIATED the rules by which the organization would be governed.",
          "word": "ENUNCIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He had such poor handwriting that it was impossible to DECIPHER his letters.",
          "word": "DECIPHER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The author was upset by the MERCILESS criticism of his new book.",
          "word": "MERCILESS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was such a GLUTTON that he couldn't go two steps without tripping.",
          "word": "GLUTTON",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "On Halloween all the children joined in various harmless ESCAPADES.",
          "word": "ESCAPADE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "During the battle we RANSACKED the enemy with our bombers.",
          "word": "RANSACK",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I couldn't FALTER him for the way he acted; I would have done the same thing myself.",
          "word": "FALTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The senator tried to DISPEL the rumors that he was running for president.",
          "word": "DISPEL",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "HASTEN",
          "answers": [
            "rush",
            "hurry",
            "escape"
          ],
          "word": "HASTEN",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FAMINE",
          "answers": [
            "illness",
            "hunger",
            "starvation"
          ],
          "word": "FAMINE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXCURSION",
          "answers": [
            "journey",
            "digression",
            "surprise"
          ],
          "word": "EXCURSION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DERANGED",
          "answers": [
            "crazy",
            "mad",
            "bitter"
          ],
          "word": "DERANGED",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DECREE",
          "answers": [
            "law",
            "suggestion",
            "regulation"
          ],
          "word": "DECREE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LEGIBLE",
          "answers": [
            "real",
            "plain",
            "clear"
          ],
          "word": "LEGIBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GRANDEUR",
          "answers": [
            "sweetness",
            "riches",
            "brilliance"
          ],
          "word": "GRANDEUR",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENUNCIATE",
          "answers": [
            "declare",
            "laugh",
            "speak"
          ],
          "word": "ENUNCIATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DECIPHER",
          "answers": [
            "decode",
            "repeat",
            "understand"
          ],
          "word": "DECIPHER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MERCILESS",
          "answers": [
            "tremendous",
            "pitiless",
            "ferocious"
          ],
          "word": "MERCILESS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GLUTTON",
          "answers": [
            "fugitive",
            "gorger",
            "hog"
          ],
          "word": "GLUTTON",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ESCAPADE",
          "answers": [
            "fun",
            "excitement",
            "terror"
          ],
          "word": "ESCAPADE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RANSACK",
          "answers": [
            "pack",
            "hunt",
            "look for"
          ],
          "word": "RANSACK",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FALTER",
          "answers": [
            "stumble",
            "question",
            "hesitate"
          ],
          "word": "FALTER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISPEL",
          "answers": [
            "clear",
            "scatter",
            "hurt"
          ],
          "word": "DISPEL",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "HASTEN": {
        "word": "HASTEN",
        "phonetic": "(hAs'-:m)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to go quickly, speed, hurry; speed up \nNote the pronunciation. The _t_ is silent. \nTo HASTEN is to move or act quickly. \n\"The policeman HASTENED to the scene of the crime.\" \n\"He HASTENED to add that the price did not include the tax.\" \nTo HASTEN something is to speed it up, to make it go faster. \n\"The general tried to HASTEN the enemy's defeat by sending more soldiers into the battle.\" \nHASTE is quickness or speed, especially careless speed. \n\"In his HASTE to leave he forgot to take his jacket.\" \nSomething which is HASTY is done quickly, often too quickly. \n\"They decided to have a party at the last minute, and then made some HASTY preparations for it.\" \nOther forms of the word: HASTE, n. HASTY, adj."
      },
      "FAMINE": {
        "word": "FAMINE",
        "phonetic": "(fam'-:m)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an extreme shortage of food \nA FAMINE is a severe lack of food in an area. \n\"When it didn't rain for months, the crops all died, and FAMINE resulted.\" \nFAMINE is also occasionally used about severe shortages of other kinds of things. \n\"The charity was suffering from a FAMINE of contributions; no one was giving it any money.\" \nA related adjective is FAMISHED, which means _extremely hungry_, _starving_. \n\"After six days without food we were FAMISHED.\" \nOther forms of the word: FAMISHED,adj."
      },
      "EXCURSION": {
        "word": "EXCURSION",
        "phonetic": "(ek-sker'-zh:;in)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a short journey, pleasure trip; a digression \nSee _ex-_ under Prefixes. An EXCURSION is a short trip, usually made for pleasure as part of a group, with the intention of returning to the starting point. \n\"We had a pleasant EXCURSION to the country last weekend.\" \n\"They made their annual EXCURSION to the seashore.\" \nEXCURSION is also occasionally used to mean digression, a brief departure from the main idea or the main goal. \n\"We could never follow him when he went off on one of his EXCURSIONS into higher mathematics.\""
      },
      "DERANGED": {
        "word": "DERANGED",
        "phonetic": "(d:;i-rAnjd')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "crazy, insane \nTo DERANGE something is to put it out of proper order, to _disarrange_ it. As an adjective, DERANGED is used about people whose minds are not working properly, and means _insane_. \n\"The DERANGED man wandered across the highway in the middle of rush hour.\" \n\"The DERANGED killer said that he heard voices telling him whom to murder.\" \nThe most common wrong answer on the Pretest is _unhappy_. Great sorrow can sometimes cause a person to become DERANGED, but someone who is _unhappy_ is not necessarily insane. \nOther forms of the word: DERANGE,v."
      },
      "DECREE": {
        "word": "DECREE",
        "phonetic": "(d:;i-krE')",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an order, edict \nA DECREE is an order, given by a ruler, judge, or anyone in power, which is to be obeyed just like a law. \n\"The king's DECREE that property taxes were to be raised did not increase his popularity.\" \n\"We tried every way we could think of to get around Dad's DECREE that we were to be in bed by nine o'clock.\" \nDECREE is also a verb which means \"to give an order.\" \n\"The judge DECREED that the company had to rehire the two employees.\""
      },
      "LEGIBLE": {
        "word": "LEGIBLE",
        "phonetic": "(lej'-:;i-b:;il)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "readable \nSee _-able_ under Suffixes. The _leg_ part of the word is from a Latin word meaning to _read_. Something which is LEGIBLE is able to be read easily, is clear and plain. \n\"Her handwriting was small but LEGIBLE.\" \n\"The sign was so covered over with dirt that it was barely LEGIBLE.\" \nThe opposite of LEGIBLE is ILLEGIBLE, _not readable_. \n\"He signed his name so quickly that it was completely ILLEGIBLE.\" \n_Sensible_ is often chosen as the meaning of LEGIBLE. Something can be LEGIBLE, however, and not make any sense. \nOther forms of the word: LEGIBILITY, n."
      },
      "GRANDEUR": {
        "word": "GRANDEUR",
        "phonetic": "(gran'-j:)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "greatness, majesty, magnificence, splendor \nGRANDEUR comes from the word _grand_. GRANDEUR is greatness, impressiveness. The word is used about people and things. \n\"He admired the GRANDEUR of those ancient kings.\" \n\"The GRANDEUR of the magnificent scenery left us all in awe.\" \n\"His ideas had a certain GRANDEUR, but he never had enough money to carry them out.\""
      },
      "ENUNCIATE": {
        "word": "ENUNCIATE",
        "phonetic": "(i-nuhn'-sE-At)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to declare, proclaim, state definitely; pronounce, utter \nENUNCIATE is from the same Latin word as _pronunciation_ and _renunciation_. All have to do with speaking out or declaring something. ENUNCIATE has two somewhat different uses. One meaning is \"to state or declare in a formal way.\" \n\"Jefferson was among the first to ENUNCIATE the principles of representative government.\" \n\"He ENUNCIATED his grand theory of the universe.\" \nThe second use is simply to _pronounce_, to _utter_. \n\"He ENUNCIATED his words carefully.\" \n\"You must learn to ENUNCIATE clearly.\" \nIn both senses the basic idea is _speaking out_. \nOther forms of the word: ENUNCIATION, n."
      },
      "DECIPHER": {
        "word": "DECIPHER",
        "phonetic": "(di-sl'-far)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to make out the meaning of, decode \nOne meaning of the word CIPHER is a _code_. To DECIPHER something is to take it out of its code and make it understandable. See _de-_ under Prefixes. \n\"The army DECIPHERED the enemy's top-secret messages.\" \nDECIPHER also means \"to make out the meaning of\" something difficult to understand or read. \n\"He managed to DECIPHER the hastily written note.\" \n\"They DECIPHERED the faint writing on the cave walls.\""
      },
      "MERCILESS": {
        "word": "MERCILESS",
        "phonetic": "(mer'-S:)-lgs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "without mercy, showing no pity, cruel \nSee _-less_ under Suffixes. A MERCILESS person lacks MERCY or pity. \n\"The judge was MERCILESS in punishing criminals.\" \n\"The other boys laughed MERCILESSLY at John's attempt to sing.\" \n\"The boxer kept up his MERCILESS attack until his opponent was knocked out.\" \nThe opposite of MERCILESS is MERCIFUL, _full of_ MERCY. \n\"The father decided to be MERCIFUL and not punish his son.\" \nOther forms of the word: MERCY, n. MERCIFUL, adj."
      },
      "GLUTTON": {
        "word": "GLUTTON",
        "phonetic": "(gluht'-gn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a person who eats too much \nTo GLUT something is to overfill it, to supply it with more than it needs. \n\"There are too many television sets for sale; the market is GLUTTED with them.\" \nA GLUTTON eats too much; he stuffs or gorges himself at every meal and always wants more food than is good for him. \n\"He was a real GLUTTON; he always had six hamburgers for lunch.\" \nGLUTTON can also be used about a person who never seems to have enough of something besides food. A \"GLUTTON for punishment\" is someone who can take a lot of punishment without giving in. \nOther forms of the word: GLUT, v. GLUTTONY, n. GLUTTONOUS, adj."
      },
      "ESCAPADE": {
        "word": "ESCAPADE",
        "phonetic": "(es'-kÔøΩpAd)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an adventure, prank, wild experience \nESCAPADE is from the same root as _escape_, and an old meaning of ESCAPADE was \"an act of escaping.\" Today the word has come to mean \"an exciting adventure or action which goes against normal behavior.\" \n\"His trip to Tahiti was a surprising ESCAPADE for such an old man.\" \nAn ESCAPADE isn't usually evil, but it can cause trouble. \n\"His childish ESCAPADES usually cost us a lot of money.\" \n\"The foolish ESCAPADE on the boat almost caused them to drown.\" \nThe most common mistake for the meaning of ESCAPADE is _crime_. An ESCAPADE could be a _crime_, but it generally suggests something less serious."
      },
      "RANSACK": {
        "word": "RANSACK",
        "phonetic": "(ran'-sak)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to search thoroughly, rifle \nTo RANSACK something is to search through it thoroughly. RANSACK usually suggests that the searching is violent or disorderly, or for the purpose of robbery. \n\"He RANSACKED the house looking for his mittens.\" \n\"The jewel thief RANSACKED the vault.\" \n\"The invaders RANSACKED the city and took everything of value they could find.\" \nMany people think RANSACK means _destroy_, probably because of the violence often associated with RANSACKING."
      },
      "FALTER": {
        "word": "FALTER",
        "phonetic": "(fol'-t:)r)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to hesitate, waver, stumble, stagger \nTo FALTER is to waver or hesitate, to act uncertainly out of fear, weakness, or nervousness. \n\"He started the speech well, but FALTERED halfway through.\" \n\"She never FALTERED in her drive to become a successful doctor.\" \n\"The football team began to FALTER in the second quarter, and by the end of the game couldn't do anything right.\" \n\"His legs began to FALTER, and he knew he would never make it to the top of the mountain.\" \nThe most frequently chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is _change_, probably because FALTER looks like _alter_, which means to _change_."
      },
      "DISPEL": {
        "word": "DISPEL",
        "phonetic": "(di-spel'",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to drive away, scatter, clear away \nSee _dis-_ under Prefixes. The _pel_ part of DISPEL means to _drive_ or _push_. To _impel_ is to drive _forward_; to _repel_ is to drive _back_. To DISPEL is to drive _away_. DISPEL is used more about emotions and states of mind than about actual physical objects. \n\"His arguments DISPELLED any remaining doubts they had about the plan.\" \n\"The teacher DISPELLED any illusions he might have had about passing the course.\" \n\"Bill's reassurances couldn't DISPEL her feeling that someone was following them.\""
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.2",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Determined SKEPTIC.",
          "answers": [
            "doctor",
            "debater",
            "doubter",
            "judge",
            "believer"
          ],
          "word": "SKEPTIC",
          "correct": "doubter"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXPLICIT instructions.",
          "answers": [
            "necessary",
            "clear",
            "long",
            "confusing",
            "easy"
          ],
          "word": "EXPLICIT",
          "correct": "clear"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RURAL life.",
          "answers": [
            "double",
            "natural",
            "city",
            "lonely",
            "country"
          ],
          "word": "RURAL",
          "correct": "country"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Find some REFUGE.",
          "answers": [
            "happiness",
            "open space",
            "orphan",
            "rubbish",
            "protection"
          ],
          "word": "REFUGE",
          "correct": "protection"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "THERMAL power.",
          "answers": [
            "heat",
            "great",
            "gas",
            "air",
            "water"
          ],
          "word": "THERMAL",
          "correct": "heat"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Quick GESTURE.",
          "answers": [
            "smile",
            "look",
            "handshake",
            "motion",
            "reply"
          ],
          "word": "GESTURE",
          "correct": "motion"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "What will you WAGER?",
          "answers": [
            "promise",
            "attack",
            "bet",
            "win",
            "earn"
          ],
          "word": "WAGER",
          "correct": "bet"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INQUISITIVE people.",
          "answers": [
            "talkative",
            "bored",
            "greedy",
            "curious",
            "friendly"
          ],
          "word": "INQUISITIVE",
          "correct": "curious"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was UNSAVORY.",
          "answers": [
            "secret",
            "forgotten",
            "fascinating",
            "distasteful",
            "useless"
          ],
          "word": "UNSAVORY",
          "correct": "distasteful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They EMERGED.",
          "answers": [
            "came out",
            "began",
            "met",
            "went in",
            "left"
          ],
          "word": "EMERGE",
          "correct": "came out"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ADJACENT houses.",
          "answers": [
            "similar",
            "new",
            "neighboring",
            "distant",
            "empty"
          ],
          "word": "ADJACENT",
          "correct": "neighboring"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REPEL the enemy.",
          "answers": [
            "drive back",
            "beg",
            "fight",
            "forgive",
            "seek out"
          ],
          "word": "REPEL",
          "correct": "drive back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Wanted to SURMOUNT it.",
          "answers": [
            "increase",
            "end",
            "give up on",
            "avoid",
            "overcome"
          ],
          "word": "SURMOUNT",
          "correct": "overcome"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To EXECUTE the commands.",
          "answers": [
            "laugh at",
            "understand",
            "prepare for",
            "carry out",
            "disobey"
          ],
          "word": "EXECUTE",
          "correct": "carry out"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To RATIFY it.",
          "answers": [
            "refuse",
            "change",
            "admire",
            "improve",
            "approve"
          ],
          "word": "RATIFY",
          "correct": "approve"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Is it hard to trick a SKEPTIC?",
          "word": "SKEPTIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it easy to be confused by EXPLICIT directions?",
          "word": "EXPLICIT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a RURAL area likely to be full of factories and traffic?",
          "word": "RURAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an open field a REFUGE in a heavy rain?",
          "word": "REFUGE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is THERMAL underwear supposed to keep you warm?",
          "word": "THERMAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you have to use your hand to make a GESTURE?",
          "word": "GESTURE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you lose money by WAGERING?",
          "word": "WAGER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a newspaper reporter supposed to be INQUISITIVE?",
          "word": "INQUISITIVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people like to do business with UNSAVORY characters?",
          "word": "UNSAVORY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does the sun EMERGE when it goes behind a cloud?",
          "word": "EMERGE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is Los Angeles ADJACENT to New York?",
          "word": "ADJACENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would an insect REPELLENT attract bugs?",
          "word": "REPEL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you usually SURMOUNT an obstacle by ignoring it?",
          "word": "SURMOUNT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a person be EXECUTED?",
          "word": "EXECUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does RATIFYING a decision show that it displeases you?",
          "word": "RATIFY",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Ever since he lied to me, I am inclined to be SKEPTICAL of anything he says.",
          "word": "SKEPTIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Alice was quite EXPLICIT about her complaints. She told everyone exactly what was wrong.",
          "word": "EXPLICIT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He felt RURAL whenever he was by himself for very long.",
          "word": "RURAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She thought of her home as a place of REFUGE from the troubles of the world.",
          "word": "REFUGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A glider depends on rising THERMAL air currents to keep it up.",
          "word": "THERMAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "With a thumbs-down GESTURE he showed his disapproval of their plan.",
          "word": "GESTURE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bill refused to WAGER on the horse race; he said he never won bets like that.",
          "word": "WAGER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He's very INQUISITIVE: making money is all he thinks about.",
          "word": "INQUISITIVE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "People came from miles around just to get a taste of her UNSAVORY cooking.",
          "word": "UNSAVORY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The bear EMERGED from the cave after hibernating all winter.",
          "word": "EMERGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They sat in ADJACENT seats in the hall so that they could talk to each other.",
          "word": "ADJACENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The defending army was prepared to REPEL the invaders.",
          "word": "REPEL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She SURMOUNTED a painting over the fireplace.",
          "word": "SURMOUNT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": " The idea was good, but they EXECUTED it so poorly that the whole plan failed.",
          "word": "EXECUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The teacher RATIFIED us that we had passed the exam.",
          "word": "RATIFY",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "SKEPTIC",
          "answers": [
            "doubter",
            "defender",
            "questioner"
          ],
          "word": "SKEPTIC",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXPLICIT",
          "answers": [
            "open",
            "necessary",
            "definite"
          ],
          "word": "EXPLICIT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RURAL",
          "answers": [
            "rustic",
            "agricultural",
            "identical"
          ],
          "word": "RURAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REFUGE",
          "answers": [
            "prison",
            "safety",
            "shelter"
          ],
          "word": "REFUGE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "THERMAL",
          "answers": [
            "hot",
            "warm",
            "cool"
          ],
          "word": "THERMAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GESTURE",
          "answers": [
            "point",
            "nod",
            "stare"
          ],
          "word": "GESTURE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "WAGER",
          "answers": [
            "card game",
            "circus",
            "horse race"
          ],
          "word": "WAGER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INQUISITIVE",
          "answers": [
            "nosy",
            "mysterious",
            "prying"
          ],
          "word": "INQUISITIVE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UNSAVORY",
          "answers": [
            "fat",
            "evil",
            "rotten"
          ],
          "word": "UNSAVORY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EMERGE",
          "answers": [
            "start",
            "appear",
            "arise"
          ],
          "word": "EMERGE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ADJACENT",
          "answers": [
            "close",
            "nearby",
            "identical"
          ],
          "word": "ADJACENT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REPEL",
          "answers": [
            "defeat",
            "disgust",
            "threaten"
          ],
          "word": "REPEL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SURMOUNT",
          "answers": [
            "give up",
            "go over",
            "get past"
          ],
          "word": "SURMOUNT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXECUTE",
          "answers": [
            "achieve",
            "perform",
            "accept"
          ],
          "word": "EXECUTE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RATIFY",
          "answers": [
            "improve",
            "confirm",
            "authorize"
          ],
          "word": "RATIFY",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "SKEPTIC": {
        "word": "SKEPTIC",
        "phonetic": "(skep'-tik)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a doubter, unbeliever \nA SKEPTIC is inclined to question the value or truth of things. He doubts everything, and trusts or believes in nothing. \n\"He was a SKEPTIC when it came to believing the promises of politicians.\" \n\"She was unable to convince those SKEPTICS that she really did mean what she said.\" \nThe adjective form is SKEPTICAL, which means _doubting_. \"She was very SKEPTICAL about the plan's chances for success.\" \n\"He was SKEPTICAL of his brother's loyalty.\" \nOther forms of the word: SKEPTICAL, adj. SKEPTICISM, n. \nUsage: SKEPTIC is sometimes spelled _sceptic_."
      },
      "EXPLICIT": {
        "word": "EXPLICIT",
        "phonetic": "(ik-splis'-it)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "clear, clearly expressed, definite, outspoken \nSee _ex-_ under Prefixes. The root meaning of EXPLICIT is _folded out_. Something which is EXPLICIT is open to view like a piece of paper all folded out. EXPLICIT instructions are fully given and leave no room for misunderstanding. An EXPLICIT belief is clearly developed and fully understood. A person who is EXPLICIT says exactly what he means. \n\"He gave us EXPLICIT orders not to leave the room.\" \n\"She was EXPLICIT about the need for complete obedience.\" \nThe opposite of EXPLICIT is _implicit_. Something which is _implicit_ is not clearly expressed; it is only hinted at or implied. \n\"Although he didn't actually say so, we thought it was _implicit_ that he agreed with us.\""
      },
      "RURAL": {
        "word": "RURAL",
        "phonetic": "(rur'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "country, rustic \nRURAL means \"having to do with the country\"—as opposed to the city. \n\"The mountains and lakes in the RURAL areas of the state attract many visitors from the cities.\" \n\"Is the RURAL population growing or declining?\" \n\"I prefer RURAL life to city life. People are much friendlier in the country.\" \nMost people who misunderstand this word confuse it with its opposite, and think it means _city_."
      },
      "REFUGE": {
        "word": "REFUGE",
        "phonetic": "(ref'-yUj)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "protection, shelter \nREFUGE is shelter or protection from something that threatens or troubles you. \n\"We found REFUGE from the storm in an old barn.\" \n\"He sought REFUGE from his worries in music.\" \nA REFUGE is also the place that gives a person or animal shelter. \n\"The house was a REFUGE for stray cats and dogs.\" \nA REFUGEE is a person who flees his own country because of war, political trouble, or the like, and seeks safety in another country. \n\"Thousands of REFUGEES poured across the border when the war broke out.\" \nOther forms of the word: REFUGEE, n."
      },
      "THERMAL": {
        "word": "THERMAL",
        "phonetic": "(ther'-mÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "of heat, caused by heat \nSee _-al_ under Suffixes. The _therm_ part of THERMAL means _heat_; it is also found in the word _thermometer_, which is an instrument that measures how hot something is. THERMAL means \"having to do with heat or temperature.\" \n\"They used the hot water of the THERMAL springs as a source of THERMAL power.\""
      },
      "GESTURE": {
        "word": "GESTURE",
        "phonetic": "(jes'-chÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a movement of the body, motion \nA GESTURE is a movement of a part of the body, usually the hands or the head, which shows a thought, idea, or feeling. \n\"He reached out his hand in a GESTURE of friendship.\" \n\"He had lost his voice, so he had to get his idea across by means of GESTURES.\" \nGESTURE can also be used in a general way to indicate an action done for show or as a symbol of something else. \n\"In a GESTURE of protest the workers refused to speak to their boss.\" \n\"She offered to buy the car for him, but it was a meaningless GESTURE, since she knew he wouldn't let her.\" \n_Reply_ is the most commonly chosen incorrect answer. A GESTURE can be used as a _reply_ to someone, but it is used in many other situations as well."
      },
      "WAGER": {
        "word": "WAGER",
        "phonetic": "(wA'-jÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to bet \nWAGER means to _bet_. \n\"I WAGER that he will be successful in his new job.\" \n\"How much do you have to WAGER to stay in the poker game?\" \nWAGER is also a noun meaning a _bet_. \n\"He placed a WAGER of five dollars on the horse race.\" \n\"Each day she made a WAGER with herself that she would get to work on time.\" \nMany people think WAGER means to _earn_. You may make money as the result of a WAGER, but you _earn_ money by working, not by betting."
      },
      "INQUISITIVE": {
        "word": "INQUISITIVE",
        "phonetic": "(in-kwiz'-ÔøΩ-tiv)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "curious, prying \nINQUISITIVE is related to the word _inquire_, which means to _ask_. Someone who is INQUISITIVE likes to inquire about things. \n\"He had an INQUISITIVE mind. He was curious about the reasons for everything.\" \nThe word is often used in a bad sense, about someone who is too curious about the affairs of other people. \n\"She answered his questions until she thought he was becoming too INQUISITIVE, and then she refused to say any more.\" \n\"He pulled the shade so that his experiment would be safe from the eyes of INQUISITIVE reporters.\" \n_Friendly_ and _talkative_ are both often picked as the meaning of INQUISITIVE. An INQUISITIVE person might have both these qualities, but his basic characteristic would be _curiosity_."
      },
      "UNSAVORY": {
        "word": "UNSAVORY",
        "phonetic": "(uhn-sA'-vÔøΩrE)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "distasteful, nasty, disgusting \nSomething which is SAVORY is pleasant tasting or smelling. \n\"He could smell the SAVORY odor of the apple pie as it cooked.\" \nUNSAVORY means _not savory_, _distasteful_, _disgusting_. See _un-_ under Prefixes. \n\"She felt sick the first time she had the UNSAVORY task of cleaning an infected wound.\" \nThe word is usually used about people or things that are morally disgusting. \n\"He was led astray by UNSAVORY companions.\" \n\"There is a great deal of truth in the UNSAVORY stories about him.\""
      },
      "EMERGE": {
        "word": "EMERGE",
        "phonetic": "(i-merj')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to come out, come into view; to become known \nIn its original meaning, EMERGE was an exact opposite of _submerge_. When you EMERGE you rise up out of the water; when you _submerge_ you sink or plunge beneath the surface of the water. The word now means to _come out_ or _come into view_ the way something does when it rises from water. See _ex-_ under Prefixes. \n\"The men EMERGED from the cave.\" \n\"The sun EMERGED from behind a cloud.\" \nEMERGE can also be used with ideas or facts or problems, in the sense of to _appear_, to _become known_. \n\"No new solutions EMERGED during the discussion.\" \nThe most commonly chosen incorrect answer for EMERGED on the Pretest is _went in_, which is an exact opposite."
      },
      "ADJACENT": {
        "word": "ADJACENT",
        "phonetic": "(Q-jA'-sÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "nearby, neighboring \nWhen two things are ADJACENT to each other they are nearby; they are close together but do not necessarily touch or have a common border. \n\"The Andersons would like to reserve two ADJACENT rooms, one for themselves and one for their three children.\" \n\"We were able to rent a parking space in the lot ADJACENT to our building.\" \n\"The man in the ADJACENT apartment always left his door wide open.\" \nIn geometry, ADJACENT angles do indeed touch each other, having one side in common."
      },
      "REPEL": {
        "word": "REPEL",
        "phonetic": "(ri-pel')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to drive back, drive away; to cause distaste \nSee _re-_ under Prefixes. To REPEL someone is to drive him back or away. The word is used about a person or group fighting off an attack. \n\"We REPELLED the robbers by throwing rocks at them.\" \n\"The mayor REPELLED their attempt to force him out of office.\" \nREPEL also means \"to cause distaste\"—that is, to force someone away by being offensive. \n\"His dirty appearance REPELS many people.\" \n\"I am REPELLED by the idea of telling a lie.\" \nThe adjective from REPEL is REPELLENT, which means \"tending to REPEL or drive away,\" _disgusting_. \n\"Many people find this movie REPELLENT.\" \n_Fight_ is the most common mistake made on the Pretest. _Fight_ would often be used in the same situation as REPEL, but you could _fight_ someone without managing to REPEL him. \nOther forms of the word: REPELLENT, adj., n."
      },
      "SURMOUNT": {
        "word": "SURMOUNT",
        "phonetic": "(sÔøΩr-mownt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to overcome, rise above, get over \nThe prefix _sur-_ means _over_. The _mount_ part of the word SURMOUNT is related to _mountain_. To SURMOUNT something is to climb over or rise above it. The word is especially applied to overcoming obstacles and problems. \n\"She SURMOUNTED every difficulty on her way to becoming a doctor.\" \n\"He managed to SURMOUNT the temptation to eat another piece of pie.\" \n\"It is difficult to SURMOUNT the lack of a good education.\""
      },
      "EXECUTE": {
        "word": "EXECUTE",
        "phonetic": "(ek'-si-kyUt",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to carry out, fulfill, put into effect; to put to death \nTo EXECUTE something is to carry it out as you have planned or as you have been told to do. \n\"They EXECUTED the plan perfectly\"—that is, they carried it out with no mistakes. \n\"They EXECUTED the officer's orders without a complaint.\" \n\"The football team tried to EXECUTE a trick plan.\" \nThe most common use of EXECUTE is to EXECUTE a prisoner, to carry out a legal sentence of death on someone. \n\"They EXECUTED the criminal because of the brutal murders he had committed.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXECUTION, n."
      },
      "RATIFY": {
        "word": "RATIFY",
        "phonetic": "(rat'-ÔøΩ-fl)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to approve, confirm, make valid \nTo RATIFY something is to confirm it or make it legal by giving your approval. The word is used about laws, treaties, agreements, actions, and so on. \n\"Congress will have to RATIFY the treaty before it will go into effect.\" \n\"The union members refused to RATIFY the contract with the company.\" \nOther forms of the word: RATIFICATION, n."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.3",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "They were all APPRENTICES.",
          "answers": [
            "carpenters",
            "experts",
            "printers",
            "beginners",
            "servants"
          ],
          "word": "APPRENTICE",
          "correct": "beginners"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was a NOMAD.",
          "answers": [
            "native",
            "knight",
            "farmer",
            "wanderer",
            "settler"
          ],
          "word": "NOMAD",
          "correct": "wanderer"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Hard to REPRESS.",
          "answers": [
            "hold back",
            "speak to",
            "make right",
            "start",
            "criticize"
          ],
          "word": "REPRESS",
          "correct": "hold back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ILLUMINATE the room.",
          "answers": [
            "destroy",
            "darken",
            "clean up",
            "find",
            "light up"
          ],
          "word": "ILLUMINATE",
          "correct": "light up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We must be PUNCTUAL.",
          "answers": [
            "prepared",
            "cruel",
            "polite",
            "early",
            "prompt"
          ],
          "word": "PUNCTUAL",
          "correct": "prompt"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Aware of the SURVEILLANCE.",
          "answers": [
            "secret talks",
            "expedition",
            "close watch",
            "suspicion",
            "vehicle"
          ],
          "word": "SURVEILLANCE",
          "correct": "close watch"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He FABRICATED the whole story.",
          "answers": [
            "illustrated",
            "made up",
            "listened to",
            "lived through",
            "retold"
          ],
          "word": "FABRICATE",
          "correct": "made up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A typical FELON.",
          "answers": [
            "criminal",
            "young man",
            "old person",
            "minister",
            "prisoner"
          ],
          "word": "FELON",
          "correct": "criminal"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Seems PERPETUAL.",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "dead",
            "old",
            "endless",
            "excellent"
          ],
          "word": "PERPETUAL",
          "correct": "endless"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The REVOLT began.",
          "answers": [
            "trouble",
            "spinning",
            "journey",
            "rebellion",
            "victory"
          ],
          "word": "REVOLT",
          "correct": "rebellion"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Visited the METROPOLIS.",
          "answers": [
            "great city",
            "old fortress",
            "village",
            "tall building",
            "center"
          ],
          "word": "METROPOLIS",
          "correct": "great city"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Sat in the NOOK.",
          "answers": [
            "middle",
            "stream",
            "attic",
            "bedroom",
            "corner"
          ],
          "word": "NOOK",
          "correct": "corner"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "You must REFRAIN.",
          "answers": [
            "continue",
            "change",
            "hold back",
            "give in",
            "hold on"
          ],
          "word": "REFRAIN",
          "correct": "hold back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The town was DEVASTATED.",
          "answers": [
            "divided",
            "attacked",
            "saved",
            "surrounded",
            "ruined"
          ],
          "word": "DEVASTATE",
          "correct": "ruined"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The water RECEDED.",
          "answers": [
            "entered",
            "stopped",
            "moved back",
            "came close",
            "disappeared"
          ],
          "word": "RECEDE",
          "correct": "moved back"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Would an APPRENTICE work by himself?",
          "word": "APPRENTICE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a NOMAD build a mansion?",
          "word": "NOMAD",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is someone who is shouting and screaming REPRESSING his anger?",
          "word": "REPRESS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do logs burning in a fireplace help to ILLUMINATE a room?",
          "word": "ILLUMINATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would you be PUNCTUAL if you were half an hour late?",
          "word": "PUNCTUAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people like to be kept under SURVEILLANCE?",
          "word": "SURVEILLANCE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do liars FABRICATE the stories they tell?",
          "word": "FABRICATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would kidnapping be a FELONY?",
          "word": "FELON",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does PERPETUAL motion ever stop?",
          "word": "PERPETUAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can people REVOLT against laws?",
          "word": "REVOLT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is Los Angeles a METROPOLIS?",
          "word": "METROPOLIS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could you play a baseball game in a NOOK?",
          "word": "NOOK",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people REFRAIN from jumping in front of a speeding car?",
          "word": "REFRAIN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can an atomic bomb DEVASTATE a region?",
          "word": "DEVASTATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do objects appear to get larger as they RECEDE?",
          "word": "RECEDE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He wanted to be an APPRENTICE to a good plumber.",
          "word": "APPRENTICE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was quite a NOMAD; he saved every penny he earned and hid it all in a chest beneath his bed.",
          "word": "NOMAD",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The lecture was so boring that we had to keep REPRESSING yawns.",
          "word": "REPRESS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": " He tried hard to ILLUMINATE all mistakes from his paper.",
          "word": "ILLUMINATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The PUNCTUAL teenagers burned down the building on a dare.",
          "word": "PUNCTUAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The SURVEILLANCE lasted for months before they saw him do something illegal.",
          "word": "SURVEILLANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "My mother gets upset when somebody tries to FABRICATE her.",
          "word": "FABRICATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The FELONS were kept after school for talking back to the teacher.",
          "word": "FELON",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They had a PERPETUAL argument once in a while, but overall they were very happy.",
          "word": "PERPETUAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Many people joined the REVOLT against paying high taxes.",
          "word": "REVOLT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We live in a tiny METROPOLIS at the top of a mountain.",
          "word": "METROPOLIS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "There was a little NOOK where she could sit and be by herself.",
          "word": "NOOK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She came back tanned and well-rested when she REFRAINED from her summer vacation.",
          "word": "REFRAIN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A DEVASTATING plague of insects stripped the trees of fruit and thoroughly ruined that year's crop.",
          "word": "DEVASTATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The fear that he felt in the dark forest RECEDED with the coming of the dawn.",
          "word": "RECEDE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "APPRENTICE",
          "answers": [
            "learner",
            "worker",
            "writer"
          ],
          "word": "APPRENTICE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NOMAD",
          "answers": [
            "hunter",
            "traveler",
            "wanderer"
          ],
          "word": "NOMAD",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REPRESS",
          "answers": [
            "give up",
            "keep down",
            "hold back"
          ],
          "word": "REPRESS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ILLUMINATE",
          "answers": [
            "brighten",
            "explain",
            "decorate"
          ],
          "word": "ILLUMINATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PUNCTUAL",
          "answers": [
            "on time",
            "prompt",
            "well-dressed"
          ],
          "word": "PUNCTUAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SURVEILLANCE",
          "answers": [
            "observation",
            "justice",
            "watchfulness"
          ],
          "word": "SURVEILLANCE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FABRICATE",
          "answers": [
            "make up",
            "invent",
            "discover"
          ],
          "word": "FABRICATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FELON",
          "answers": [
            "nuisance",
            "criminal",
            "lawbreaker"
          ],
          "word": "FELON",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERPETUAL",
          "answers": [
            "constant",
            "hopeless",
            "eternal"
          ],
          "word": "PERPETUAL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REVOLT",
          "answers": [
            "rebellion",
            "uprising",
            "explosion"
          ],
          "word": "REVOLT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "METROPOLIS",
          "answers": [
            "crowd",
            "jungle",
            "city"
          ],
          "word": "METROPOLIS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NOOK",
          "answers": [
            "circle",
            "corner",
            "alcove"
          ],
          "word": "NOOK",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REFRAIN",
          "answers": [
            "hold back",
            "fall down",
            "stay away"
          ],
          "word": "REFRAIN",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEVASTATE",
          "answers": [
            "ravage",
            "destroy",
            "darken"
          ],
          "word": "DEVASTATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECEDE",
          "answers": [
            "move back",
            "go back",
            "come back"
          ],
          "word": "RECEDE",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "APPRENTICE": {
        "word": "APPRENTICE",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩpren'-tis)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a beginner, learner \nAn APPRENTICE is a person who learns a trade or skill by working with someone who already knows it. Thus, an APPRENTICE is a _learner_ or _beginner_. \n\"Before becoming a good carpenter or plumber, you must spend several years as an APPRENTICE in order to learn the work.\" \n\"Although she was just an APPRENTICE, she was quite skillful at doing electrical repairs.\" \nOther forms of the word: APPRENTICESHIP, n."
      },
      "NOMAD": {
        "word": "NOMAD",
        "phonetic": "(nO'-mad)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "wanderer, roamer \nA NOMAD is a person who moves around constantly without settling in one spot. Usually the word is used in connection with tribes or groups of people who move about in search of food or grazing lands. \n\"The Bedouins of North Africa are NOMADS who wander from place to place with their camels, sheep, and goats.\" \n\"After they invaded the city, the NOMADS settled down to a different way of life.\" \nNOMAD is also used about anyone who travels about constantly. \n\"The workers lived like NOMADS, going anywhere in the country their company needed them.\" \nOther forms of the word: NOMADIC, adj."
      },
      "REPRESS": {
        "word": "REPRESS",
        "phonetic": "(ri-pres')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to hold back, keep down, control, subdue \nSee _re-_ under Prefixes. To REPRESS something is to hold it back, to keep it under control. The word is used especially about feelings or actions that are controlled by an effort of the will. \n\"She REPRESSED a desire to speak up.\" \n\"He REPRESSED a smile as he listened to the boy recite the poem.\" \nIn a stronger sense, REPRESS can mean \"to put down by force,\" to _subdue_. \n\"The army was sent to REPRESS all rioting in the area.\" \nUsually, however, this sense is better expressed by the word _suppress_. \nOther forms of the word: REPRESSION, n. REPRESSIVE, adj."
      },
      "ILLUMINATE": {
        "word": "ILLUMINATE",
        "phonetic": "(i-lU'-mÔøΩnAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to brighten, light up; to make clear \nSee _in-1_ under Prefixes and _-ate1_ under Suffixes. The root _lumin_ in the word ILLUMINATE means _light_; it is also found in the word _luminous_. To ILLUMINATE means to _put light on_ or _in_ an object or space. \n\"The ballroom was ILLUMINATED by hundreds of glowing candles.\" \n\"She decided to ILLUMINATE her paintings with spotlights that were hung from the ceiling.\" \nILLUMINATE can also mean to _make clear_ or _help explain_—that is, to _shed light upon_ an idea or subject. \n\"The English professor had a remarkable way of ILLUMINATING difficult passages in the book so that we could easily understand what we had read.\" \n\"The meaning of a word can be ILLUMINATED by using the word in several different sentences.\" \nOther forms of the word: ILLUMINATION, n."
      },
      "PUNCTUAL": {
        "word": "PUNCTUAL",
        "phonetic": "(pungk'-chU-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "prompt, on time \nPUNCTUAL comes from the Latin word for _point_ or _dot_. A person or thing that is PUNCTUAL arrives right on the dot, is not late or tardy. \n\"Because John is always PUNCTUAL, he spends a lot of time waiting for others to show up.\" \n\"I always try to be PUNCTUAL, but sometimes I'm late anyway.\" \n\"The class starts PUNCTUALLY at nine o'clock.\" \nOther forms of the word: PUNCTUALITY, n."
      },
      "SURVEILLANCE": {
        "word": "SURVEILLANCE",
        "phonetic": "(sÔøΩ-vAl'-ÔøΩns)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "close watch, observation \nSURVEILLANCE is a close watch that is maintained on a person who is suspected of being involved in a crime, or who needs to be watched for some other reason. \n\"The man who was suspected of being a dope peddler was kept under SURVEILLANCE by the police.\" \n\"The government kept the foreign agent under SURVEILLANCE while he was in the country.\" \n\"The staff had to maintain a strict SURVEILLANCE of all the patients in the mental hospital.\""
      },
      "FABRICATE": {
        "word": "FABRICATE",
        "phonetic": "(fab'-rÔøΩkAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to make up, invent, create \nThe basic meaning of FABRIC is \"something that is put together,\" a product of building or construction. To FABRICATE something is to make or produce it. See _-ate_1 under Suffixes. \n\"They FABRICATED the bridge using whatever material was on hand.\" \nWhen used about what people say, the word means to _make up_ something false, in order to deceive. \n\"He FABRICATED the account of his travels in Europe.\" \n\"The teacher thought his excuse was completely FABRICATED and she didn't believe a word of it.\" \nIn this sense, the word FABRICATION means \"made up,\" a _lie_. \n\"His story about winning the lottery was a FABRICATION.\" \nOther forms of the word: FABRIC, n. FABRICATION, n."
      },
      "FELON": {
        "word": "FELON",
        "phonetic": "(fel'-ÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a criminal \nA FELON is a person who commits a serious crime, like murder or armed robbery, for which he could be sent to prison for a long time. Such a crime is called a FELONY. A FELONY is contrasted in law with a _misdemeanor_, which is a less serious offense (like speeding in a car) for which you usually don't get sent to prison. \n\"The convicted FELON found it difficult to get a job when he got out of prison.\" \n\"The judge made the FELONS pay back the people they had robbed.\" \nOther forms of the word: FELONIOUS, adj. FELONY, n."
      },
      "PERPETUAL": {
        "word": "PERPETUAL",
        "phonetic": "(pÔøΩr-pech'-U-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "endless, everlasting, eternal; constant, continual \nPERPETUAL means _lasting forever_. \n\"He hoped for PERPETUAL happiness in heaven after he died.\" \n\"The old man longed for a drug that would give him PERPETUAL youth.\" \nIn a similar sense, PERPETUAL also means _constant_, _not stopping_. \n\"They are PERPETUALLY fighting. They never get along.\" \n\"It's a PERPETUAL problem. We may never solve it.\" \nTo PERPETUATE something is to make it PERPETUAL, to keep it from being ended or forgotten. \n\"They built a monument to PERPETUATE the memory of his great deeds.\" \nOther forms of the word: PERPETUATE, v. PERPETUITY, n."
      },
      "REVOLT": {
        "word": "REVOLT",
        "phonetic": "(ri-vOlt')",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a rebellion, uprising \nA REVOLT is an uprising against the government. \n\"The people rose in REVOLT against the cruel king.\" \n\"The soldiers quickly put down the REVOLT.\" \nA REVOLT can also be any kind of refusal to accept authority. \n\"The young people were in REVOLT against the beliefs of their parents.\" \nREVOLT is also a verb. \n\"They REVOLTED against their rulers.\" \nSometimes, the verb can mean to _disgust_. \n\"The filth in the house REVOLTED him.\" \n_Trouble_ is the most commonly chosen incorrect answer in the Pretest. REVOLT, however, is much more specific than that. A REVOLT is a _rebellion_."
      },
      "METROPOLIS": {
        "word": "METROPOLIS",
        "phonetic": "(mÔøΩtrop'-ÔøΩlÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a large city \nA METROPOLIS is a large or great city. The word is formed from two Greek words meaning _mother_ and _city_. Originally a METROPOLIS was a \"mother-city\"—one which sent people to start colonies or new cities. Now the word is used for any large, busy city. \n\"The explorers discovered a thriving METROPOLIS in the middle of the jungle.\" \n\"New York has been a METROPOLIS for over a hundred years.\" \nOther forms of the word: METROPOLITAN, adj."
      },
      "NOOK": {
        "word": "NOOK",
        "phonetic": "(nuk)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a corner or recess, an out-of-the-way place \nA NOOK is a corner or recess in a house or a room, a small alcove. NOOK is also used for any out-of-the-way spot. \n\"They found a quiet little NOOK in the crowded room where they could talk.\" \n\"He sat in a shady NOOK at the far end of the garden.\" \n\"She sat in her usual NOOK by the fireplace.\""
      },
      "REFRAIN": {
        "word": "REFRAIN",
        "phonetic": "(ri-frAn')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to hold back, abstain \nTO REFRAIN from something is to keep from doing it, to _hold back_. See _re-_ under Prefixes. \n\"Try to REFRAIN from interrupting me while I'm speaking.\" \n\"The neighbors asked him to REFRAIN from playing the drums after midnight.\" \n\"Sue REFRAINED from shouting out the window at him despite the noise he was making.\" \nUsage: REFRAIN is usually followed by _from_."
      },
      "DEVASTATE": {
        "word": "DEVASTATE",
        "phonetic": "(dev'-ÔøΩstAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to ruin, lay waste to, ravage; to overwhelm \nTo DEVASTATE something is to ruin it completely. \n\"The enemy's bombs DEVASTATED the city.\" \n\"The region was DEVASTATED by the hurricane.\" \nIn a slightly different use, DEVASTATE can mean to _overwhelm_. \n\"She was completely DEVASTATED by the news of her husband's death.\" \n\"The book gave a DEVASTATING picture of the evils of war.\" \nDEVASTATE is often confused with _attack_. An _attack_ may cause a place to be DEVASTATED, but the words do not have the same meaning. \nOther forms of the word: DEVASTATION, n."
      },
      "RECEDE": {
        "word": "RECEDE",
        "phonetic": "(ri-sEd')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to go back, become more distant; decline \nSee _re-_ under Prefixes. To RECEDE is to _go back_ or _move away_. Usually this \"going back\" is slow or gradual. \n\"The land slowly RECEDED from sight as we set out to sea.\" \n\"The flood waters began to RECEDE when the rain stopped.\" \nSometimes RECEDE has the meaning \"to fall to a lower level,\" to _decline_. \n\"Public support of the president RECEDED as he continued to support a tax increase.\" \n\"His financial worries began to RECEDE as his salary increased.\" \nOther forms of the word: RECESSION, n."
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "ADJACENT",
        "EXCURSION",
        "INQUISITIVE",
        "PUNCTUAL",
        "RURAL",
        "DECIPHER",
        "FABRICATE",
        "MERCILESS",
        "REFRAIN",
        "SURVEILLANCE",
        "DECREE",
        "GLUTTON",
        "NOMAD",
        "REPEL",
        "THERMAL",
        "EMERGE",
        "HASTEN",
        "NOOK",
        "REVOLT",
        "UNSAVORY",
        "APPRENTICE",
        "ESCAPADE",
        "FELON",
        "METROPOLIS",
        "REFUGE",
        "DERANGED",
        "EXECUTE",
        "GESTURE",
        "PERPETUAL",
        "REPRESS",
        "DEVASTATE",
        "EXPLICIT",
        "GRANDEUR",
        "RANSACK",
        "SKEPTIC",
        "DISPEL",
        "FALTER",
        "ILLUMINATE",
        "RATIFY",
        "SURMOUNT",
        "ENUNCIATE",
        "FAMINE",
        "LEGIBLE",
        "RECEDE",
        "WAGER"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "Several towns decided to start a(n)",
          "part2": "against the unpopular dictator.",
          "answer": "revolt"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The train",
          "part2": "from the tunnel going sixty miles an hour.",
          "answer": "emerged"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He liked his workers to be",
          "part2": "; he fired them if they were late three times.",
          "answer": "punctual"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It took several experts to",
          "part2": "the Russians' secret code.",
          "answer": "decipher"
        },
        {
          "part1": "There are fewer",
          "part2": "villages as more and more people leave their farms and move into cities.",
          "answer": "rural"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We wanted to keep bugs off the tree so we sprayed it with a chemical which is supposed to",
          "part2": "them.",
          "answer": "repel"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They went on a short",
          "part2": "to the country last weekend.",
          "answer": "excursion"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The police kept him under constant",
          "part2": "to see if he would lead them to the gang's hideout.",
          "answer": "surveillance"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The king was",
          "part2": "; he sentenced all of his enemies to death.",
          "answer": "merciless"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Johnny",
          "part2": "that story about feeling ill so that he wouldn't have to do his share of the work.",
          "answer": "fabricated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The store is",
          "part2": "to a subway stop, so it is easy for you to get there.",
          "answer": "adjacent"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Bob was very angry at the dog, but he",
          "part2": "from hitting it.",
          "answer": "refrained"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We are trying to",
          "part2": "the delivery of our furniture so that we can move in sooner.",
          "answer": "hasten"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The water in a(n)",
          "part2": "spring can be very hot.",
          "answer": "thermal"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They sat in the cozy",
          "part2": "by the window and chatted.",
          "answer": "nook"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Everyone resented the king's",
          "part2": "that doubled taxes.",
          "answer": "decree"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He was such a(n)",
          "part2": "that he would eat three helpings of everything.",
          "answer": "glutton"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "little boy asked questions about everything he saw in the museum.",
          "answer": "inquisitive"
        },
        {
          "part1": "This part of town has a(n)",
          "part2": "reputation; a lot of nasty people live here.",
          "answer": "unsavory"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He gave up his job and became a(n)",
          "part2": ", traveling wherever he wanted to, living by his wits.",
          "answer": "nomad"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We were impressed by the",
          "part2": "of the ceremony in which the new king was crowned.",
          "answer": "grandeur"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She felt scared and lonely in the huge, busy",
          "part2": "after living on a farm all her life.",
          "answer": "metropolis"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The judge said that stealing a car was not a childish",
          "part2": "but a serious crime.",
          "answer": "escapade"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I don't understand all these hints. Could you please be more",
          "part2": "about what you mean?",
          "answer": "explicit"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We looked high and low for the missing necklace, and",
          "part2": "the house trying to find it.",
          "answer": "ransacked"
        },
        {
          "part1": "This will be a(n)",
          "part2": "problem for us; I don't think we'll ever solve it.",
          "answer": "perpetual"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Once he made up his mind, he stuck to his decision and did not",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "falter"
        },
        {
          "part1": "After the earthquake, the church provided a(n)",
          "part2": "for those who had lost their homes.",
          "answer": "refuge"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The new street lights helped to",
          "part2": "the street so that there were fewer accidents.",
          "answer": "illuminate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Because the storekeeper was deaf, I had to use a lot of",
          "part2": "to make him understand what I wanted.",
          "answer": "gestures"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Bill",
          "part2": "ten dollars that he would beat Tim in the race.",
          "answer": "wagered"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It was hard to",
          "part2": "the strange feeling that this had all happened to me before.",
          "answer": "dispel"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Sam never believed in anything wholeheartedly; he remained a(n)",
          "part2": "all his life.",
          "answer": "skeptic"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The criminals",
          "part2": "the robbery so successfully that no one knew what had happened.",
          "answer": "executed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Two square blocks of the city were totally",
          "part2": "by the explosion.",
          "answer": "devastated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "If it doesn't rain soon the crops will die and there will be a(n)",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "famine"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The sound of thunder",
          "part2": "as the storm moved away.",
          "answer": "receded"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The legislature refused to",
          "part2": "the treaty.",
          "answer": "ratify"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He must be",
          "part2": "No one in his right mind would act that way.",
          "answer": "deranged"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The gravestones were so old and worn that the names on them were barely",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "legible"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Tom had to",
          "part2": "many obstacles on his climb to the presidency.",
          "answer": "surmount"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Art said he was not a(n)",
          "part2": "; the worst thing he had ever done was to park illegally.",
          "answer": "felon"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He was only a(n)",
          "part2": ", but already we could tell that someday he would be a great master of his trade.",
          "answer": "apprentice"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He",
          "part2": "every word clearly so that he wouldn't be misunderstood.",
          "answer": "enunciated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She tried very hard to",
          "part2": "a grin, but she was too happy to keep from smiling.",
          "answer": "repress"
        }
      ]
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.4",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "PERILOUS journey.",
          "answers": [
            "unlucky",
            "safe",
            "boring",
            "dangerous",
            "endless"
          ],
          "word": "PERILOUS",
          "correct": "dangerous"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUBDUE all of them.",
          "answers": [
            "overcome",
            "go beneath",
            "fight",
            "lose to",
            "change"
          ],
          "word": "SUBDUE",
          "correct": "overcome"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Foreign COMMERCE.",
          "answers": [
            "warfare",
            "offer",
            "talk",
            "trade",
            "ship"
          ],
          "word": "COMMERCE",
          "correct": "trade"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PRELIMINARY material.",
          "answers": [
            "easy",
            "introductory",
            "new",
            "well-known",
            "final"
          ],
          "word": "PRELIMINARY",
          "correct": "introductory"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BRISK people.",
          "answers": [
            "homely",
            "slow",
            "lively",
            "clever",
            "mean"
          ],
          "word": "BRISK",
          "correct": "lively"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NONCHALANT attitude.",
          "answers": [
            "mental",
            "undecided",
            "concerned",
            "former",
            "casual"
          ],
          "word": "NONCHALANT",
          "correct": "casual"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To DENOUNCE him.",
          "answers": [
            "leave",
            "dislike",
            "capture",
            "praise",
            "criticize"
          ],
          "word": "DENOUNCE",
          "correct": "criticize"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A very EARNEST boy.",
          "answers": [
            "rich",
            "serious",
            "sad",
            "playful",
            "stingy"
          ],
          "word": "EARNEST",
          "correct": "serious"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Unusually OPTIMISTIC.",
          "answers": [
            "hopeful",
            "excited",
            "friendly",
            "happy",
            "worried"
          ],
          "word": "OPTIMISTIC",
          "correct": "hopeful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Joined in the CONQUEST.",
          "answers": [
            "victory",
            "game",
            "tour",
            "celebration",
            "surrender"
          ],
          "word": "CONQUEST",
          "correct": "victory"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STERN words.",
          "answers": [
            "loud",
            "final",
            "gentle",
            "severe",
            "unknown"
          ],
          "word": "STERN",
          "correct": "severe"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BEHOLD it.",
          "answers": [
            "remember",
            "enjoy",
            "forget",
            "go to",
            "look at"
          ],
          "word": "BEHOLD",
          "correct": "look at"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Unwilling to DISCLOSE it.",
          "answers": [
            "start",
            "find",
            "reveal",
            "unlock",
            "hide"
          ],
          "word": "DISCLOSE",
          "correct": "reveal"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Different ETIQUETTE.",
          "answers": [
            "invitation",
            "phrases",
            "laws",
            "manners",
            "dance"
          ],
          "word": "ETIQUETTE",
          "correct": "manners"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To MANIPULATE it.",
          "answers": [
            "drop",
            "handle",
            "copy",
            "fix",
            "demand"
          ],
          "word": "MANIPULATE",
          "correct": "handle"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do lion tamers have a PERILOUS job?",
          "word": "PERILOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are SUBDUED voices very loud?",
          "word": "SUBDUE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is money involved in COMMERCE?",
          "word": "COMMERCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a PRELIMINARY decision the last one that will be made?",
          "word": "PRELIMINARY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can winds be BRISK?",
          "word": "BRISK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people be NONCHALANT about winning a million dollars?",
          "word": "NONCHALANT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a reporter on television DENOUNCE the news?",
          "word": "DENOUNCE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should you pay attention to someone who is in EARNEST?",
          "word": "EARNEST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would an OPTIMIST worry a lot?",
          "word": "OPTIMISTIC",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If someone climbed a mountain that had never been climbed before, would that be considered a CONQUEST?",
          "word": "CONQUEST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a comedian STERN?",
          "word": "STERN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you BEHOLD something that is in the distance?",
          "word": "BEHOLD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are secrets supposed to be DISCLOSED?",
          "word": "DISCLOSE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it usually considered proper ETIQUETTE to slam the door in someone's face?",
          "word": "ETIOUETTE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it possible to MANIPULATE a hammer?",
          "word": "MANIPULATE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "They all breathed a sigh of relief when they had completed the PERILOUS journey.",
          "word": "PERILOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The wrestler SUBDUED his opponent with a trick hold.",
          "word": "SUBDUE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The COMMERCIAL bank dealt mainly with the money needs of large businesses.",
          "word": "COMMERCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "There will be a PRELIMINARY interview before we will let you formally apply for the job.",
          "word": "PRELIMINARY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He ran at a BRISK pace through the park.",
          "word": "BRISK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The angry teacher was NONCHALANT with everyone for disobeying.",
          "word": "NONCHALANT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The politician took every opportunity to issue public DENUNCIATIONS of his opponent.",
          "word": "DENOUNCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I EARNESTLY recommend that you fix those stairs before someone gets hurt.",
          "word": "EARNEST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The coach was OPTIMISTIC about winning the title despite our injuries.",
          "word": "OPTIMISTIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was a close CONQUEST, but we finally lost.",
          "word": "CONQUEST",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His parents were very STERN. He wasn't allowed to do anything the other children did.",
          "word": "STERN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Traffic on the highway was BEHELD by a serious accident.",
          "word": "BEHOLD",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They asked for a full DISCLOSURE of what he knew about the business deal.",
          "word": "DISCLOSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He knows nothing about ETIQUETTE: his table manners are disgraceful.",
          "word": "ETIQUETTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He is easily MANIPULATED: he will do anything if you ask him in the right way.",
          "word": "MANIPULATE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "PERILOUS",
          "answers": [
            "hazardous",
            "miserable",
            "risky"
          ],
          "word": "PERILOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUBDUE",
          "answers": [
            "quiet",
            "control",
            "demand"
          ],
          "word": "SUBDUE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMMERCE",
          "answers": [
            "selling",
            "taxing",
            "buying"
          ],
          "word": "COMMERCE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PRELIMINARY",
          "answers": [
            "first",
            "fast",
            "prior"
          ],
          "word": "PRELIMINARY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BRISK",
          "answers": [
            "quick",
            "energetic",
            "powerful"
          ],
          "word": "BRISK",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NONCHALANT",
          "answers": [
            "calm",
            "smart",
            "casual"
          ],
          "word": "NONCHALANT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DENOUNCE",
          "answers": [
            "disappoint",
            "blame",
            "condemn"
          ],
          "word": "DENOUNCE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EARNEST",
          "answers": [
            "passionate",
            "determined",
            "cheerful"
          ],
          "word": "EARNEST",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OPTIMISTIC",
          "answers": [
            "happy",
            "young",
            "confident"
          ],
          "word": "OPTIMISTIC",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONQUEST",
          "answers": [
            "attempt",
            "victory",
            "win"
          ],
          "word": "CONQUEST",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STERN",
          "answers": [
            "serious",
            "firm",
            "brilliant"
          ],
          "word": "STERN",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BEHOLD",
          "answers": [
            "remember",
            "examine",
            "notice"
          ],
          "word": "BEHOLD",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISCLOSE",
          "answers": [
            "expect",
            "uncover",
            "tell"
          ],
          "word": "DISCLOSE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ETIQUETTE",
          "answers": [
            "rules",
            "beliefs",
            "manners"
          ],
          "word": "ETIQUETTE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MANIPULATE",
          "answers": [
            "handle",
            "influence",
            "ruin"
          ],
          "word": "MANIPULATE",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "PERILOUS": {
        "word": "PERILOUS",
        "phonetic": "(per'-ÔøΩlÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "dangerous, hazardous \nPERIL is _hazard_ or _danger_.n\"They faced many PERILS climbing the mountain.\" \nSomething that is PERILOUS is full of PERIL. See _-ous_ under Suffixes. \n\"The journey across the ocean was a PERILOUS one in the days of sailing ships.\" \n\"Crossing a minefield is PERILOUS.\" \n\"On the top floor of the burning building, they felt their situation was PERILOUS but not hopeless.\" \nOther forms of the word: PERIL, n."
      },
      "SUBDUE": {
        "word": "SUBDUE",
        "phonetic": "(sÔøΩb-dU'",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to overcome, control, tame, curb; to quiet down, tone down \nTo SUBDUE is to conquer or get control of by force, threat, or by an effort of the will. \n\"The conquering army SUBDUED the uprising by the natives.\" \n\"The expert rider SUBDUED the wild horse.\" \n\"She managed to SUBDUE her desire to own a new car.\" \nSUBDUE can also mean \"to reduce in intensity,\" to _quiet down_. \n\"They SUBDUED their voices when they saw the teacher approaching.\" \nThe adjective SUBDUED is usually used in this sense. \n\"The SUBDUED lighting made the restaurant appear mysterious and romantic.\" \nOther forms of the word: SUBDUED, adj."
      },
      "COMMERCE": {
        "word": "COMMERCE",
        "phonetic": "(kom'-ÔøΩrs)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "trade \nCOMMERCE is the buying and selling of goods, especially on a large scale or between different countries. \n\"The shipping strike caused COMMERCE to decline.\" \n\"Congress encouraged COMMERCE with other countries by reducing the taxes on goods coming into the United States.\" \nThe Chamber of COMMERCE is an association which promotes trade and business activity in a particular area. \nCOMMERCIAL is the adjective from COMMERCE, and means \"having to do with trade or business.\" \n\"The COMMERCIAL interests in the city urged that more roads be built to carry goods to and from the factories.\" \nA COMMERCIAL _message_ or COMMERCIAL is an advertisement in a radio or television program. \nOther forms of the word: COMMERCIAL, adj., n."
      },
      "PRELIMINARY": {
        "word": "PRELIMINARY",
        "phonetic": "(prÔøΩlim'-ÔøΩner-E)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "introductory, preparatory \nSomething that is PRELIMINARY comes before something else, and usually leads up to or prepares for it. See _pre-_ under Prefixes. \n\"These are just PRELIMINARY findings. The final report will be published later.\" \n\"There were three PRELIMINARY fights before the main event.\" \nPRELIMINARY is also a noun. \n\"This test is just a PRELIMINARY. If you pass it, you have to take a much harder one.\" \nThe most commonly marked incorrect answer on the Pretest is _final_, which is almost an opposite of PRELIMINARY."
      },
      "BRISK": {
        "word": "BRISK",
        "phonetic": "(brisk)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "lively, quick-moving, stimulating \nBRISK means _lively_, _quick_, _energetic_. The word is used about the way people or things act and move, and also about people's manners and attitudes. BRISK often suggests a liveliness that makes a person feel strong and healthy. \n\"The BRISK ten-minute walk made us all feel wonderful.\" \n\"After the heavy rain, a BRISK wind dried the newly washed ground.\" \n\"She was a BRISK, intelligent woman with plenty of plans and the energy to carry them out.\" \n\"It was a BRISK fall day: the sun was out but it was cool and there was no humidity.\""
      },
      "NONCHALANT": {
        "word": "NONCHALANT",
        "phonetic": "(non-shÔøΩlont')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "casual, cool, unconcerned \nSee _non-_ under Prefixes. The root meaning of NONCHALANT is _not warm_. The word is applied to people who have a cool and calm manner, who do not get excited or upset easily. \n\"He seems very NONCHALANT about winning the prize, but he's really quite pleased.\" \n\"When she was accused of lying, she acted very NONCHALANT, as if it didn't bother her a bit.\" \nOther forms of the word: NONCHALANCE, n."
      },
      "DENOUNCE": {
        "word": "DENOUNCE",
        "phonetic": "(di-nowns'",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to criticize, speak against \nTo DENOUNCE someone is to criticize or make charges against him, usually publicly. \n\"He DENOUNCED his former friend as a crook and a liar.\" \n\"She DENOUNCED the plan, calling it unfair and illegal.\" \nIn a slightly different sense, the word means \"to give information against\" a person, usually to the authorities. \n\"He DENOUNCED his co-worker to the police as a traitor.\" \nThe noun from DENOUNCE is DENUNCIATION. \"Despite the City Council's DENUNCIATION of his plan, the mayor said he would go ahead with it.\" \nOther forms of the word: DENUNCIATION, n."
      },
      "EARNEST": {
        "word": "EARNEST",
        "phonetic": "(er'-nist)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "serious, determined, sincere \nAn EARNEST person is sincere and serious in pursuing a goal. The word suggests steady purpose and deep feeling. \n\"The EARNEST student tried to learn all he could about the subject.\" \n\"He made an EARNEST attempt to climb the mountain, but finally had to give up.\" \n\"The teacher EARNESTLY warned Jack to study harder or else he wouldn't graduate.\" \nEARNEST is also a noun, which is usually found in the phrase \"in EARNEST.\" Someone who is \"in EARNEST\" is serious, is not joking. \n\"She was in EARNEST when she told us a hurricane was coming and we were in danger.\""
      },
      "OPTIMISTIC": {
        "word": "OPTIMISTIC",
        "phonetic": "(op-tÔøΩmis'-tik)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "hopeful, cheerful, confident \nThe word OPTIMIST comes from a Latin word meaning _best_. An OPTIMIST believes everything will turn out for the best. \n\"He's such an OPTIMIST—he believes that he will soon be rich and famous.\" \nOPTIMISTIC is the adjective from OPTIMIST. See _-ic_ under Suffixes. Someone who is OPTIMISTIC is hopeful and cheerful in his outlook. OPTIMISTIC people are confident that everything will turn out well, even though they may have no good reason to believe this. \n\"Although he knew he had only one year to live, he was OPTIMISTIC that a cure would be found in time to save him.\" \n\"She was OPTIMISTIC about getting the job on the newspaper because the editor had seemed to like her during the interview.\" \nOther forms of the word: OPTIMISM, n. OPTIMIST, n."
      },
      "CONQUEST": {
        "word": "CONQUEST",
        "phonetic": "(kon'-kwest)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "victory, conquering \nCONQUEST is related to the word CONQUER. To CONQUER is to defeat or overcome an enemy. A CONQUEST is a victory or the act of CONQUERING. The word is usually used about victory in war or battle. \n\"The CONQUEST of Germany was a long campaign; it took four years to CONQUER the country.\" \n\"The Norman CONQUEST of England began with the Battle of Hastings.\" \nCONQUEST is also used about any act of overcoming or gaining a victory, especially after a struggle. \n\"Many doctors deserve credit for helping in the CONQUEST of polio.\""
      },
      "STERN": {
        "word": "STERN",
        "phonetic": "(stern)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "severe, strict, firm, grim \nSomeone who is STERN has a firm and unyielding manner, is strict and severe. \n\"The STERN teacher would punish the whole class for any mistakes.\" \nSTERN is also used about the way people look and what they do. \n\"He gave them a STERN look when he heard them laughing at him.\" \n\"The children were unhappy because of their mother's STERN refusal to let them play outside.\" \nSomething which is a \"STERN necessity\" isn't very pleasant, but has to be done. \n\"He was faced with the STERN necessity of having to fire his best friend from the job.\""
      },
      "BEHOLD": {
        "word": "BEHOLD",
        "phonetic": "(bÔøΩhOld')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to look at, observe, see \nTo BEHOLD something is to look at it. The word usually suggests seeing fully and clearly. \n\"When we first BEHELD the city we knew we wanted to live there.\" \n\"After a snowstorm the woods are beautiful to BEHOLD.\" \n\"Last night I BEHELD the strangest sight I have ever seen.\" \n\"The magician opened the box and BEHOLD! the girl had disappeared.\" \nMany people confuse BEHOLD with _remember_, perhaps because the _hold_ part of the word suggests holding something in your memory. \nUsage: The past tense of BEHOLD is BEHELD."
      },
      "DISCLOSE": {
        "word": "DISCLOSE",
        "phonetic": "(dis-klOz')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to reveal, uncover, expose, divulge, make known \nSee _dis-_ under Prefixes. To DISCLOSE something is to make it \"not closed,\" to open it up to view or to public knowledge. \n\"Examination of their records DISCLOSED several illegal business deals.\" \nThe word is usually used about people saying something which was previously secret. \n\"Jim DISCLOSED that he had once been in jail.\" \nThe noun from DISCLOSE is DISCLOSURE. \n\"Everyone was shocked by his DISCLOSURE that he was an alcoholic.\" \nOther forms of the word: DISCLOSURE, n."
      },
      "ETIQUETTE": {
        "word": "ETIQUETTE",
        "phonetic": "(et'-ÔøΩkÔøΩt)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "manners, rules of behavior \nNote the pronunciation. The _qu_ is pronounced like _k_. \nEvery society or profession has its own unwritten rules of how to behave, what to do and what not to do in certain situations. ETIQUETTE is the general name for these accepted ways of behaving. \n\"To leave the table so soon was not proper ETIQUETTE\"—that is, it was not the accepted way to act.\" \n\"Medical ETIQUETTE prohibits a doctor from stealing another doctor's patient.\" \nIt is not against the law to go against ETIQUETTE, but you can be looked down on or disliked for ignoring proper ETIQUETTE."
      },
      "MANIPULATE": {
        "word": "MANIPULATE",
        "phonetic": "(mÔøΩnip'-yU-IAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to handle skillfully, manage, control \nMANIPULATE comes from the Latin word for _hand_, also the source of the words _manual_ and _manufacture_. To MANIPULATE something is to _handle_ it, particularly with skill or cleverness. \n\"She MANIPULATED the controls expertly.\" \nIn a general sense the word means to _control_ or _manage_ something or someone, particularly by artful or tricky means. \n\"The speaker knew how to MANIPULATE his audience so that they agreed with him.\" \n\"I don't mind being given advice, but I don't like the idea that I'm being MANIPULATED to do what someone else wants.\" \nOther forms of the word: MANIPULATION, n."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.5",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "PRIMARILY interested in trade.",
          "answers": [
            "suddenly",
            "actively",
            "somewhat",
            "chiefly",
            "usually"
          ],
          "word": "PRIMARILY",
          "correct": "chiefly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TESTY people.",
          "answers": [
            "irritable",
            "curious",
            "mean",
            "quiet",
            "pleasant"
          ],
          "word": "TESTY",
          "correct": "irritable"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Expected the CALAMITY.",
          "answers": [
            "hatred",
            "disaster",
            "problem",
            "good luck",
            "laughter"
          ],
          "word": "CALAMITY",
          "correct": "disaster"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STUPENDOUS performances.",
          "answers": [
            "interesting",
            "slow",
            "amazing",
            "ordinary",
            "boring"
          ],
          "word": "STUPENDOUS",
          "correct": "amazing"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were VULNERABLE",
          "answers": [
            "unbeatable",
            "ancient",
            "wounded",
            "unhappy",
            "unprotected"
          ],
          "word": "VULNERABLE",
          "correct": "unprotected"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Very STRENUOUS.",
          "answers": [
            "expensive",
            "dangerous",
            "boring",
            "energetic",
            "easy"
          ],
          "word": "STRENUOUS",
          "correct": "energetic"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "What does it ENTAIL?",
          "answers": [
            "involve",
            "need",
            "show",
            "forbid",
            "mean"
          ],
          "word": "ENTAIL",
          "correct": "involve"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Takes VENGEANCE.",
          "answers": [
            "offense",
            "firmness",
            "revenge",
            "courage",
            "pity"
          ],
          "word": "VENGEANCE",
          "correct": "revenge"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Let no one INTERVENE.",
          "answers": [
            "come between",
            "join",
            "take sides",
            "come in",
            "decide"
          ],
          "word": "INTERVENE",
          "correct": "come between"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Very ELABORATE.",
          "answers": [
            "painful",
            "complicated",
            "bright",
            "huge",
            "simple"
          ],
          "word": "ELABORATE",
          "correct": "complicated"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her face was DISTINCT.",
          "answers": [
            "clear",
            "beautiful",
            "famous",
            "strange",
            "hidden"
          ],
          "word": "DISTINCT",
          "correct": "clear"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REMOTE lands.",
          "answers": [
            "unknown",
            "wet",
            "nearby",
            "dangerous",
            "far-away"
          ],
          "word": "REMOTE",
          "correct": "far-away"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DINGY curtains.",
          "answers": [
            "tiny",
            "soiled",
            "white",
            "old",
            "soaked"
          ],
          "word": "DINGY",
          "correct": "soiled"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It is OBSCURE.",
          "answers": [
            "stupid",
            "bright",
            "familiar",
            "unclear",
            "lost"
          ],
          "word": "OBSCURE",
          "correct": "unclear"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Good-natured RIVALRY.",
          "answers": [
            "disagreement",
            "enjoyment",
            "drinking",
            "teamwork",
            "competition"
          ],
          "word": "RIVALRY",
          "correct": "competition"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "If someone is PRIMARILY interested in math, is that his favorite subject?",
          "word": "PRIMARILY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do little children often get TESTY when they're overtired?",
          "word": "TESTY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a plane crash be a CALAMITY?",
          "word": "CALAMITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are all television shows STUPENDOUS?",
          "word": "STUPENDOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If a person is VULNERABLE to attack, is he in danger?",
          "word": "VULNERABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is climbing a mountain STRENUOUS exercise?",
          "word": "STRENUOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does being a salesman ENTAIL meeting many people?",
          "word": "ENTAIL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people take VENGEANCE for a favor?",
          "word": "VENGEANCE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it possible to INTERVENE in an argument?",
          "word": "INTERVENE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a meal of bread and water ELABORATE?",
          "word": "ELABORATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does mud make things DISTINCT?",
          "word": "DISTINCT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is Canada REMOTE from the United States?",
          "word": "REMOTE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a freshly washed shirt usually be DINGY?",
          "word": "DINGY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is George Washington OBSCURE?",
          "word": "OBSCURE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there usually a RIVALRY among the people who want to be president?",
          "word": "RIVALRY",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He was PRIMARILY an actor, but he could also sing and dance quite well.",
          "word": "PRIMARILY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Al was TESTY about how long the corridor was, so he measured it himself.",
          "word": "TESTY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "No one else minded much, but Bob thought it was a CALAMITY when lunch was a few minutes late.",
          "word": "CALAMITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Hal thought the book was good, but not really STUPENDOUS.",
          "word": "STUPENDOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The city was so VULNERABLE that no one could ever conquer it.",
          "word": "VULNERABLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "These wires are quite STRENUOUS. Touch one and you will die instantly.",
          "word": "STRENUOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Getting high marks in school usually ENTAILS a great deal of studying.",
          "word": "ENTAIL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her VENGEANCE for the murder of her child was both swift and terrifying.",
          "word": "VENGEANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He INTERVENED her to come with him to the party.",
          "word": "INTERVENE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "In her speech she ELABORATED on some of the points I had made in mine.",
          "word": "ELABORATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bill had the DISTINCT feeling that he was being followed.",
          "word": "DISTINCT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The doctor was only REMOTELY concerned about the danger of getting any diseases from his patients.",
          "word": "REMOTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was such a DINGY amount of money that we didn't care about it.",
          "word": "DINGY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I felt OBSCURE about it until someone showed me what to do.",
          "word": "OBSCURE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He had several RIVALS in the swimming competition, but he was able to beat them all.",
          "word": "RIVALRY",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "PRIMARILY",
          "answers": [
            "mainly",
            "gladly",
            "chiefly"
          ],
          "word": "PRIMARILY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TESTY",
          "answers": [
            "cross",
            "evil",
            "annoyed"
          ],
          "word": "TESTY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CALAMITY",
          "answers": [
            "danger",
            "misfortune",
            "accident"
          ],
          "word": "CALAMITY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STUPENDOUS",
          "answers": [
            "fine",
            "magnificent",
            "unbelievable"
          ],
          "word": "STUPENDOUS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VULNERABLE",
          "answers": [
            "weak",
            "helpless",
            "unhappy"
          ],
          "word": "VULNERABLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STRENUOUS",
          "answers": [
            "dynamic",
            "heavy",
            "active"
          ],
          "word": "STRENUOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENTAIL",
          "answers": [
            "involve",
            "require",
            "decide"
          ],
          "word": "ENTAIL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VENGEANCE",
          "answers": [
            "defense",
            "punishment",
            "retaliation"
          ],
          "word": "VENGEANCE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERVENE",
          "answers": [
            "disappear",
            "intrude",
            "interfere"
          ],
          "word": "INTERVENE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ELABORATE",
          "answers": [
            "difficult",
            "detailed",
            "complex"
          ],
          "word": "ELABORATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISTINCT",
          "answers": [
            "obvious",
            "plain",
            "neat"
          ],
          "word": "DISTINCT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REMOTE",
          "answers": [
            "distant",
            "slight",
            "future"
          ],
          "word": "REMOTE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DINGY",
          "answers": [
            "shabby",
            "dirty",
            "small"
          ],
          "word": "DINGY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBSCURE",
          "answers": [
            "wrong",
            "vague",
            "faint"
          ],
          "word": "OBSCURE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RIVALRY",
          "answers": [
            "disliking",
            "struggle",
            "competition"
          ],
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "PRIMARILY": {
        "word": "PRIMARILY",
        "phonetic": "(prl-mer'-ÔøΩIE)",
        "pos": "adv.",
        "deftext": "chiefly, mainly, first of all \nPRIMARILY comes from the Latin word for _first_. It is related to words like _prime_ and _primary_. PRIMARILY means \"in the first place,\" _mainly_. \n\"He is PRIMARILY interested in making money.\" \n\"We are here PRIMARILY to visit friends, but we will also see the sights if we have time.\" \nThe most commonly marked incorrect answer on the Pretest is _somewhat_, which is not at all close in meaning to PRIMARILY. \nOther forms of the word: PRIMARY, adj."
      },
      "TESTY": {
        "word": "TESTY",
        "phonetic": "(tes'-tE)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "irritable, easily annoyed, cross, touchy \nSomeone who is TESTY gets easily annoyed when even small things go wrong. \n\"Jim gets very TESTY when things start to go wrong.\" \n\"The teacher was quite TESTY this morning. She got angry at us no matter what we did.\" \n\"He is usually very patient, but when people are late he starts to get TESTY.\" \nMany people think TESTY means _curious_, perhaps because one meaning of the verb TEST is to _try out_. A _curious_ person would be willing to try out many different things. TESTY, however, is not related to this meaning of the word TEST. \nOther forms of the word: TESTINESS,n."
      },
      "CALAMITY": {
        "word": "CALAMITY",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩ-lam'-ÔøΩ-tE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a disaster, great misfortune, catastrophe \nA CALAMITY is a major misfortune, like a plane crash or a crippling injury. \n\"The closing of the plant was a CALAMITY for the town, since suddenly no one had a job.\" \n\"We were robbed, but it was no great CALAMITY. We just lost a few things.\" \n\"The sudden death of Mr. Jones was quite a CALAMITY for the family.\" \nA common mistake is to choose _problem_ as the meaning of CALAMITY. CALAMITY is much stronger than _problem_, however. The word should only be used about great disasters or misfortunes. \nOther forms of the word: CALAMITOUS, adj."
      },
      "STUPENDOUS": {
        "word": "STUPENDOUS",
        "phonetic": "(stU-pen'-dÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "amazing, awesome, astonishing \nSTUPENDOUS comes from a Latin word that means \"to be astonished.\" Something that is STUPENDOUS is so large or great that it leaves you speechless with amazement. \n\"The STUPENDOUS size of the Himalaya mountains is hard to believe.\" \n\"He called the first trip to the moon one of man's most STUPENDOUS accomplishments.\" \n\"That earthquake was a STUPENDOUS disaster. Thousands of people died in it.\" \nThe most popular wrong answer is _interesting_. STUPENDOUS is a much stronger word than _interesting_, though. \n\"Some movies are merely _interesting_. This movie was STUPENDOUS.\""
      },
      "VULNERABLE": {
        "word": "VULNERABLE",
        "phonetic": "(vul'-nÔøΩr-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "unprotected, exposed, open to attack \nVULNERABLE comes from the Latin word for _wound_. Something that is VULNERABLE is able to be wounded; it is unprotected against damage or attack. See _-able_ under Suffixes. \n\"Our army is VULNERABLE to an attack from the rear.\" \n\"In this new armor only his eyes and hands are VULNERABLE.\" \nVULNERABLE can be used about more than just physical attack. \n\"Several people ran against our governor this year because they thought he was VULNERABLE and could be defeated.\" \nThe most common mistake is to choose _unbeatable_ as the meaning of VULNERABLE. This is confusing a word with its opposite. INVULNERABLE means \"not able to be wounded.\" See _in-2_ under Prefixes. _Unbeatable_ would be synonymous with INVULNERABLE, but it is the opposite of VULNERABLE. \nOther forms of the word: VULNERABILITY, n."
      },
      "STRENUOUS": {
        "word": "STRENUOUS",
        "phonetic": "(stren'-yU-ÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "energetic, active, vigorous \nSTRENUOUS means \"using or requiring great effort,\" _vigorous_. The word can be used about people or their activities. \n\"He was a STRENUOUS opponent of higher taxes.\" \n\"The doctor advised him to avoid STRENUOUS exercise and to eat sensibly.\" \n\"The students objected STRENUOUSLY to the plan to lengthen the school day.\" \nMany people confuse STRENUOUS with _dangerous_. STRENUOUS activities may sometimes be _dangerous_, but they do not have to be."
      },
      "ENTAIL": {
        "word": "ENTAIL",
        "phonetic": "(en-tAI')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to involve, necessitate, impose, require \nThe original use of ENTAIL was in law. To ENTAIL property is to leave it in a will to particular people who cannot sell it or give it away. For example, a man might leave his house to his oldest child, who could only leave it to _his_ oldest child, and so on. This was a way of ensuring that the property remained in the family. \nIf land is ENTAILED, this means that only certain things can be done with it, and certain people will automatically come into possession of it. From this, ENTAIL came generally to mean \"to involve as a necessary result,\" to _require_. \n\"This project will ENTAIL an enormous amount of work\"—that is, a great deal of work will be necessary during the project. \n\"Freedom ENTAILS sacrifice\"—that is, you cannot have one without the other."
      },
      "VENGEANCE": {
        "word": "VENGEANCE",
        "phonetic": "(ven'-jÔøΩns)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "revenge \nVENGEANCE is _revenge_, getting even for some insult or harm that has been done to you or your loved ones. \n\"He sought VENGEANCE against the person who had run over his dog.\" \n\"He is so determined to get VENGEANCE for that insult that it's impossible to reason with him.\" \nThe person who is seeking VENGEANCE is VENGEFUL. \n\"The VENGEFUL man swore he wouldn't rest until he'd found the person who had killed his wife.\" \nOther forms of the word: VENGEFUL, adj."
      },
      "INTERVENE": {
        "word": "INTERVENE",
        "phonetic": "(in-tÔøΩr-vEn')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to come between, be between \nSee _inter-_ under Prefixes. INTERVENE is used in several different senses, each of which basically means to _come between_. The word is used about events or actions which might occur in the course of something. \n\"We will go on as usual unless some problem INTERVENES.\" \nA person INTERVENES when he comes between other people in a quarrel or fight. \n\"It looked like the two of them were going to fight until the teacher INTERVENED.\" \nThe word is used about time that passes between two events. \n\"Nothing much happened during the years that INTERVENED between his graduation and his marriage.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTERVENTION,n."
      },
      "ELABORATE": {
        "word": "ELABORATE",
        "phonetic": "{i-lab'-ÔøΩrÔøΩt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "complicated, intricate, complex \nELABORATE is related to the word _labor_. Something which is ELABORATE has been worked out with great care and in great detail. \n\"She made ELABORATE plans for her wedding.\" \n\"There were ELABORATE decorations on the cake.\" \n\"He gave an ELABORATE explanation of why he was so late.\" \nELABORATE is also a verb. To ELABORATE or ELABORATE _on_ something is to work it out or describe it in detail. \n\"We asked him to ELABORATE on his ideas about student government.\" \nOther forms of the word: ELABORATION,n."
      },
      "DISTINCT": {
        "word": "DISTINCT",
        "phonetic": "(dis-tingkt')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "separate; clear, plain \nDISTINCT is related to the word distinguish. Something that is DISTINCT can clearly be seen as different from something else. \n\"His contribution to the project is quite DISTINCT from everyone else's.\" \n\"The two issues are DISTINCT: one is what we _want_ to do, the other is what we _can_ do.\" \nIn a similar sense DISTINCT can be used about anything that is clear and unmistakable to the mind or senses. \n\"Although the background of the picture is blurred, his face is quite DISTINCT.\" \n\"There is a DISTINCT difference between the Northern and Southern pronunciation of many words.\" \n\"There is a DISTINCT smell of gas in the cellar. It isn't a bad smell, but it's very strong.\""
      },
      "REMOTE": {
        "word": "REMOTE",
        "phonetic": "(ri-mOt'",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "far away, far off, distant; slight \nSomething that is REMOTE is far away, either in space or time. \n\"He sailed to a REMOTE island in the middle of the ocean.\" \n\"In the REMOTE past this area was all under water.\" \n\"Their farm is REMOTE from any city or town.\" \nREMOTE can also mean _small_ or _slight_. \n\"There is only a REMOTE possibility we will be there\"—that is, there is a chance, but not a very good one. \n\"I haven't the REMOTEST idea what you are talking about.\" \nMany people think REMOTE means _unknown_. Something that is far away, however, does not have to be unknown."
      },
      "DINGY": {
        "word": "DINGY",
        "phonetic": "(din'-jE)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "soiled, dirty, drab, shabby \nDINGY means \"having a dark, dirty appearance.\" The word is used about things that have become soiled or faded through use or the passing of time. \n\"The sheets that were once so white are now gray and DINGY.\" \n\"It was a dark, DINGY little room. Everything had a layer of dust on it.\" \nOld is often picked as meaning the same as DINGY. Something that is old, though, does not have to be DINGY."
      },
      "OBSCURE": {
        "word": "OBSCURE",
        "phonetic": "(ob-skyUr'",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "unclear, hidden, vague \nThe basic meaning of OBSCURE is _dark_ or _hard to see_. \n\"Their faces were OBSCURE in the dark room.\" \nOBSCURE has developed several slightly different uses from this basic meaning. The word can mean _unclear_, _hard to understand_. \n\"This poem is OBSCURE. I have no idea what the poet is trying to say.\" \nIt can also mean _little known_. \n\"He was an OBSCURE artist who never achieved any success.\" \n\"From OBSCURE beginnings he rose to become world famous.\" \nOr it can mean _faint_ or _indistinct_. \n\"They heard OBSCURE sounds far in the distance.\" \nTo OBSCURE something is to make it hard to see or understand. \n\"All the difficult words OBSCURED the meaning of the poem.\" \nOther forms of the word: OBSCURITY,n."
      },
      "RIVALRY": {
        "word": "RIVALRY",
        "phonetic": "(rI'-vÔøΩl-rE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "competition \nRIVAL comes originally from a Latin word meaning _stream_. In Latin, a RIVAL was someone who lived on the opposite side of a stream and who had the right to use it along with you. Thus RIVALS are people who compete against each other because they want the same thing. RIVALRY is the state of being RIVALS. \n\"There was quite a RIVALRY between the two schools to see which would win the title.\" \n\"Although their RIVALRY was intense, they still respected each other.\" \n\"There was always RIVALRY among the brothers. Each one wanted to be the best in everything.\" \nOther forms of the word: RIVAL,n.,v."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.6",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "They CONDEMN him.",
          "answers": [
            "overlook",
            "fear",
            "praise",
            "dislike",
            "blame"
          ],
          "word": "CONDEMN",
          "correct": "blame"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A great ENTERPRISE.",
          "answers": [
            "plan",
            "idea",
            "project",
            "trip",
            "mistake"
          ],
          "word": "ENTERPRISE",
          "correct": "project"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Impressed by the MURAL.",
          "answers": [
            "small statue",
            "landscape",
            "photograph",
            "wall painting",
            "portrait"
          ],
          "word": "MURAL",
          "correct": "wall painting"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Saw the REMNANT.",
          "answers": [
            "remainder",
            "difficulty",
            "result",
            "whole thing",
            "beginning"
          ],
          "word": "REMNANT",
          "correct": "remainder"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "During the CORONATION.",
          "answers": [
            "battle",
            "funeral",
            "crowning",
            "celebration",
            "speech"
          ],
          "word": "CORONATION",
          "correct": "crowning"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He EMPLOYED everything.",
          "answers": [
            "begged for",
            "used",
            "improved",
            "threw out",
            "started"
          ],
          "word": "EMPLOY",
          "correct": "used"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GALA events.",
          "answers": [
            "famous",
            "theatrical",
            "dull",
            "feminine",
            "festive"
          ],
          "word": "GALA",
          "correct": "festive"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Began to OOZE.",
          "answers": [
            "sink",
            "leak slowly",
            "overflow",
            "slide",
            "boil away"
          ],
          "word": "OOZE",
          "correct": "leak slowly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Impressive ORATION.",
          "answers": [
            "thought",
            "politician",
            "speech",
            "badge",
            "action"
          ],
          "word": "ORATION",
          "correct": "speech"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SATANIC expression.",
          "answers": [
            "unfriendly",
            "devilish",
            "crazy",
            "saintly",
            "clever"
          ],
          "word": "SATANIC",
          "correct": "devilish"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Saw the MULTITUDE.",
          "answers": [
            "heavens",
            "stars",
            "crowd",
            "beauty",
            "desert"
          ],
          "word": "MULTITUDE",
          "correct": "crowd"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHUN these people.",
          "answers": [
            "dislike",
            "greet",
            "hurt",
            "fight",
            "avoid"
          ],
          "word": "SHUN",
          "correct": "avoid"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Examined the AGENDA.",
          "answers": [
            "contents",
            "program",
            "article",
            "report",
            "office"
          ],
          "word": "AGENDA",
          "correct": "program"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MATERNAL interest.",
          "answers": [
            "undying",
            "feminine",
            "motherly",
            "family",
            "fatherly"
          ],
          "word": "MATERNAL",
          "correct": "motherly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STREW the seeds.",
          "answers": [
            "pick",
            "find",
            "destroy",
            "spread",
            "want"
          ],
          "word": "STREW",
          "correct": "spread"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do judges CONDEMN people to prison?",
          "word": "CONDEMN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a restaurant an ENTERPRISE?",
          "word": "ENTERPRISE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a MURAL he outside?",
          "word": "MURAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a single tree be a REMNANT of a forest?",
          "word": "REMNANT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does the president of the United States have a CORONATION when he enters office?",
          "word": "CORONATION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you EMPLOY a new worker?",
          "word": "EMPLOY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a wedding celebration usually a GALA event?",
          "word": "GALA",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can catsup OOZE?",
          "word": "OOZE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an ORATION spoken?",
          "word": "ORATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a SATANIC person be frightening?",
          "word": "SATANIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there a MULTITUDE of cars on the streets during a traffic jam?",
          "word": "MULTITUDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you SHUN someone you're eager to see?",
          "word": "SHUN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can there be several items on an AGENDA?",
          "word": "AGENDA",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a person's MATERNAL aunt his mother's sister?",
          "word": "MATERNAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do neat people like to see things STREWN about?",
          "word": "STREW",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "You shouldn't CONDEMN him just because he's not perfect.",
          "word": "CONDEMN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was her ENTERPRISE that kept the business going.",
          "word": "ENTERPRISE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He carried the MURAL around in his wallet to show people.",
          "word": "MURAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He wrote himself a REMNANT that he had to go to the store after school.",
          "word": "REMNANT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "After the young queen's CORONATION, there were parties throughout the city.",
          "word": "CORONATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "My father is no longer EMPLOYED by the hardware store.",
          "word": "EMPLOY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The Mardi Gras festival in New Orleans is a city-wide GALA.",
          "word": "GALA",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The new father seemed to OOZE happiness as he showed us pictures of the baby.",
          "word": "OOZE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His ORATION moved the audience to tears.",
          "word": "ORATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His SATANIC laughter made their blood run cold.",
          "word": "SATANIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He complained about the MULTITUDE of problems he had to solve.",
          "word": "MULTITUDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His father told Tom to SHUN the company of evil people.",
          "word": "SHUN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He wrote a complete AGENDA about what had happened at the meeting last week.",
          "word": "AGENDA",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She took a MATERNAL interest in the girls in the club, treating them as she would her own daughters.",
          "word": "MATERNAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Two little girls walked in front of the bride and STREWED rose petals along the path.",
          "word": "STREW",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "CONDEMN",
          "answers": [
            "doom",
            "disbelieve",
            "criticize"
          ],
          "word": "CONDEMN",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENTERPRISE",
          "answers": [
            "courage",
            "happiness",
            "business"
          ],
          "word": "ENTERPRISE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MURAL",
          "answers": [
            "design",
            "sculpture",
            "painting"
          ],
          "word": "MURAL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REMNANT",
          "answers": [
            "beginning",
            "trace",
            "fragment"
          ],
          "word": "REMNANT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CORONATION",
          "answers": [
            "enthronement",
            "crowning",
            "trip"
          ],
          "word": "CORONATION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EMPLOY",
          "answers": [
            "use",
            "seek",
            "hire"
          ],
          "word": "EMPLOY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GALA",
          "answers": [
            "joy",
            "nervousness",
            "excitement"
          ],
          "word": "GALA",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OOZE",
          "answers": [
            "flood",
            "flow",
            "leak"
          ],
          "word": "OOZE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ORATION",
          "answers": [
            "talk",
            "song",
            "lecture"
          ],
          "word": "ORATION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SATANIC",
          "answers": [
            "criminal",
            "fiendish",
            "demonic"
          ],
          "word": "SATANIC",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MULTITUDE",
          "answers": [
            "several",
            "many",
            "few"
          ],
          "word": "MULTITUDE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHUN",
          "answers": [
            "switch",
            "escape",
            "evade"
          ],
          "word": "SHUN",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AGENDA",
          "answers": [
            "list",
            "story",
            "plan"
          ],
          "word": "AGENDA",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MATERNAL",
          "answers": [
            "parental",
            "motherly",
            "childish"
          ],
          "word": "MATERNAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STREW",
          "answers": [
            "find",
            "sprinkle",
            "cover"
          ],
          "word": "STREW",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "CONDEMN": {
        "word": "CONDEMN",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-dem')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to blame, criticize; to sentence, doom \nTo CONDEMN something is to declare that it is wrong or evil. CONDEMN is a very strong word and suggests complete disapproval. \n\"We all CONDEMNED his cruel treatment of the students.\" \n\"She CONDEMNED the governor for his stand on taxes.\" \nTo CONDEMN someone _to_ something is to doom or sentence him to it. \n\"The judge CONDEMNED him to death.\" \n\"His illness CONDEMNED him to a life spent in a wheelchair.\" \nThe most common mistake in the Pretest is to choose _dislike_ as the meaning of CONDEMN. CONDEMN is much stronger than _dislike_, however. You can _dislike_ someone but not CONDEMN him. \nOther forms of the word: CONDEMNATION, n."
      },
      "ENTERPRISE": {
        "word": "ENTERPRISE",
        "phonetic": "(en'-tÔøΩr-prlz)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an undertaking, project; a business, company; energy, daring, spirit \nAn ENTERPRISE is a project or undertaking, especially one that is risky or requires a great deal of skill or courage. \n\"Climbing MountbEverest is quite an ENTERPRISE.\" \n\"Getting him up in the morning was a difficult ENTERPRISE.\" \nENTERPRISE is also used for the spirit or energy which someone has to have to accomplish a challenging project. \n\"It took men of great ENTERPRISE to explore this jungle.\" \nENTERPRISE is also another word for _business_ or _company_. \n\"He owned a small but growing ENTERPRISE.\" \n\"Free ENTERPRISE\" is an economic system in which business projects can be undertaken with little restriction by the government. \nOther forms of the word: ENTERPRISING, adj."
      },
      "MURAL": {
        "word": "MURAL",
        "phonetic": "(myUr'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a wall painting \nA MURAL is a painting done directly on a wall. The word MURAL comes from the Latin word for _wall_. MURALS can also be large photographs or wallpaper scenes which are attached right to the wall, without a frame. \n\"_The Last Supper_ is a MURAL painted by Leonardo da Vinci.\" \n\"The artist painted a colorful MURAL in the subway station.\""
      },
      "REMNANT": {
        "word": "REMNANT",
        "phonetic": "(rem'-nÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a remainder, part left over \nREMNANT is related to the word _remain_. A REMNANT is a part left over, usually a very small or insignificant part. \n\"This painting is the only REMNANT of a once-huge art collection.\" \n\"The enemy quickly captured the REMNANTS of the defeated army.\" \n\"After the town burned down, people searched through the REMNANTS looking for survivors.\" \nA specific use of REMNANT is for a small piece of cloth left over after the larger part has been sold. \n\"The fabric store sold the REMNANTS at a greatly reduced price.\""
      },
      "CORONATION": {
        "word": "CORONATION",
        "phonetic": "(kor-;}-nA'-shÔøΩn",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "the act of crowning \nCorona is the Latin word for _crown_. A CORONATION is a crowning of a king, queen, or other ruler, with all the ceremonies that are part of the event. \n\"Many heads of state attended the CORONATION of the new king.\" \n\"At Napoleon's CORONATION he took the crown and placed it on his head himself.\" \nThe most common wrong answer on the Pretest is _celebration_. There may be _celebrations_ along with a CORONATION, but CORONATION has to do specifically with the crowning of a ruler."
      },
      "EMPLOY": {
        "word": "EMPLOY",
        "phonetic": "(em-ploy')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to use, make use of; to give work to \nTo EMPLOY something is to make use of it. \n\"He EMPLOYED every trick he knew, but he still couldn't beat his opponent.\" \n\"The grounds crew EMPLOYED a large helicopter to help dry off the field.\" \nTo EMPLOY a person is to make use of his services, usually for pay. \n\"This factory EMPLOYS thousands of workers.\" \n\"Bill is EMPLOYED by the insurance company to investigate accident claims.\" \nAn EMPLOYER is a person or company who hires a worker, and an EMPLOYEE is a person who works for a company. \nOther forms of the word: EMPLOYEE, n. EMPLOYER, n. EMPLOYMENT, n."
      },
      "GALA": {
        "word": "GALA",
        "phonetic": "(gA'-1:;,",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "festive, showy \nGALA is both an adjective and a noun. As a noun it means \"a special entertainment,\" a _celebration_. \n\"All the leading society figures came to the GALA celebrating the opening of the museum.\" \nAs an adjective the word means \"like a GALA or celebration,\" _festive_. \n\"His parties were always GALA occasions. Everyone loved to go to them.\" \n\"It was a GALA day from beginning to end, with parades, games, plays, and all kinds of festivities.\""
      },
      "OOZE": {
        "word": "OOZE",
        "phonetic": "(Uz)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to flow slowly, leak out \nOOZE is the soft liquid mud at the bottom of a river or other body of water. To OOZE is to flow slowly like this mud, especially through small openings. \n\"Oil OOZED out of the crack in the engine.\" \n\"Blood OOZED from the wound.\" \nOOZE can also mean to _give off_. \n\"His faced OOZED sweat as he tried to lift the trunk.\" \nThe word can be used in a general sense about things and qualities besides liquids. \n\"She OOZED self-confidence as she strode into the room\"—that is, she had so much self-confidence that it seemed to flow out of her. \nMany people think OOZE means to _overflow_. Both words are used about the flow of liquids, but OOZE means to _flow out slowly_."
      },
      "ORATION": {
        "word": "ORATION",
        "phonetic": "(8-rA'-sh:;,n)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a formal speech \nAn ORATION is a formal, dignified speech made on a public occasion. \n\"Marc Antony delivered a great ORATION at Caesar's funeral.\" \n\"The politician's ORATION put most of the audience to sleep.\" \nAn ORATOR is a person who makes such speeches. \n\"Daniel Webster was a great ORATOR. People would travel hundreds of miles to hear one of his speeches.\" \nOther forms of the word: ORATOR, n. ORATORY, n."
      },
      "SATANIC": {
        "word": "SATANIC",
        "phonetic": "(s:;,-tan'-ik",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "devilish, wicked, evil \nSATANIC is the adjective formed from SATAN, one of several names for the devil. See _-ic_ under Suffixes. SATANIC means _wicked_ or _evil_, like the devil. \n\"His SATANIC smile frightened everyone there.\" \n\"Sometimes a truly SATANIC nature is hidden behind a mask of good manners.\" \n_Crazy_ is the most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest, perhaps because SATANIC sounds a little like _moronic_."
      },
      "MULTITUDE": {
        "word": "MULTITUDE",
        "phonetic": "(muhl'-tg-tUd",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a crowd, a great number \nSee _-tude_ under Suffixes. MULTITUDE comes from a Latin word meaning _many_, also the source of the word _multiply_. A MULTITUDE is a great number of something. \n\"This wonderful machine can do a MULTITUDE of jobs all at once.\" \n\"There was a MULTITUDE of complaints about the new system of report cards.\" \nWhen used by itself, the word usually means \"a great crowd of people.\" \n\"A MULTITUDE had gathered to hear the president's speech.\""
      },
      "SHUN": {
        "word": "SHUN",
        "phonetic": "(shuhn)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to avoid, stay away from \nSHUN means to _avoid_ or _stay away from_ something, usually because it is hateful, undesirable, or dangerous. You can SHUN both people and things. \n\"His friends SHUNNED him after they learned about his evil past.\" \"She SHUNS work whenever she can.\" \n\"A hermit SHUNS the company of other people.\""
      },
      "AGENDA": {
        "word": "AGENDA",
        "phonetic": "(g-jen'-dg)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an outline, program \nAn AGENDA is a list or outline of things to be done, a plan of procedure. Often a committee will organize its meetings around an AGENDA of subjects to be discussed or business to be carried out. \n\"The chairman made sure that every committee member received an AGENDA before each meeting.\" \n\"The next item on the AGENDA is a discussion of how the money is to be spent.\" \n\"My father called and wanted to know what was on our AGENDA for this weekend\"—that is, he wanted to know what we were planning to do."
      },
      "MATERNAL": {
        "word": "MATERNAL",
        "phonetic": "(m:rter'-ngl)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "motherly \n_Mater_ means _mother_ in Latin. MATERNAL means \"of or like a mother.\" See _-al_ under Suffixes. \n\"She has MATERNAL feelings for her students. She treats them all like her children.\" \n\"Her MATERNAL instincts told her that her children were in trouble.\" \nMATERNAL also means \"on your mother's side of the family.\" Your MATERNAL grandfather is your mother's father."
      },
      "STREW": {
        "word": "STREW",
        "phonetic": "(strU)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to spread, scatter, sprinkle \nTo STREW something is to spread it here and there over a surface. \n\"She STREWED the birdseed on the ground for the pigeons.\" \nSTREW also means \"to cover a surface with scattered things.\" \n\"Pebbles STREW the surface of the road.\" \nThe form STREWN is often used for what is called the _past participle_ of STREW. \n\"The floor was STREWN with books and papers.\" \n\"The child's toys were STREWN over the room.\""
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "BEHOLD",
        "DISCLOSE",
        "GALA",
        "ORATION",
        "STREW",
        "CONDEMN",
        "EARNEST",
        "MANIPULATE",
        "REMOTE",
        "STUPENDOUS",
        "CONQUEST",
        "ELABORATE",
        "MATERNAL",
        "STERN",
        "VENGEANCE",
        "DENOUNCE",
        "EMPLOY",
        "NONCHALANT",
        "STRENUOUS",
        "VULNERABLE",
        "DINGY",
        "ENTAIL",
        "AGENDA",
        "DISTINCT",
        "MURAL",
        "PRELIMINARY",
        "SATANIC",
        "BRISK",
        "ENTERPRISE",
        "OBSCURE",
        "PRIMARILY",
        "SHUN",
        "CALAMITY",
        "ETIQUETTE",
        "OOZE",
        "REMNANT",
        "SUBDUE",
        "COMMERCE",
        "INTERVENE",
        "OPTIMISTIC",
        "RIVALRY",
        "TESTY",
        "CORONATION",
        "MULTITUDE",
        "PERILOUS"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "He knew that becoming a doctor would",
          "part2": "many years of training.",
          "answer": "entail"
        },
        {
          "part1": "In the box was the most beautiful diamond ring she had ever",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "beheld"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He was very",
          "part2": "about winning the championship; you'd think it happened to him every day.",
          "answer": "nonchalant"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The senator gave a long",
          "part2": "about the need for peace in the world.",
          "answer": "oration"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The tablecloth was so",
          "part2": "after years of use that we were ashamed of it.",
          "answer": "dingy"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It is difficult to",
          "part2": "people into doing something they are totally unwilling to do.",
          "answer": "manipulate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He had to",
          "part2": "more carpenters to get the project finished on time.",
          "answer": "employ"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His desire for revenge was uncontrollable; his life was spent seeking",
          "part2": "against the murderers of his father.",
          "answer": "vengeance"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The critics called it a(n)",
          "part2": "play, one of the greatest ever written.",
          "answer": "stupendous"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He is very",
          "part2": "about becoming a millionaire. He is working toward that goal twenty-four hours a day.",
          "answer": "earnest"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her",
          "part2": "instincts were aroused when she saw the little baby crying.",
          "answer": "maternal"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She was afraid to",
          "part2": "the secret information she had about the criminals.",
          "answer": "disclose"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We had a(n)",
          "part2": "celebration to mark the end of the school year.",
          "answer": "gala"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Their army was so tired and hungry that it was quite",
          "part2": "to an attack by the enemy.",
          "answer": "vulnerable"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Their vacation home was in a(n)",
          "part2": "area, far away from noise and traffic.",
          "answer": "remote"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The newspaper",
          "part2": "the new law as a threat to freedom of the press.",
          "answer": "denounced"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The general said it was his soldiers who should get the credit for the",
          "part2": "of the enemy city.",
          "answer": "conquest"
        },
        {
          "part1": "In the cluttered little store, every surface was",
          "part2": "with items for sale.",
          "answer": "strewn"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The rug had a(n)",
          "part2": "pattern in it which had obviously taken years to weave.",
          "answer": "elaborate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "After so much",
          "part2": "activity she was extremely tired.",
          "answer": "strenuous"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His lack of education",
          "part2": "him to a low-paying job.",
          "answer": "condemned"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The judge looked very",
          "part2": "as she walked into the courtroom. We knew she wouldn't put up with any nonsense.",
          "answer": "stern"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The writer was",
          "part2": "and unappreciated during his lifetime, but after his death he became famous.",
          "answer": "obscure"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "results showed him to be the winner, but in the final figures he came in second.",
          "answer": "preliminary"
        },
        {
          "part1": "A few deserted buildings and ruined houses were the only",
          "part2": "of the once-great city.",
          "answer": "remnants"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The Interstate",
          "part2": "Commission regulates the shipment of goods across state lines.",
          "answer": "Commerce"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I think the teacher was being",
          "part2": "when she said we would all be rich and famous.",
          "answer": "optimistic"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The usually pleasant bus driver began to act",
          "part2": "because of the heat and noise and heavy traffic.",
          "answer": "testy"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Only the most important people in the land received invitations to attend the",
          "part2": "of the new king.",
          "answer": "coronation"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Getting through enemy lines was a daring and dangerous",
          "part2": "for the spies.",
          "answer": "enterprise"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The wind was so",
          "part2": "that we had trouble walking into it.",
          "answer": "brisk"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He painted a large",
          "part2": "on one whole wall of his bedroom.",
          "answer": "mural"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Bob managed to",
          "part2": "three of his attackers singlehandedly, and the rest fled in fear.",
          "answer": "subdue"
        },
        {
          "part1": "There was quite a(n)",
          "part2": "among the students to see who would get the scholarship.",
          "answer": "rivalry"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His injury is a(n)",
          "part2": "because the team doesn't have another quarterback.",
          "answer": "calamity"
        },
        {
          "part1": "After they broke up, she",
          "part2": "any further contact with him.",
          "answer": "shunned"
        },
        {
          "part1": "There was a(n)",
          "part2": "of people in the stands for the championship game.",
          "answer": "multitude"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The next item on the committee's",
          "part2": "is a discussion of the financial report.",
          "answer": "agenda"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Jim is",
          "part2": "paid to pump gasoline, although he has other duties as well.",
          "answer": "primarily"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The writing was so",
          "part2": "that I could make it out quite easily, even from the back of the room.",
          "answer": "distinct"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His situation was truly",
          "part2": "He was hanging from the bridge by a thin rope, and the rope was breaking.",
          "answer": "perilous"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Milk",
          "part2": "out of the small hole in the bottom of the carton.",
          "answer": "oozed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The look on his face was truly",
          "part2": "; I felt sure he was going to murder me.",
          "answer": "satanic"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The president decided to",
          "part2": "in the dispute between the union and the industry.",
          "answer": "intervene"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He said it went against legal",
          "part2": "to give advice to both sides in the dispute.",
          "answer": "etiquette"
        }
      ]
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.7",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "This COMPOUND.",
          "answers": [
            "particle",
            "solution",
            "combination",
            "problem",
            "series"
          ],
          "word": "COMPOUND",
          "correct": "combination"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We APPOINTED him.",
          "answers": [
            "demanded",
            "named",
            "favored",
            "accepted",
            "wanted"
          ],
          "word": "APPOINT",
          "correct": "named"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMPENSATE for it.",
          "answers": [
            "watch out",
            "hope",
            "wait",
            "get ready",
            "make up"
          ],
          "word": "COMPENSATE",
          "correct": "make up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were DUMBFOUNDED.",
          "answers": [
            "unwanted",
            "amazed",
            "stupid",
            "bored",
            "excited"
          ],
          "word": "DUMBFOUNDED",
          "correct": "amazed"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The book was ELEVATING.",
          "answers": [
            "uplifting",
            "boring",
            "interesting",
            "exciting",
            "expensive"
          ],
          "word": "ELEVATING",
          "correct": "uplifting"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACKNOWLEDGED his mistake.",
          "answers": [
            "admitted",
            "found",
            "learned",
            "ignored",
            "discussed"
          ],
          "word": "ACKNOWLEDGE",
          "correct": "admitted"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Unusual CLARITY.",
          "answers": [
            "cleverness",
            "closeness",
            "kindness",
            "clearness",
            "darkness"
          ],
          "word": "CLARITY",
          "correct": "clearness"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Please CONDENSE it.",
          "answers": [
            "lengthen",
            "lighten",
            "change",
            "end",
            "shorten"
          ],
          "word": "CONDENSE",
          "correct": "shorten"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IMPARTIAL judges.",
          "answers": [
            "calm",
            "full-time",
            "fair",
            "unfriendly",
            "wise"
          ],
          "word": "IMPARTIAL",
          "correct": "fair"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONTRARY opinions.",
          "answers": [
            "obvious",
            "opposite",
            "mistaken",
            "similar",
            "extreme"
          ],
          "word": "CONTRARY",
          "correct": "opposite"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BARREN effort.",
          "answers": [
            "fruitless",
            "silly",
            "difficult",
            "useful",
            "total"
          ],
          "word": "BARREN",
          "correct": "fruitless"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Spoke to his COMRADE.",
          "answers": [
            "cousin",
            "brother",
            "enemy",
            "friend",
            "leader"
          ],
          "word": "COMRADE",
          "correct": "friend"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To BARTER goods.",
          "answers": [
            "trade",
            "steal",
            "buy",
            "destroy",
            "keep"
          ],
          "word": "BARTER",
          "correct": "trade"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Happened to COINCIDE.",
          "answers": [
            "depart",
            "appear",
            "arrive",
            "differ",
            "agree"
          ],
          "word": "COINCIDE",
          "correct": "agree"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Found the COURIER.",
          "answers": [
            "reporter",
            "messenger",
            "stableboy",
            "knight",
            "prince"
          ],
          "word": "COURIER",
          "correct": "messenger"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Is dog a COMPOUND word?",
          "word": "COMPOUND",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people make APPOINTMENTS to see doctors?",
          "word": "APPOINT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a dollar adequate COMPENSATION for painting a house?",
          "word": "COMPENSATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should people be DUMBFOUNDED if the sun rises in the morning?",
          "word": "DUMBFOUNDED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is stealing money an ELEVATING experience?",
          "word": "ELEVATING",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it polite to ACKNOWLEDGE a favor that someone has done for you?",
          "word": "ACKNOWLEDGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does mud increase water's CLARITY?",
          "word": "CLARITY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does it take less time to read a book if it has been CONDENSED?",
          "word": "CONDENSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are judges supposed to be IMPARTIAL?",
          "word": "IMPARTIAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If a person's belief is CONTRARY to your own, do you agree?",
          "word": "CONTRARY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a BARREN area have many people in it?",
          "word": "BARREN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually dislike their COMRADES?",
          "word": "COMRADE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Will most stores BARTER with you?",
          "word": "BARTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does New Year's Day COINCIDE with Christmas?",
          "word": "COINCIDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a COURIER use a car?",
          "word": "COURIER",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The chemist came up with a new COMPOUND that was the most powerful glue ever invented.",
          "word": "COMPOUND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She APPOINTED at me and said I was the one.",
          "word": "APPOINT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He COMPENSATED for a long time before finally making up his mind.",
          "word": "COMPENSATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He is the most DUMBFOUNDED person I know. He can't add two and two.",
          "word": "DUMBFOUNDED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Although the speech was both informative and ELEVATING, many people slipped out before it was over.",
          "word": "ELEVATING",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The suspect refused to ACKNOWLEDGE that he had done anything wrong.",
          "word": "ACKNOWLEDGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They don't know English very well, so you must speak slowly and with CLARITY.",
          "word": "CLARITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The school CONDENSED the six-month course so that now it takes a year.",
          "word": "CONDENSE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We became very IMPARTIAL for him to arrive after we had been waiting for two hours.",
          "word": "IMPARTIAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The boy is so CONTRARY that he won't do anything the teacher asks him to do.",
          "word": "CONTRARY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His efforts were completely BARREN; he had nothing to show for his work.",
          "word": "BARREN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were my COMRADES in the army; now I never see them any more.",
          "word": "COMRADE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He thought that getting a car in exchange for a few old chairs was a good BARTER.",
          "word": "BARTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The two cars arrived at the corner at the same time and COINCIDED with a loud crash.",
          "word": "COINCIDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The COURIER had to slip through enemy territory to bring the news to headquarters.",
          "word": "COURIER",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "COMPOUND",
          "answers": [
            "fixture",
            "combination",
            "mixture"
          ],
          "word": "COMPOUND",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "APPOINT",
          "answers": [
            "expect",
            "choose",
            "select"
          ],
          "word": "APPOINT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMPENSATE",
          "answers": [
            "offset",
            "refuse",
            "repay"
          ],
          "word": "COMPENSATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DUMBFOUNDED",
          "answers": [
            "speechless",
            "worried",
            "astonished"
          ],
          "word": "DUMBFOUNDED",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ELEVATING",
          "answers": [
            "uplifting",
            "exalting",
            "hoisting"
          ],
          "word": "ELEVATING",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACKNOWLEDGE",
          "answers": [
            "approve",
            "recognize",
            "confess"
          ],
          "word": "ACKNOWLEDGE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CLARITY",
          "answers": [
            "clearness",
            "distinctness",
            "separation"
          ],
          "word": "CLARITY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONDENSE",
          "answers": [
            "destroy",
            "reduce",
            "shrink"
          ],
          "word": "CONDENSE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IMPARTIAL",
          "answers": [
            "fair",
            "wise",
            "just"
          ],
          "word": "IMPARTIAL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONTRARY",
          "answers": [
            "stubborn",
            "contradictory",
            "unusual"
          ],
          "word": "CONTRARY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BARREN",
          "answers": [
            "funny",
            "empty",
            "bare"
          ],
          "word": "BARREN",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMRADE",
          "answers": [
            "associate",
            "cousin",
            "companion"
          ],
          "word": "COMRADE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BARTER",
          "answers": [
            "swap",
            "exchange",
            "return"
          ],
          "word": "BARTER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COINCIDE",
          "answers": [
            "approach",
            "correspond",
            "match"
          ],
          "word": "COINCIDE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COURIER",
          "answers": [
            "information",
            "television",
            "message"
          ],
          "word": "COURIER",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "COMPOUND": {
        "word": "COMPOUND",
        "phonetic": "(kom'-pownd)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a combination, mixture \nA COMPOUND is something formed by combining different parts or ingredients. See _con-_ under Prefixes. \n\"Water is a COMPOUND of oxygen and hydrogen.\" \n\"His book is a COMPOUND of interesting facts and silly theories.\" \nCOMPOUND _words_, such as storeroom and outside, are words that are made up of other words. \nCOMPOUND is also a verb, meaning \"to make a mixture.\" \n\"The druggist COMPOUNDED the medicine out of several others.\" \nThe verb also means simply to _add to_, _increase_. \n\"Our latest attempt at a solution simply COMPOUNDED our problems.\""
      },
      "APPOINT": {
        "word": "APPOINT",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩpoynt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to name, designate \nTo APPOINT someone is to name him to a job or a position. \n\"The president APPOINTED him to be his personal secretary.\" \n\"Jim was APPOINTED class treasurer by the teacher.\" \nTo APPOINT is also to fix or choose a time for an event. \n\"We were all there at the APPOINTED time, ready to begin work.\" \nAn APPOINTMENT is the act of APPOINTING. \n\"He opposed the APPOINTMENT of that judge to the Supreme Court.\" \nIt is especially used to mean \"an agreed-upon arrangement for a meeting.\" \n\"They had an APPOINTMENT to eat lunch together on Thursday.\" \nOther forms of the word: APPOINTMENT, n."
      },
      "COMPENSATE": {
        "word": "COMPENSATE",
        "phonetic": "(kom'-p:m-sAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to make up, offset, balance; to pay, pay back \nTo COMPENSATE for something is to make up for it. \n\"She COMPENSATED for being unable to use her legs by getting a special car with hand controls.\" \n\"You can't COMPENSATE for weeks of not studying by staying up and reading all night just before the exam.\" \nVery often COMPENSATE refers to money which is used to make up for loss or injury. \n\"The company paid Sam a thousand dollars to COMPENSATE him for the injury he suffered at work.\" \nThe noun form of COMPENSATE is COMPENSATION, which is something given, usually money, to make up for something else. \n\"She had to sue to get the COMPENSATION due her for the accident.\" \n\"He receives adequate COMPENSATION for the work he does.\" \nOther forms of the word: COMPENSATION, n."
      },
      "DUMBFOUNDED": {
        "word": "DUMBFOUNDED",
        "phonetic": "(duhm'-fown-ded)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "amazed, astonished, puzzled \nThe word DUMB has two meanings. The first is \"not able to speak,\" _speechless_, as in the phrase \"deaf and DUMB.\" The second is _stupid_, _dull_. DUMBFOUNDED comes from the first meaning. To be DUMBFOUNDED is to be so surprised and puzzled that you are speechless. \n\"We were DUMBFOUNDED when we discovered that the treasure was missing.\" \n\"The DUMBFOUNDED explorers could only stare in wonder at the palace they had discovered in the middle of the jungle.\" \nThe most common mistake on the Pretest is the choice of _stupid_ as the meaning of DUMBFOUNDED—due to confusion, of course, with the second meaning of DUMB. \nOther forms of the word: DUMBFOUND, v. \nUsage: DUMBFOUNDED is also often spelled _dumfounded_."
      },
      "ELEVATING": {
        "word": "ELEVATING",
        "phonetic": "(el'-ÔøΩvAt-ing)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "uplifting, exalting \nTo ELEVATE something is to lift it up higher. The adjective ELEVATING means \"tending to lift up minds or morals.\" The word is almost never used about something that is physically being lifted. \n\"The minister gave a very ELEVATING sermon which left everyone determined to lead better lives.\" \n\"Alice said her visit to the art museum had been an ELEVATING experience.\" \nOther forms of the word: ELEVATE,v."
      },
      "ACKNOWLEDGE": {
        "word": "ACKNOWLEDGE",
        "phonetic": "(ak-nol'-ij",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to admit, confess; to recognize, accept \nYou can see the word _knowledge_ in ACKNOWLEDGE. ACKNOWLEDGE has two rather different uses that deal with _knowledge_. First, to ACKNOWLEDGE something is to admit you have knowledge of it, to state or agree that it exists or has happened. \n\"By signing the form, he ACKNOWLEDGED receipt of the package from the post office.\" \n\"The criminal ACKNOWLEDGED his guilt and begged for another chance.\" \nSecond, to ACKNOWLEDGE can mean to _take notice of_. Often the word is used about a gift or letter, to show that you have received it. \n\"She sent them a short note ACKNOWLEDGING their present and thanking them for their thoughtfulness.\" \nACKNOWLEDGE in this sense can also be used about responsibilities or duties to show that you recognize and accept them. \n\"Bill ACKNOWLEDGED his obligation to help the poor in any way he could.\" \nOther forms of the word: ACKNOWLEDGMENT, n."
      },
      "CLARITY": {
        "word": "CLARITY",
        "phonetic": "(klar'-ÔøΩtE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "clearness, distinctness \nCLARITY is the quality of being clear. The word can be used about things that are clear to the eye or clear to the mind. \n\"The water was of such CLARITY that you could see all the way to the bottom of the lake.\" \n\"The photograph lacked CLARITY. We couldn't make out any of the faces.\" \n\"He presented his arguments with great CLARITY. Everyone could follow him quite easily.\""
      },
      "CONDENSE": {
        "word": "CONDENSE",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-dens')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to shorten, compress, abridge \nCONDENSE is related to the word _dense_, which means \"packed tightly together.\" When something CONDENSES,it occupies less space,it becomes denser or more compact. The word is used about gases which turn into liquids. \n\"The steam CONDENSED to water when it reached the cold window.\" \nCONDENSE is also used about written material or other kinds of information. To CONDENSE it is to make it shorter, to abridge it. \n\"We don't have time to hear that long report. Could you CONDENSE it into a few sentences?\" \n\"They had to CONDENSE twenty hours of film into a half-hour television show.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONDENSATION, n."
      },
      "IMPARTIAL": {
        "word": "IMPARTIAL",
        "phonetic": "(im-pahr'-shÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "fair, unbiased, just \nSee _in-2_ under Prefixes. One meaning of _partial_ is \"favoring one person or side more than the other.\" \n\"He admitted that he was partial to people with a sense of humor.\" \nSomeone who is IMPARTIAL shows no favoritism, is strictly fair and unprejudiced. \n\"We want an IMPARTIAL jury. We don't want people who have made up their minds ahead of time.\" \n\"They couldn't agree among themselves, so they brought the problem to an IMPARTIAL outsider and let him decide.\" \n\"It's hard to be IMPARTIAL when you know someone who's involved in the case.\" \nOther forms of the word: IMPARTIALITY,n."
      },
      "CONTRARY": {
        "word": "CONTRARY",
        "phonetic": "(kon'-trer-E)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "opposite, opposed; stubborn, self-willed \nSomething that is CONTRARY to something else is opposed to it, is the total opposite of it. \n\"You may think he is kind, but I have heard a CONTRARY opinion from someone else.\" \n\"CONTRARY to what you might have expected, I passed the course quite easily.\" \n\"The two candidates held CONTRARY views on many issues.\" \nCONTRARY can also be used about a person who is very self-willed and is always doing or saying the opposite of what people want or suggest. \n\"She's a CONTRARY child. We can never get her to obey.\""
      },
      "BARREN": {
        "word": "BARREN",
        "phonetic": "(bar'-an)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "empty, fruitless \nBARREN has several uses, all of which have the idea of _empty_, _fruitless_, or _unproductive_. Land which is BARREN is no good for growing crops; it is unproductive. BARREN land is also often very difficult for people or animals to survive in, because it is too cold or windy or desert-like. BARREN trees or plants do not produce fruit or seeds. BARREN discussions have no results; they are empty and worthless. \n\"We had several BARREN conversations about the matter; we never came to any conclusion about what should be done.\""
      },
      "COMRADE": {
        "word": "COMRADE",
        "phonetic": "(kom'-rad)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a friend, companion \nA COMRADE is a friend or companion, someone who is loyal to you and whom you see often. \n\"They became friends when they were in the fifth grade and remained COMRADES for life.\" \n\"She was my COMRADE in school. We went everywhere together; we were almost never apart.\" \n\"His trusted COMRADE turned against him and betrayed him.\" \nCOMRADE is a usual form of address used by Communists. \n\"COMRADE Ustinov will give a speech at the next meeting of the Communist party.\" \nThis may lead many people to choose _enemy_ or _leader_ as a synonym for COMRADE."
      },
      "BARTER": {
        "word": "BARTER",
        "phonetic": "(bahr'-tar)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to trade, exchange \nWhen you BARTER you trade goods or services for what you want instead of using money. \n\"In 'Jack and the Beanstalk,' Jack BARTERED the family's cow for a handful of beans. His mother thought it was a bad trade.\" \n\"The farmer BARTERED the use of his tractor in exchange for part of the crop.\" \nBARTER is also a noun meaning a _trade_ or _exchange_. \n\"The doctor decided that having his cellar cleaned was a good BARTER for fixing Dan's broken arm.\""
      },
      "COINCIDE": {
        "word": "COINCIDE",
        "phonetic": "(kO-an-sld')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to agree, be the same, correspond; to happen at the same time \nWhen two things COINCIDE, they are in agreement or in harmony with one another. In this sense, COINCIDE is generally used about opinions, wishes, judgments, or the like. \n\"Your views on politics COINCIDE completely with my own.\" \n\"The teacher's opinion of the boy did not COINCIDE with his parents' opinion of him.\" \nCOINCIDE also means \"to happen at the same time.\" \n\"His arrival at the airport COINCIDED with a strike by the pilots.\" \n\"Her birthday and mine COINCIDE.\" \nA COINCIDENCE is a chance occurrence of two events at the same time. \n\"It was a strange COINCIDENCE that the two old friends should both be in the foreign city on business.\" \nOther forms of the word: COINCIDENCE, n."
      },
      "COURIER": {
        "word": "COURIER",
        "phonetic": "(kuhr'-E-ar)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a messenger \nCOURIER comes from a French word which means to _run_. A COURIER is someone who carries messages or information. A COURIER doesn't necessarily run, but the word often suggests speed and urgency. \n\"The general sent a COURIER ahead to tell the fort that more troops were on their way.\" \n\"The COURIER arrived at the palace with the secret papers.\" \n\"Each morning the COURIER brought them reports on the military situation.\""
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.8",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "TIMID children.",
          "answers": [
            "fearful",
            "brave",
            "lonely",
            "well-behaved",
            "pretty"
          ],
          "word": "TIMID",
          "correct": "fearful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SPLINTER the board.",
          "answers": [
            "smooth down",
            "drop",
            "break up",
            "take away",
            "repair"
          ],
          "word": "SPLINTER",
          "correct": "break up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Typical PROVERB.",
          "answers": [
            "answer",
            "country",
            "story",
            "action",
            "saying"
          ],
          "word": "PROVERB",
          "correct": "saying"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Said it was INFECTIOUS.",
          "answers": [
            "curable",
            "sugary",
            "catching",
            "exciting",
            "deadly"
          ],
          "word": "INFECTIOUS",
          "correct": "catching"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Among the POPULACE.",
          "answers": [
            "businessmen",
            "winners",
            "families",
            "common people",
            "best"
          ],
          "word": "POPULACE",
          "correct": "common people"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Had to REVISE it.",
          "answers": [
            "change",
            "increase",
            "repeat",
            "inspect",
            "start"
          ],
          "word": "REVISE",
          "correct": "change"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MONUMENTAL proportions.",
          "answers": [
            "artistic",
            "immense",
            "tiny",
            "unknown",
            "basic"
          ],
          "word": "MONUMENTAL",
          "correct": "immense"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She PONDERED the incident.",
          "answers": [
            "feared",
            "forgot",
            "imagined",
            "considered",
            "wrote about"
          ],
          "word": "PONDER",
          "correct": "considered"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SCORNED them.",
          "answers": [
            "suspected",
            "admired",
            "burned",
            "advised",
            "despised"
          ],
          "word": "SCORN",
          "correct": "despised"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REIMBURSE them.",
          "answers": [
            "repay",
            "satisfy",
            "back",
            "plead with",
            "relieve"
          ],
          "word": "REIMBURSE",
          "correct": "repay"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBSTINATE boys.",
          "answers": [
            "stubborn",
            "lazy",
            "mean",
            "obedient",
            "angry"
          ],
          "word": "OBSTINATE",
          "correct": "stubborn"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Unusual VELOCITY.",
          "answers": [
            "depth",
            "power",
            "size",
            "speed",
            "slowness"
          ],
          "word": "VELOCITY",
          "correct": "speed"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was PERPLEXED.",
          "answers": [
            "excited",
            "overlooked",
            "enraged",
            "relieved",
            "confused"
          ],
          "word": "PERPLEX",
          "correct": "confused"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Their PEDIGREE.",
          "answers": [
            "talent",
            "ancestry",
            "beauty",
            "future",
            "size"
          ],
          "word": "PEDIGREE",
          "correct": "ancestry"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INFORMAL visits.",
          "answers": [
            "daily",
            "unimportant",
            "unofficial",
            "necessary",
            "educational"
          ],
          "word": "INFORMAL",
          "correct": "unofficial"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Are heroes usually TIMID?",
          "word": "TIMID",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you SPLINTER ice cream?",
          "word": "SPLINTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are PROVERBS usually new?",
          "word": "PROVERB",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a sprained ankle INFECTIOUS?",
          "word": "INFECTIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are most people part of the POPULACE?",
          "word": "POPULACE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can books be REVISED?",
          "word": "REVISE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a MONUMENTAL mistake be easy to fix?",
          "word": "MONUMENTAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually PONDER things quickly?",
          "word": "PONDER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it pleasant to be SCORNED?",
          "word": "SCORN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a person earn a lot of money by being REIMBURSED?",
          "word": "REIMBURSE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it difficult to change the mind of an OBSTINATE person?",
          "word": "OBSTINATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does using the brake of a car increase its VELOCITY?",
          "word": "VELOCITY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a riddle PERPLEX a person?",
          "word": "PERPLEX",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a prince have a distinguished PEDIGREE?",
          "word": "PEDIGREE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a picnic usually be INFORMAL?",
          "word": "INFORMAL",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He TIMIDLY tasted the octopus soup, and then discovered he liked it.",
          "word": "TIMID",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We used tweezers to get the SPLINTERS out of his knee.",
          "word": "SPLINTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He said that this latest problem was the PROVERBIAL straw that broke the camel's back.",
          "word": "PROVERB",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His INFECTIOUS enthusiasm made everyone want to try harder.",
          "word": "INFECTIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The president could not convince the POPULACE that they should pay higher taxes.",
          "word": "POPULACE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He REVISED us again that we would be in trouble if we didn't agree.",
          "word": "REVISE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He claimed his invention was of MONUMENTAL importance.",
          "word": "MONUMENTAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She PONDERED why he could be acting so strangely.",
          "word": "PONDER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The coach feels nothing but SCORN for players who don't try as hard as they can.",
          "word": "SCORN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We offered to REIMBURSE him, but he said he had spent too little money for us to worry about it.",
          "word": "REIMBURSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The lock proved to be quite OBSTINATE, so finally we had to break the door down.",
          "word": "OBSTINATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The arrows hit the target at different times because each had a different VELOCITY.",
          "word": "VELOCITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She PERPLEXED us to stop talking during class.",
          "word": "PERPLEX",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Since the dog had no PEDIGREE, we decided not to buy him.",
          "word": "PEDIGREE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The president met INFORMALLY with the two reporters this morning, but his official news conference isn't until this afternoon.",
          "word": "INFORMAL",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "TIMID",
          "answers": [
            "nervous",
            "lost",
            "bashful"
          ],
          "word": "TIMID",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SPLINTER",
          "answers": [
            "wood",
            "cloth",
            "glass"
          ],
          "word": "SPLINTER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PROVERB",
          "answers": [
            "joke",
            "saying",
            "adage"
          ],
          "word": "PROVERB",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INFECTIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "spreading",
            "growing",
            "improving"
          ],
          "word": "INFECTIOUS",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "POPULACE",
          "answers": [
            "family",
            "people",
            "crowd"
          ],
          "word": "POPULACE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REVISE",
          "answers": [
            "review",
            "correct",
            "reject"
          ],
          "word": "REVISE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MONUMENTAL",
          "answers": [
            "huge",
            "important",
            "strange"
          ],
          "word": "MONUMENTAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PONDER",
          "answers": [
            "reflect",
            "expect",
            "think"
          ],
          "word": "PONDER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SCORN",
          "answers": [
            "hate",
            "enjoy",
            "refuse"
          ],
          "word": "SCORN",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REIMBURSE",
          "answers": [
            "refund",
            "recover",
            "repay"
          ],
          "word": "REIMBURSE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBSTINATE",
          "answers": [
            "stupid",
            "unyielding",
            "dogged"
          ],
          "word": "OBSTINATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VELOCITY",
          "answers": [
            "excitement",
            "rapidity",
            "speed"
          ],
          "word": "VELOCITY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERPLEX",
          "answers": [
            "puzzle",
            "mystify",
            "anger"
          ],
          "word": "PERPLEX",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PEDIGREE",
          "answers": [
            "lineage",
            "education",
            "parents"
          ],
          "word": "PEDIGREE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INFORMAL",
          "answers": [
            "unplanned",
            "useless",
            "casual"
          ],
          "word": "INFORMAL",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "TIMID": {
        "word": "TIMID",
        "phonetic": "()",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "fearful, easily frightened, shy \nTIMID means _fearful_, _easily frightened_, _easily alarmed_. \n\"He became very TIMID about riding in elevators after he was stuck in one once.\" \n\"She looks TIMID, but she can really be quite brave when she needs to be.\" \nTIMID often adds to _fearful_ the idea of _shyness_. \n\"He greeted his grandfather with a TIMID smile.\" \n\"She is very TIMID at large parties.\" \nOther forms of the word: TIMIDITY, n."
      },
      "SPLINTER": {
        "word": "SPLINTER",
        "phonetic": "(splin'-tÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to break up, split into pieces, break off \nA SPLINTER is a little piece of something, usually wood. \n\"You're apt to get SPLINTERS in your fingers when you're working with wood.\" \nSPLINTER, when used as a verb, means \"to break into very small pieces.\" \n\"The wall SPLINTERED with just one blow from the heavy hammer.\" \n\"The icicles SPLINTERED when they hit the ground.\" \n\"He could SPLINTER a board with his bare hand.\""
      },
      "PROVERB": {
        "word": "PROVERB",
        "phonetic": "(prov'-erb)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a saying, maxim, adage \nA PROVERB is a short saying that uses simple, vivid language to express some ancient wisdom. Some examples of PROVERBS are \"Look before you leap,\" \"A rolling stone gathers no moss,\" and \"Still waters run deep.\" \nSomething that is so well known that it has become a PROVERB is called PROVERBIAL. \n\"She talked about the PROVERBIAL curiosity of a cat.\" \nThe most common mistake for the meaning of PROVERB on the Pretest is _story_. A PROVERB is never more than a sentence or two long. It does not tell a story, but gives some general truth. \nOther forms of the word: PROVERBIAL, adj."
      },
      "REVISE": {
        "word": "REVISE",
        "phonetic": "(ri-vlz')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to change, correct \nREVISE basically means \"to look back at.\" See _re-_ under Prefixes. The _vise_ part of the word is related to words like _vision_. To REVISE something is to look it over or reexamine it and make changes and corrections. \n\"He REVISED his composition so that it made better sense.\" \n\"The new figures caused them to REVISE their estimate of how much the job would cost.\" \n\"When he started being nice to everyone we had to REVISE our bad opinion of him.\" \nOther forms of the word: REVISION, n."
      },
      "INFECTIOUS": {
        "word": "INFECTIOUS",
        "phonetic": "(in-fek'-shÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "catching, contagious \nTo INFECT someone is to contaminate him with disease-producing germs. \n\"Mosquitoes INFECTED the natives with malaria.\" \n\"The wound became INFECTED when he didn't keep it clean.\" \nINFECTIOUS is an adjective from INFECT. See _-ous_ under Suffixes. An INFECTIOUS disease is one that spreads by INFECTING, like the flu or smallpox. INFECTIOUS is also used in a general way and means \"spreading quickly,\" _catching_. \n\"Yawning is INFECTIOUS. Once one person starts, everyone begins to do it.\" \n\"He had an INFECTIOUS laugh that caused everyone to laugh with him.\" \n_Deadly_ is the most commonly chosen incorrect answer on the Pretest. INFECTIOUS diseases are communicated by germs. Some of these diseases are deadly, others are not. \nOther forms of the word: INFECT, v. INFECTION, n."
      },
      "POPULACE": {
        "word": "POPULACE",
        "phonetic": "(pop'-yÔøΩlis)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "the common people, the general public \nPOPULACE comes from the Latin word for _people_, also the source of the words _population_ and _popular_. The POPULACE is the common people, as opposed to the wealthy or the noble. \n\"The politician's plan appealed to the POPULACE, although big business was against it.\" \n\"Although the king now had less power, the POPULACE still did not like him.\" \nPOPULACE is also used for the entire population of a place. \n\"It seemed as if the whole POPULACE of the town had turned out to greet him.\""
      },
      "MONUMENTAL": {
        "word": "MONUMENTAL",
        "phonetic": "(mon-yU-ment'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "immense, massive, imposing \nA MONUMENT is a large building, statue, or other object which serves to keep alive the memory of a person or event. \n\"The Washington MONUMENT is a great tribute to our first president.\" \nMONUMENTAL means \"having the size and impressiveness of a MONUMENT,\" _massive_, _immense_. See _-al_ under Suffixes. \n\"It was a MONUMENTAL structure, almost a hundred stories high.\" \n\"They made a mistake of MONUMENTAL proportions. They almost ruined the entire project.\" \n\"Building the Panama Canal was a MONUMENTAL achievement.\" \nOther forms of the word: MONUMENT, n."
      },
      "PONDER": {
        "word": "PONDER",
        "phonetic": "(pon'-dÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to consider, reflect, meditate, deliberate \nPONDER comes from a Latin word meaning to _weigh_. PONDER means \"to weigh carefully in the mind.\" \n\"He PONDERED the decision for a long time before acting.\" \n\"Sally PONDERED whether to save her money or buy a new dress.\" \nPONDER is sometimes followed by _over_ or _on_, in which case it means to _think deeply_, to _meditate_. \n\"She PONDERED over the mysteries of life.\" \n\"He PONDERED on the importance of planning ahead.\""
      },
      "SCORN": {
        "word": "SCORN",
        "phonetic": "(skorn)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to despise, feel contempt for; refuse SCORN is both a verb and a noun. To SCORN something is to despise it, to treat it or consider it with contempt. \n\"Everyone SCORNED him for his laziness.\" \nYou can also SCORN something and refuse to do it because it is worthless or beneath you. \n\"Although she needs the money, she SCORNS offers of jobs as a cleaning person.\" \nWhen SCORN is used as a noun, it means \"a feeling of contempt.\" \n\"She has a great deal of SCORN for people who lie about their ages.\" \nOther forms of the word: SCORNFUL, adj."
      },
      "REIMBURSE": {
        "word": "REIMBURSE",
        "phonetic": "(rE-im-bers')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to pay back, repay \nSee _re-_ and _in-1_ under Prefixes. The _burse_ part of the word is related to the word _purse_. The basic meaning of the word is \"to put back into someone's purse,\" that is, to _repay_ someone. Usually the word is used about paying money to a person who has already had to spend some of his own. \n\"The company REIMBURSED him for the money he spent on the trip.\" \n\"We will gladly REIMBURSE you for the cost of the phone calls.\" \n\"He bought the plane ticket himself, expecting to be REIMBURSED later.\" \nThe most commonly chosen incorrect answer on the Pretest is _back up_. This is probably chosen because REIMBURSE sounds like _reinforce_."
      },
      "OBSTINATE": {
        "word": "OBSTINATE",
        "phonetic": "(ob'-stÔøΩnit)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "stubborn, unyielding \nOBSTINATE people do not yield to another's arguments or persuasion. They hold fast to their own ideas or plans. The word often suggests that OBSTINATE people are being unreasonable in not changing their minds or listening to others. \n\"The OBSTINATE mule wouldn't move until its master fed him.\" \n\"He OBSTINATELY refused to see a doctor until it was too late.\" \nSomething that is OBSTINATE is not easily overcome or removed. \n\"Their OBSTINATE resistance to change finally forced them to go out of business.\" \n\"His illness was quite OBSTINATE; despite all the treatment he still didn't get better.\" \nOther forms of the word: OBSTINACY, n."
      },
      "VELOCITY": {
        "word": "VELOCITY",
        "phonetic": "(v:rlos'-:rtE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "speed, quickness \nVELOCITY is the speed of something along a given path. \n\"The car traveled at a VELOCITY of fifty miles an hour.\" \n\"They had an instrument which measured the VELOCITY of a baseball thrown by a pitcher.\" \n\"The wind is blowing in an easterly direction at a VELOCITY of 25 miles per hour.\""
      },
      "PERPLEX": {
        "word": "PERPLEX",
        "phonetic": "(pÔøΩr-pleks')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to confuse, bewilder, puzzle \nTo PERPLEX someone is to confuse and puzzle him. The word usually suggests a problem that worries and frustrates a person. \n\"The teacher's questions PERPLEXED him until he suddenly hit upon the answer.\" \n\"We have several PERPLEXING problems that we must somehow solve.\" \n\"I'm PERPLEXED by your attitude. I just don't understand why you're acting this way.\" \nPERPLEXED is also an adjective. \n\"The PERPLEXED young man didn't know which way to turn for help.\" \nPERPLEXITY is the state of being PERPLEXED. \n\"He admitted his PERPLEXITY at the strange way she was behaving.\" \nOther forms of the word: PERPLEXITY, n."
      },
      "PEDIGREE": {
        "word": "PEDIGREE",
        "phonetic": "(ped'-:rgrE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "ancestry, family descent \nA PEDIGREE is the ancestry of a person or animal, or a record of that ancestry. The word usually suggests a noble or distinguished family tree. The word is especially used in reference to animals, where it stresses proof of pure breeding for many generations. \n\"She insisted that any dog she bought should have a PEDIGREE.\" \n\"They were very proud of their family's long PEDIGREE.\""
      },
      "INFORMAL": {
        "word": "INFORMAL",
        "phonetic": "(in-for'-mÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "not formal, unofficial \nSee _in-2_ under Prefixes. FORMAL means \"following the rules or customs.\" Something which is INFORMAL is done without ceremony or great attention to the rules. \n\"They held some INFORMAL discussions before starting the official meeting.\" \n\"There was an INFORMAL investigation into the cause of the fire, but no report was ever written.\" \n\"He gave a brief, INFORMAL talk about his trip to Europe.\" \nMany people think INFORMAL means _unimportant_. An INFORMAL meeting or discussion could, however, be quite important. \nOther forms of the word: INFORMALITY, n."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.9",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Was it CREDIBLE?",
          "answers": [
            "delicious",
            "true",
            "believable",
            "false",
            "readable"
          ],
          "word": "CREDIBLE",
          "correct": "believable"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The LEGITIMATE king.",
          "answers": [
            "cruel",
            "popular",
            "false",
            "confident",
            "lawful"
          ],
          "word": "LEGITIMATE",
          "correct": "lawful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She UNEARTHED it.",
          "answers": [
            "imagined",
            "needed",
            "lost",
            "discovered",
            "overheard"
          ],
          "word": "UNEARTH",
          "correct": "discovered"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UNFURL the flag.",
          "answers": [
            "open out",
            "wave",
            "fold",
            "hang",
            "roll up"
          ],
          "word": "UNFURL",
          "correct": "open out"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Always PRIM.",
          "answers": [
            "neat",
            "happy",
            "healthy",
            "thin",
            "sloppy"
          ],
          "word": "PRIM",
          "correct": "neat"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His HABITUAL place.",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "favorite",
            "regular",
            "chosen",
            "old"
          ],
          "word": "HABITUAL",
          "correct": "regular"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PUTRID food.",
          "answers": [
            "cheap",
            "raw",
            "burnt",
            "fresh",
            "rotten"
          ],
          "word": "PUTRID",
          "correct": "rotten"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Moved by the PAGEANTRY.",
          "answers": [
            "ancient gods",
            "grand display",
            "feasts",
            "foot soldiers",
            "barrenness"
          ],
          "word": "PAGEANTRY",
          "correct": "grand display"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To HERALD his arrival.",
          "answers": [
            "threaten",
            "long for",
            "talk about",
            "announce",
            "expect"
          ],
          "word": "HERALD",
          "correct": "announce"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ENDORSE the plan.",
          "answers": [
            "support",
            "write out",
            "disagree with",
            "begin",
            "receive"
          ],
          "word": "ENDORSE",
          "correct": "support"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Aware of the UPRISING.",
          "answers": [
            "defeat",
            "riot",
            "cheering",
            "rebellion",
            "raid"
          ],
          "word": "UPRISING",
          "correct": "rebellion"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PROMINENT people.",
          "answers": [
            "well-known",
            "wise",
            "well-liked",
            "forgotten",
            "rich"
          ],
          "word": "PROMINENT",
          "correct": "well-known"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They MIMIC her.",
          "answers": [
            "trick",
            "laugh at",
            "copy",
            "like",
            "love"
          ],
          "word": "MIMIC",
          "correct": "copy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Suspected LUNACY.",
          "answers": [
            "illness",
            "robbery",
            "madness",
            "danger",
            "brilliance"
          ],
          "word": "LUNACY",
          "correct": "madness"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The teacher was ACCESSIBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "believable",
            "kind",
            "impossible",
            "approachable",
            "unfriendly"
          ],
          "word": "ACCESSIBLE",
          "correct": "approachable"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "If someone said he could run a hundred miles an hour, would most people find that CREDIBLE?",
          "word": "CREDIBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a LEGITIMATE excuse be made up?",
          "word": "LEGITIMATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you UNEARTH something by burying it?",
          "word": "UNEARTH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you UNFURL a flag by rolling it up?",
          "word": "UNFURL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a hobo usually be PRIM?",
          "word": "PRIM",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a HABITUAL smoker smoke very often?",
          "word": "HABITUAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is PUTRID food bad to eat?",
          "word": "PUTRID",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would you expect a lot of PAGEANTRY in a parade?",
          "word": "PAGEANTRY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is the first snowfall a HERALD of summer?",
          "word": "HERALD",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you ENDORSE a check by ripping it up?",
          "word": "ENDORSE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Was World War II an UPRISING?",
          "word": "UPRISING",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do rabbits have PROMINENT ears?",
          "word": "PROMINENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do parakeets MIMIC human speech?",
          "word": "MIMIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are LUNATICS sometimes dangerous?",
          "word": "LUNACY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is the North Pole ACCESSIBLE by automobile?",
          "word": "ACCESSIBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Their success has been so CREDIBLE that we still can't believe it.",
          "word": "CREDIBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The contest isn't LEGITIMATE: the winners have been picked already.",
          "word": "LEGITIMATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It took several years to UNEARTH the cause of the strange disease.",
          "word": "UNEARTH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The ship set out with all her sails UNFURLED and billowing in the breeze.",
          "word": "UNFURL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He's so PRIM and proper he'd think that wrestling in the mud was the most disgusting thing in the world.",
          "word": "PRIM",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "As usual he performed his HABITUAL morning exercises.",
          "word": "HABITUAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Meat will turn PUTRID if not cooked or frozen.",
          "word": "PUTRID",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "After a while he became bored by all the PAGEANTRY and longed for something simpler.",
          "word": "PAGEANTRY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The development of the polio vaccine HERALDED the conquest of that terrible disease.",
          "word": "HERALD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The mayor ENDORSED the police department's efforts to reduce crime.",
          "word": "ENDORSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The government is just too strong; an UPRISING against it would have no chance of success.",
          "word": "UPRISING",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was a PROMINENT person, always saying he would do something and never getting around to it.",
          "word": "PROMINENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He liked to MIMIC the unusual way the teacher walked.",
          "word": "MIMIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone admired her quiet LUNACY.",
          "word": "LUNACY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We placed all our medicines in a place that was INACCESSIBLE to the baby.",
          "word": "ACCESSIBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "CREDIBLE",
          "answers": [
            "smart",
            "believable",
            "reliable"
          ],
          "word": "CREDIBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LEGITIMATE",
          "answers": [
            "expected",
            "real",
            "reasonable"
          ],
          "word": "LEGITIMATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UNEARTH",
          "answers": [
            "wash",
            "find",
            "uncover"
          ],
          "word": "UNEARTH",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UNFURL",
          "answers": [
            "unroll",
            "unravel",
            "unfold"
          ],
          "word": "UNFURL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PRIM",
          "answers": [
            "stuffy",
            "tidy",
            "silly"
          ],
          "word": "PRIM",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HABITUAL",
          "answers": [
            "casual",
            "usual",
            "regular"
          ],
          "word": "HABITUAL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PUTRID",
          "answers": [
            "decaying",
            "dying",
            "stinking"
          ],
          "word": "PUTRID",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PAGEANTRY",
          "answers": [
            "necessity",
            "splendor",
            "magnificence"
          ],
          "word": "PAGEANTRY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HERALD",
          "answers": [
            "announce",
            "decide",
            "advertise"
          ],
          "word": "HERALD",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENDORSE",
          "answers": [
            "reverse",
            "sign",
            "support"
          ],
          "word": "ENDORSE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UPRISING",
          "answers": [
            "argument",
            "revolt",
            "mutiny"
          ],
          "word": "UPRISING",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PROMINENT",
          "answers": [
            "common",
            "famous",
            "obvious"
          ],
          "word": "PROMINENT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MIMIC",
          "answers": [
            "imitate",
            "change",
            "mock"
          ],
          "word": "MIMIC",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LUNACY",
          "answers": [
            "craziness",
            "wildness",
            "cleverness"
          ],
          "word": "LUNACY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACCESSIBLE",
          "answers": [
            "near",
            "bright",
            "easy"
          ],
          "word": "ACCESSIBLE",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "CREDIBLE": {
        "word": "CREDIBLE",
        "phonetic": "(kred'-ÔøΩ-bJI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "believable, trustworthy \nSee _-able_ under Suffixes. The _cred_ part of the word comes from the Latin word for _believe_. Something which is CREDIBLE is able to be believed. \n\"His explanation of why he was late was CREDIBLE.\" \n\"His story about being captured by Martians was not very CREDIBLE.\" \nSomeone who is CREDIBLE is trustworthy and can be believed. \n\"A CREDIBLE witness says she saw him somewhere else, so I guess he didn't commit the crime.\" \nMany people select _true_ as the meaning of CREDIBLE on the Pretest. Something that is CREDIBLE will usually be true, but does not have to be. \n\"The story was CREDIBLE, so newspapers printed it; we then found out it was a practical joke.\" \nOther forms of the word: CREDIBILITY, n."
      },
      "LEGITIMATE": {
        "word": "LEGITIMATE",
        "phonetic": "(lÔøΩ-jit'-:)-mJt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "lawful; reasonable, proper, valid \nLEGITIMATE comes from the Latin word for _law_, also the source of the word _legal_. The basic meaning of LEGITIMATE is _lawful_. \n\"The court decided his claim was LEGITIMATE.\" \nThe word is now also used rather broadly to mean _reasonable_, _logical_, _justifiable_. \n\"He has a LEGITIMATE excuse for being absent\"—that is, his excuse makes sense, it is justified. \n\"This money should only be used for LEGITIMATE purposes.\" \n\"He had a LEGITIMATE reason to be upset with us.\""
      },
      "UNEARTH": {
        "word": "UNEARTH",
        "phonetic": "(uhn-erth')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to discover, uncover, find \nSee _un-_ under Prefixes. UNEARTH basically means \"to take the earth covering off something.\" In general use, UNEARTH means to _uncover_ or _discover_ something. \n\"The researcher UNEARTHED some new information about George Washington's career in the army.\" \n\"When tracing your family's history, you may UNEARTH embarrassing things about your ancestors.\" \n\"He UNEARTHED a plot to kill the judge.\""
      },
      "UNFURL": {
        "word": "UNFURL",
        "phonetic": "(uhn-ferl')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to open out, unroll, spread out \nUNFURL is used chiefly with flags, sails, and other large pieces of fabric. When you FURL a flag or sail, you roll it up. So to UNFURL a flag is to open it out or to spread it out. See _un-_ under Prefixes. \n\"For the holiday, all the flags were UNFURLED.\" \n\"In preparation for the journey, all the sails on the ship were UNFURLED and inspected for damage.\" \nOther forms of the word: FURL, v."
      },
      "PRIM": {
        "word": "PRIM",
        "phonetic": "(prim)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "neat, tidy, stiffly formal \nA PRIM person is overly neat in his appearance and overly proper in his behavior. The word usually suggests someone who dislikes anything rough or vulgar. It often suggests that this is a bad quality, that the person is too concerned about his appearance and too worried about improper behavior. \n\"The PRIM old lady was shocked by our ragged appearance.\" \n\"The PRIM gentleman never went out of the house without being perfectly dressed.\" \n\"She PRIMLY informed us that little boys were not allowed to sit on her nice clean chairs.\""
      },
      "HABITUAL": {
        "word": "HABITUAL",
        "phonetic": "(h:)-bich'-:)-wÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "regular, usual, customary \nA HABIT is a fixed way of doing something. \n\"He had a bad HABIT of talking with his mouth full.\" \nSomething which is HABITUAL results from HABIT, is usual or regular. See _-al_ under Suffixes. \n\"He took his HABITUAL walk after dinner.\" \n\"She drank her HABITUAL cup of coffee in the middle of the morning.\" \nHABITUAL is also used about people, and means \"acting by HABIT.\" \n\"Don't believe him; he's a HABITUAL liar.\" \n\"She's a HABITUAL latecomer; she never gets anywhere on time.\" \nOther forms of the word: HABIT, n."
      },
      "PUTRID": {
        "word": "PUTRID",
        "phonetic": "(pyU'-trid)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "rotten, decayed, very distasteful \nSomething that is PUTRID is in an advanced state of decay, so that it has a foul taste and smell. Food which is PUTRID is disgusting and distasteful. \n\"They refused to eat the fish because of its PUTRID smell.\" \n\"The meat had been left outside in the sun and turned PUTRID.\" \nOften PUTRID is simply used to mean _awful_, _terrible_, _vile_. \n\"Ed said the movie was PUTRID—one of the worst he had ever seen.\""
      },
      "PAGEANTRY": {
        "word": "PAGEANTRY",
        "phonetic": "(paj'-ÔøΩn-trE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "grand display, splendid spectacle \nA PAGEANT is a public show or spectacle, often involving colorful floats and costumes. PAGEANTRY is the colorful, splendid display of a PAGEANT. \n\"The crowning of a new king is always full of PAGEANTRY.\" \nPAGEANTRY is sometimes used in a bad sense, to suggest that there is nothing important beneath all the display and spectacle. \n\"The play had plenty of PAGEANTRY but little else.\" \nOther forms of the word: PAGEANT, n."
      },
      "HERALD": {
        "word": "HERALD",
        "phonetic": "(her'-ÔøΩld)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to announce, proclaim, give notice of \nA HERALD was a person who made public announcements for a king. From this the word has come to be used about any person or thing that announces or signals something that is to come. \n\"The clear sky in the distance was a HERALD of better weather in a few hours.\" \nTo HERALD something, therefore, is to give public notice that it is going to happen, to _announce_ it. You can HERALD something in other ways besides speaking. \n\"Thousands of posters throughout the town HERALDED the candidate's arrival.\" \n\"The appearance of the first robin HERALDED the arrival of spring.\""
      },
      "ENDORSE": {
        "word": "ENDORSE",
        "phonetic": "(en-dors')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to approve, support, vouch for, uphold \nThe _dorse_ part of the word comes from a Latin word for _back_; the word's basic meaning is \"to write on the back of\" something, particularly an official document or a business document. To ENDORSE a check is to write your name on the back of it in order to cash it. \nA common reason for ENDORSING a document was to indicate your approval of what was on the other side. This led to the general use of ENDORSE as a word meaning to _approve_ or _support_. \n\"We ENDORSE your position on taxes.\" \n\"Whom did they ENDORSE for president?\" \nThe sense of the word is that if you ENDORSE something, you would be willing to sign a statement that you approve of it. \nOther forms of the word: ENDORSEMENT, n."
      },
      "UPRISING": {
        "word": "UPRISING",
        "phonetic": "(uhp'-rl-zing)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a rebellion, revolt \nUPRISING is made up of the words _rising_ and _up_. An UPRISING is the rising up of people in a rebellion against their government. The word is often used about small, ineffective rebellions and also about the beginnings of widespread revolts. \n\"In the last five hundred years there have been several UPRISINGS of the Irish against English rule.\" \n\"The UPRISING against the government was quickly put down by the army.\" \n\"His kingdom was never totally peaceful; a small UPRISING was always taking place in one part or another.\" \nIn the Pretest, many people select _riot_ as the meaning of UPRISING. The two words are close in meaning. A _riot_ is any kind of public disorder by a group of people; an UPRISING is specifically aimed against the government or those in power."
      },
      "PROMINENT": {
        "word": "PROMINENT",
        "phonetic": "(prom'-ÔøΩnÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "easily seen, standing out; well-known, notable, distinguished \nThe basic meaning of PROMINENT is standing out, so as to be easily seen. See _pro-_ under Prefixes. \n\"The huge mountain is a PROMINENT landmark in the area.\" \n\"She has very PROMINENT cheekbones.\" \nWhen used about people, the word means _well-known_, _important_, usually in a good sense. \n\"He is one of the most PROMINENT citizens of this community.\" \n\"The town was shocked when two PROMINENT doctors were charged with murder.\" \n\"She played a PROMINENT part in producing the show.\" \nOther forms of the word: PROMINENCE, n."
      },
      "MIMIC": {
        "word": "MIMIC",
        "phonetic": "(mim'-ik)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to copy, imitate \nTo MIMIC someone is to copy his speech or movements, often with the intention of making fun of him. The word usually suggests a very exact copying. \n\"Sally MIMICKED the odd way her sister talked.\" \n\"The skillful actor could MIMIC any kind of character he chose.\" \nA MIMIC is a person who MIMICS. \n\"The clever MIMIC spoke and acted just like the famous politician.\" \nMany people think that to MIMIC someone is to _laugh at_ him, probably because MIMICKING often involves making fun of the person who is being MIMICKED."
      },
      "LUNACY": {
        "word": "LUNACY",
        "phonetic": "(IU'-nÔøΩsE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "insanity, madness \nLUNACY is from _luna_, the Latin word for the _moon_. It used to be thought that madness was related to the changes of the moon. Thus, LUNACY is another word for _madness_, particularly spells of madness that come and go. \n\"It was an act of LUNACY to go walking in the snowstorm without any clothes on.\" \n\"Usually he was quite reasonable, but he had moments of utter LUNACY.\" \nA LUNATIC is a crazy person, someone affected by LUNACY. \n\"Only a LUNATIC would burn down his own house.\" \nOther forms of the word: LUNATIC, n."
      },
      "ACCESSIBLE": {
        "word": "ACCESSIBLE",
        "phonetic": "(ak-ses'-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "approachable, easy to reach \nAnything you can reach, use, or visit is ACCESSIBLE. ACCESSIBLE usually suggests that it is not too difficult to get to the person or place it refers to. \n\"This store is easily ACCESSIBLE to people coming by car or bus.\" \n\"The boss was always ACCESSIBLE and ready to listen to complaints or new ideas.\" \n\"We are lucky to have the library so ACCESSIBLE to us; we don't have to walk far to exchange our books.\" \nThe opposite of ACCESSIBLE is INACCESSIBLE, which means \"out of reach.\" \n\"The librarian told her that the books were INACCESSIBLE because they were being recovered.\" \nOther forms of the word: ACCESS, n. INACCESSIBLE, adj."
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "ACCESSIBLE",
        "COMPOUND",
        "OBSTINATE",
        "PONDER",
        "TIMID",
        "ACKNOWLEDGE",
        "COURIER",
        "PAGEANTRY",
        "POPULACE",
        "UNEARTH",
        "BARREN",
        "INFECTIOUS",
        "PEDIGREE",
        "PROMINENT",
        "UNFURL",
        "BARTER",
        "LUNACY",
        "PERPLEX",
        "SCORN",
        "VELOCITY",
        "CLARITY",
        "APPOINT",
        "CONTRARY",
        "HABITUAL",
        "MIMIC",
        "REIMBURSE",
        "COINCIDE",
        "CREDIBLE",
        "HERALD",
        "MONUMENTAL",
        "REVISE",
        "COMPENSATE",
        "DUMBFOUNDED",
        "IMPARTIAL",
        "PRIM",
        "SPLINTER",
        "COMRADE",
        "ELEVATING",
        "INFORMAL",
        "PROVERB",
        "UPRISING",
        "CONDENSE",
        "ENDORSE",
        "LEGITIMATE",
        "PUTRID"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "The land was totally",
          "part2": "; farmers could not grow any crops there.",
          "answer": "barren"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He was rather",
          "part2": "about patting the huge dog, but finally he got up the courage to touch it.",
          "answer": "timid"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His",
          "part2": "increased as he went downhill until finally he was traveling at sixty miles an hour.",
          "answer": "velocity"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Ken",
          "part2": "the problem for an hour before he came up with a solution.",
          "answer": "pondered"
        },
        {
          "part1": "On Memorial Day he",
          "part2": "the flag and hung it in front of the house.",
          "answer": "unfurled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It is the most",
          "part2": "building in the city, rising twenty stories above the rest.",
          "answer": "prominent"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It was an act of",
          "part2": "for him to try to swim across the Pacific Ocean.",
          "answer": "lunacy"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Jim doesn't shop around for clothes; he goes to whatever store is most",
          "part2": "to him.",
          "answer": "accessible"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her happiness was",
          "part2": "; anyone who was with her just naturally started feeling happy, too.",
          "answer": "infectious"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Sheila",
          "part2": "people who go through life just trying to make money and never enjoying art or music.",
          "answer": "scorns"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He tried to",
          "part2": "some used clothing for a new TV, but the other fellow wouldn't agree.",
          "answer": "barter"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We were",
          "part2": "by the strange orders he gave us.",
          "answer": "perplexed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Looking through the microscope, we could see the tiny creatures with great",
          "part2": "",
          "answer": "clarity"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The entire",
          "part2": "gathered in the town square to hear the mayor's speech.",
          "answer": "populace"
        },
        {
          "part1": "What she felt was a(n)",
          "part2": "of fear, excitement, and fascination.",
          "answer": "compound"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Everyone was awed by the splendid",
          "part2": "of the princess's wedding.",
          "answer": "pageantry"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Susan is quite a(n)",
          "part2": "child; once she has made up her mind that she doesn't want to do something, no one can make her do it.",
          "answer": "obstinate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They sent a(n)",
          "part2": "to take the important documents to the ambassador.",
          "answer": "courier"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The coach",
          "part2": "that they had lost to the better team.",
          "answer": "acknowledged"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The dog's",
          "part2": "was exceptional; she came from a long line of champions.",
          "answer": "pedigree"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Scientists work hard and long seeking to",
          "part2": "the secrets of the universe.",
          "answer": "unearth"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her explanation was",
          "part2": ", so we believed her; it turned out, though, that she had lied.",
          "answer": "credible"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He has a high, squeaky laugh that is easy to",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "mimic"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We were",
          "part2": "when we discovered that the small painting was worth many thousands of dollars.",
          "answer": "dumbfounded"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It will just be a(n)",
          "part2": "get-together. You don't have to dress up or bring a present.",
          "answer": "informal"
        },
        {
          "part1": "",
          "part2": "to previous reports, no one died in the plane crash.",
          "answer": "contrary"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "lady always kept her house perfectly neat, and would never allow anyone to swear in her presence.",
          "answer": "prim"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The company refused to",
          "part2": "him for the trip because they said he took it for personal pleasure and not for business reasons.",
          "answer": "reimburse"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Bill tried to",
          "part2": "for his lack of experience by working harder.",
          "answer": "compensate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Not only did the doctors agree on the cause of the disease, but their ideas on how to treat it also",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "coincided"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Al tried to be",
          "part2": "but he found it difficult not to favor one side.",
          "answer": "impartial"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He felt that reaching the moon was a(n)",
          "part2": "achievement in human history.",
          "answer": "monumental"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We were so used to his",
          "part2": "lateness that we were surprised when he came early.",
          "answer": "habitual"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The food looked all right, but when he smelled it, it was completely",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "putrid"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I had to",
          "part2": "the report several times before it satisfied the teacher.",
          "answer": "revise"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The mayor",
          "part2": "him the new police commissioner.",
          "answer": "appointed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The board",
          "part2": "when he hit it with the ax.",
          "answer": "splintered"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The farmers started a(n)",
          "part2": "because they were dissatisfied with their government.",
          "answer": "uprising"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The pastor's sermons were",
          "part2": "; they were designed to uplift both our minds and our morals.",
          "answer": "elevating"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They were running out of time, so he had to",
          "part2": "his speech into a few brief remarks.",
          "answer": "condense"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The three of them have been close",
          "part2": "ever since they sat together in first grade.",
          "answer": "comrades"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Haven't you ever heard the",
          "part2": "\"The early bird catches the worm.\"?",
          "answer": "proverb"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The first flight of the Wright brothers",
          "part2": "the start of the air age.",
          "answer": "heralded"
        },
        {
          "part1": "What he did with the money was perfectly",
          "part2": ". After all, it's his money and he can do what he wants with it.",
          "answer": "legitimate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I'm sure everyone will wholeheartedly",
          "part2": "our idea of going to the beach.",
          "answer": "endorse"
        }
      ]
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.10",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Watched it ASCEND.",
          "answers": [
            "fall",
            "turn",
            "start",
            "rise",
            "stop"
          ],
          "word": "ASCEND",
          "correct": "rise"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OUTLANDISH clothing.",
          "answers": [
            "excellent",
            "colorful",
            "strange",
            "ragged",
            "usual"
          ],
          "word": "OUTLANDISH",
          "correct": "strange"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was UNCANNY.",
          "answers": [
            "weird",
            "sudden",
            "unknown",
            "typical",
            "wonderful"
          ],
          "word": "UNCANNY",
          "correct": "weird"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VIVID descriptions.",
          "answers": [
            "mistaken",
            "popular",
            "dull",
            "lively",
            "unbelievable"
          ],
          "word": "VIVID",
          "correct": "lively"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The contract was NULLIFIED.",
          "answers": [
            "changed",
            "made void",
            "made legal",
            "misunderstood",
            "approved"
          ],
          "word": "NULLIFY",
          "correct": "made void"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERSPERSED among them.",
          "answers": [
            "taken from",
            "lived",
            "scattered",
            "left",
            "joined"
          ],
          "word": "INTERSPERSE",
          "correct": "scattered"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Saw the FACSIMILE.",
          "answers": [
            "photograph",
            "copy",
            "book",
            "original",
            "plan"
          ],
          "word": "FACSIMILE",
          "correct": "copy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Think about the CONSEQUENCES.",
          "answers": [
            "problems",
            "effects",
            "decisions",
            "differences",
            "causes"
          ],
          "word": "CONSEQUENCE",
          "correct": "effects"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The CANINE family.",
          "answers": [
            "insect",
            "fish",
            "dog",
            "cat",
            "sheep"
          ],
          "word": "CANINE",
          "correct": "dog"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Unusually PLACID.",
          "answers": [
            "peaceful",
            "weak",
            "firm",
            "upset",
            "soft"
          ],
          "word": "PLACID",
          "correct": "peaceful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The year ELAPSED.",
          "answers": [
            "dragged on",
            "came",
            "raced by",
            "passed",
            "started"
          ],
          "word": "ELAPSE",
          "correct": "passed"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UPHOLD the decision.",
          "answers": [
            "put off",
            "oppose",
            "make",
            "change",
            "support"
          ],
          "word": "UPHOLD",
          "correct": "support"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were STRICKEN.",
          "answers": [
            "shot",
            "despised",
            "overcome",
            "taken",
            "trapped"
          ],
          "word": "STRICKEN",
          "correct": "overcome"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MONOTONOUS speech.",
          "answers": [
            "loud",
            "boring",
            "stupid",
            "exciting",
            "important"
          ],
          "word": "MONOTONOUS",
          "correct": "boring"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ELUDE them.",
          "answers": [
            "wait for",
            "find",
            "stop",
            "escape",
            "choose"
          ],
          "word": "ELUDE",
          "correct": "escape"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do you go higher as you ASCEND?",
          "word": "ASCEND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are OUTLANDISH ideas always wrong?",
          "word": "OUTLANDISH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a talking horse be UNCANNY?",
          "word": "UNCANNY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a VIVID story be dull to read?",
          "word": "VIVID",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can an agreement by NULLIFIED?",
          "word": "NULLIFY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you INTERSPERSE apples with oranges?",
          "word": "INTERSPERSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a FACSIMILE generally more valuable than an original?",
          "word": "FACSIMILE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is going to prison sometimes a CONSEQUENCE of committing a crime?",
          "word": "CONSEQUENCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a cocker spaniel a member of the CANINE family?",
          "word": "CANINE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do PLACID people get angry easily?",
          "word": "PLACID",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does it take a hundred years for a century to ELAPSE?",
          "word": "ELAPSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people like their decisions to be UPHELD?",
          "word": "UPHOLD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a grief-STRICKEN person be unhappy?",
          "word": "STRICKEN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would MONOTONOUS music be fascinating to listen to?",
          "word": "MONOTONOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Has a person in prison ELUDED punishment for his crime?",
          "word": "ELUDE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The airplane fell from the sky and ASCENDED to the ground.",
          "word": "ASCEND",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her OUTLANDISH methods of teaching constantly got her into trouble with the principal.",
          "word": "OUTLANDISH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She has an UNCANNY ability to predict the weather.",
          "word": "UNCANNY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I have a VIVID picture in my mind of exactly how the room is going to look.",
          "word": "VIVID",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The governor NULLIFIED the contract with the firm because they were cheating the state.",
          "word": "NULLIFY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His workday was INTERSPERSED with many chances to relax and regain his strength.",
          "word": "INTERSPERSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "John could produce a reasonably good FACSIMILE of George Washington's signature.",
          "word": "FACSIMILE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When the automobile was invented, no one realized the CONSEQUENCES it would have on the American way of life.",
          "word": "CONSEQUENCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We call them CANINE teeth because they resemble an elephant's tusks.",
          "word": "CANINE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She put a nice PLACID pillow beneath his head to make him more comfortable.",
          "word": "PLACID",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They ELAPSED the afternoon with friends on a picnic in the woods.",
          "word": "ELAPSE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The heavy rains UPHELD the game for over an hour.",
          "word": "UPHOLD",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The entire city was STRICKEN with the plague.",
          "word": "STRICKEN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She was very MONOTONOUS with the children—always telling them jokes and thinking up games for them to play.",
          "word": "MONOTONOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We ELUDED them by escaping through a secret passage.",
          "word": "ELUDE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "ASCEND",
          "answers": [
            "claw",
            "rise",
            "climb"
          ],
          "word": "ASCEND",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OUTLANDISH",
          "answers": [
            "weird",
            "bizarre",
            "wonderful"
          ],
          "word": "OUTLANDISH",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UNCANNY",
          "answers": [
            "mysterious",
            "frightening",
            "ancient"
          ],
          "word": "UNCANNY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VIVID",
          "answers": [
            "alive",
            "huge",
            "clear"
          ],
          "word": "VIVID",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NULLIFY",
          "answers": [
            "cancel",
            "consume",
            "negate"
          ],
          "word": "NULLIFY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERSPERSE",
          "answers": [
            "sprinkle",
            "discover",
            "strew"
          ],
          "word": "INTERSPERSE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FACSIMILE",
          "answers": [
            "copy",
            "reproduction",
            "factory"
          ],
          "word": "FACSIMILE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONSEQUENCE",
          "answers": [
            "result",
            "importance",
            "meaning"
          ],
          "word": "CONSEQUENCE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CANINE",
          "answers": [
            "sneering",
            "barking",
            "doglike"
          ],
          "word": "CANINE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PLACID",
          "answers": [
            "calm",
            "plump",
            "gentle"
          ],
          "word": "PLACID",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ELAPSE",
          "answers": [
            "miss",
            "pass",
            "go by"
          ],
          "word": "ELAPSE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UPHOLD",
          "answers": [
            "defend",
            "enjoy",
            "approve"
          ],
          "word": "UPHOLD",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STRICKEN",
          "answers": [
            "struck",
            "excited",
            "wounded"
          ],
          "word": "STRICKEN",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MONOTONOUS",
          "answers": [
            "evil",
            "dull",
            "constant"
          ],
          "word": "MONOTONOUS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ELUDE",
          "answers": [
            "evade",
            "avoid",
            "refuse"
          ],
          "word": "ELUDE",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "ASCEND": {
        "word": "ASCEND",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩsend')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to go up, rise, climb \nASCEND means simply to _go up_. \n\"The elevator ASCENDED to the top floor.\" \n\"They threw bags of sand out of the balloon to make it ASCEND.\" \n\"The soldier ASCENDED through the ranks until he became a general.\" \nMany people confuse ASCEND with its opposite _descend_, which means to _go down_. \n\"They ASCENDED the mountain in the morning, and descended it in the afternoon.\" \nOther forms of the word: ASCENT, n."
      },
      "OUTLANDISH": {
        "word": "OUTLANDISH",
        "phonetic": "(owt-lan'-dish)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "strange, bizarre, ridiculous \nSee _-ish_ under Suffixes. OUTLAND is a rare word for a foreign land or country—a land that is outside your own. Something that it OUTLANDISH has a foreign or unfamiliar appearance or quality. It is strange, bizarre, exotic. \n\"She dressed in OUTLANDISH clothing just to shock people.\" \n\"He had some OUTLANDISH ideas about flying saucers.\" \n\"They made some OUTLANDISH suggestions about how to improve television.\""
      },
      "UNCANNY": {
        "word": "UNCANNY",
        "phonetic": "(uhn-kan'-E)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "weird, strange, mysterious \nUNCANNY means _weird_ or _strange_. The word is applied to people, events, or feelings that are so beyond what is normal or expected that they make you feel frightened or uncomfortable. \n\"He has an UNCANNY way of knowing what you're thinking.\" \n\"That dog is so smart it's almost UNCANNY.\" \n\"We were frightened by the UNCANNY sounds.\""
      },
      "VIVID": {
        "word": "VIVID",
        "phonetic": "(viv'-id)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "lively, spirited, intense \nVIVID comes from a Latin word meaning to _live_, also the source of English words like _survive_ and _revive_. VIVID means \"full of life and freshness.\" The word is used about things, as well as about ideas, memories, imaginations, and the like. \n\"The picture is painted in sharp, VIVID colors that make a strong impression on the eye.\" \n\"After all these years her memories of her trip to Europe are still fresh and VIVID.\" \n\"The author wrote a VIVID account of the battle. You almost felt as if you were there.\" \n\"Little Billy has a VIVID imagination. He's always pretending to be a detective or an astronaut.\""
      },
      "NULLIFY": {
        "word": "NULLIFY",
        "phonetic": "(nuhl'-ÔøΩfl)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to make void, invalidate, negate See _-fy_ under Suffixes. The NULL part of the word means _nothing_. NULL is an adjective which means \"without value or effect.\" It is often used in the phrase \"NULL and void,\" which means \"having no legal force.\" \n\"The judges declared that the agreement was NULL and void.\" \nTo NULLIFY something is to make it as if it were nothing, to take away its force, value, or usefulness. \n\"The referee's decision NULLIFIED the touchdown.\" \n\"His refusal to let us finish NULLIFIED all our work for the past month. It's as if we'd never even begun.\" \nOther forms of the word: NULL, adj. NULLIFICATION, n."
      },
      "INTERSPERSE": {
        "word": "INTERSPERSE",
        "phonetic": "(in-t::lr-spers')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to scatter, place here and there \nSee _inter-_ under Prefixes. To INTERSPERSE things is to scatter or sprinkle them between or among other things. \n\"Some red balls were INTERSPERSED among the black ones.\" \n\"She INTERSPERSED some very funny jokes in an otherwise serious speech.\" \nIn a slightly different sense, to INTERSPERSE something _with_ other things is to supply it with these things here and there. \n\"He INTERSPERSED the black balls with some red ones.\" \n\"The book was INTERSPERSED with many beautiful pictures.\""
      },
      "FACSIMILE": {
        "word": "FACSIMILE",
        "phonetic": "(fak-sim'-ÔøΩIE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a copy, reproduction \nNote the pronunciation. The final _e_ is sounded. \nFACSIMILE is related to the word _similar_. Both come from a Latin word meaning _like_. A FACSIMILE is an exact, or almost exact, copy of a book, painting, letter, or the like. \n\"He printed a FACSIMILE of the Declaration of Independence that was identical in every detail with the original.\" \n\"She wore a dress that was a close FACSIMILE of an expensive Paris design.\" \nThe most common mistake on the Pretest is to choose _original_ as the meaning of FACSIMILE. This is a confusion of a word with its opposite. A FACSIMILE is made from an original, but it is not the original itself."
      },
      "CONSEQUENCE": {
        "word": "CONSEQUENCE",
        "phonetic": "(kon'-sÔøΩ-kwens)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an effect, result; importance, value \nA CONSEQUENCE is the effect or result of something that has gone before. \n\"His success was a direct CONSEQUENCE of his hard work.\" CONSEQUENCE often suggests a bad or undesired result. \n\"If you steal this, you'll have to accept the CONSEQUENCES when you are caught.\" \n\"He didn't consider all the CONSEQUENCES of his thoughtless behavior.\" \nIn a different sense, CONSEQUENCE means importance, particularly with regard to the results that may come about from something. \n\"His refusal to come was of no CONSEQUENCE. We had a good time anyway.\" \n\"She is a woman of great CONSEQUENCE in her community. Nothing is done without her approval.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONSEQUENTIAL, adj."
      },
      "CANINE": {
        "word": "CANINE",
        "phonetic": "(kA'-nln)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "of or relating to dogs \nCANINE means \"of or like a dog.\" \n\"A human's CANINE teeth are pointed, like a dog's teeth.\" \n\"He followed his older brother around all day with CANINE devotion\"—that is, he followed him like a dog following its master. CANINE is also a noun, meaning _dog_ or \"member of the dog family.\" \n\"Poodles, collies, and terriers are all CANINES.\" \n\"The fox is the only CANINE that can climb a tree.\" \nThe most popular wrong answer on the Pretest is _cat_. The word which means \"of or like a cat\" is _feline_, not CANINE."
      },
      "PLACID": {
        "word": "PLACID",
        "phonetic": "(plas'-ÔøΩd)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "peaceful, calm, tranquil \nPLACID means \"free from disturbance,\" _calm_, _untroubled_. \n\"Not the slightest ripple disturbed the PLACID surface of the lake.\" \nWhen used about people, PLACID means \"having a peaceful nature,\" and sometimes suggests a person who is _too_ calm and lacking in feeling. \n\"She was so PLACID that not even the roar of the jet planes bothered her.\" \n_Soft_ and _weak_ are both sometimes chosen as the meaning of PLACID. They are both close, but not quite the same as _peaceful_, _calm_, _untroubled_. They might be chosen because of a confusion of PLACID with _flaccid_, which means _weak_, _flabby_. \nOther forms of the word: PLACIDITY, n."
      },
      "ELAPSE": {
        "word": "ELAPSE",
        "phonetic": "(i-laps')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to pass, slip by, glide by \nELAPSE is almost always used about time. It means simply to _pass_, to _go by_. \n\"Twenty seconds ELAPSED between the two shots\"—that is, the shots came twenty seconds apart. \n\"He returned after six months had ELAPSED.\" \nELAPSE should not be confused with the similar verb _lapse_, which can be used about time, but it is more commonly used to mean \"to fall into error\" or \"to go out of existence.\" You can say \"The insurance policy _lapsed_\"; it doesn't make sense, however, to say \"The insurance policy ELAPSED.\""
      },
      "UPHOLD": {
        "word": "UPHOLD",
        "phonetic": "(uhp-hOld')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to support, approve \nUPHOLD is made up of the two words _hold_ and _up_. UPHOLD means just that: to _hold up_ or _support_. UPHOLD can be used about physical things like a roof, but it is generally used about ideas, decisions, or beliefs. \n\"The lower court's decision in the case was UPHELD by the higher court.\" \n\"He tried to UPHOLD his family's good reputation.\" \n\"I do not UPHOLD actions which are dangerous to oneself or others.\" \n_Put off_ is the most frequently marked wrong answer on the Pretest, probably because one meaning of _hold up_ is to _delay_."
      },
      "STRICKEN": {
        "word": "STRICKEN",
        "phonetic": "(strik'-ÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "wounded, afflicted, overcome \nSTRICKEN comes from the word _strike_. Someone who is STRICKEN with something has been _struck_ or _struck down_ by it. The word is usually used about illness, sorrow, misfortune, or the like. \n\"She was STRICKEN with a terrible disease.\" \n\"Several soldiers lay STRICKEN on the battlefield.\" \n\"After the flood the Red Cross aided the STRICKEN families.\" \n_Panic_-STRICKEN means \"overwhelmed with great fear.\" \n\"The _panic_-STRICKEN people fled from the huge monster.\" \nSTRICKEN is also used in other phrases like _conscience_-STRICKEN and _grief_-STRICKEN."
      },
      "MONOTONOUS": {
        "word": "MONOTONOUS",
        "phonetic": "(mÔøΩnot'-ÔøΩnÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "unchanging, boring, tedious, repetitious \nSee _-ous_ under Suffixes. The _mono_ part of MONOTONOUS comes from the Greek word for one. A _monologue_ is a speech for one person; a _monocle_ is an eyeglass worn in one eye only. The _ton_ part of the word comes from the word _tone_. Something that is MONOTONOUS has only one tone; it doesn't vary at all, and therefore it is boring and uninteresting. \n\"The scenery was rather MONOTONOUS; there was nothing but cornfields as far as you could see.\" \n\"The book was impressive at first, but after a while its heavy style became rather MONOTONOUS.\" \n\"She quickly became bored with the MONOTONOUS work on the assembly line in the factory.\" \nOther forms of the word: MONOTONY, n."
      },
      "ELUDE": {
        "word": "ELUDE",
        "phonetic": "(i-lUd')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to escape, evade, slip away, avoid \nTo ELUDE someone is to avoid or evade him, usually by means of cleverness or quickness. \n\"The criminal managed to ELUDE the police by hiding in the trunk of a car.\" \n\"The halfback ELUDED several tackles with his clever moves.\" \nThings or ideas can ELUDE you, usually by being very difficult or hard to see. \n\"The answer ELUDED Bob. No matter how hard he tried he couldn't quite think of it.\" \n\"The change she made in the room was so small that it ELUDED my notice.\" \nOther forms of the word: ELUSIVE, adj."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.11",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Take the INITIATIVE.",
          "answers": [
            "result",
            "position",
            "absolute power",
            "last move",
            "first step"
          ],
          "word": "INITIATIVE",
          "correct": "first step"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The rules were LAX.",
          "answers": [
            "written out",
            "not strict",
            "forgotten",
            "severe",
            "out-of-date"
          ],
          "word": "LAX",
          "correct": "not strict"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Quick RETORT.",
          "answers": [
            "question",
            "decision",
            "reply",
            "temper",
            "recovery"
          ],
          "word": "RETORT",
          "correct": "reply"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Found the SHACKLES.",
          "answers": [
            "whips",
            "boards",
            "blankets",
            "bandages",
            "chains"
          ],
          "word": "SHACKLE",
          "correct": "chains"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TRANSACT their business.",
          "answers": [
            "carry out",
            "change",
            "lie about",
            "draw",
            "forget about"
          ],
          "word": "TRANSACT",
          "correct": "carry out"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Usual ATTIRE.",
          "answers": [
            "relaxation",
            "clothing",
            "equipment",
            "appearance",
            "habit"
          ],
          "word": "ATTIRE",
          "correct": "clothing"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To COMPEL them.",
          "answers": [
            "need",
            "stop",
            "force",
            "want",
            "expect"
          ],
          "word": "COMPEL",
          "correct": "force"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXCRUCIATING moments.",
          "answers": [
            "annoying",
            "shameful",
            "boring",
            "pleasant",
            "agonizing"
          ],
          "word": "EXCRUCIATING",
          "correct": "agonizing"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FINITE resources.",
          "answers": [
            "small",
            "limited",
            "remarkable",
            "huge",
            "certain"
          ],
          "word": "FINITE",
          "correct": "limited"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was FUTILE.",
          "answers": [
            "harsh",
            "useless",
            "necessary",
            "dangerous",
            "lonely"
          ],
          "word": "FUTILE",
          "correct": "useless"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MUTINOUS behavior.",
          "answers": [
            "unusual",
            "angry",
            "obedient",
            "rebellious",
            "destructive"
          ],
          "word": "MUTINOUS",
          "correct": "rebellious"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUPERLATIVE achievement.",
          "answers": [
            "exciting",
            "doubtful",
            "supreme",
            "unexpected",
            "impossible"
          ],
          "word": "SUPERLATIVE",
          "correct": "supreme"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ATROCIOUS actors.",
          "answers": [
            "terrible",
            "unhappy",
            "remarkable",
            "angry",
            "young"
          ],
          "word": "ATROCIOUS",
          "correct": "terrible"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Completely CAMOUFLAGED.",
          "answers": [
            "revealed",
            "protected",
            "disguised",
            "changed",
            "spoiled"
          ],
          "word": "CAMOUFLAGE",
          "correct": "disguised"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ENLIGHTEN them.",
          "answers": [
            "amuse",
            "meet",
            "know",
            "inform",
            "change"
          ],
          "word": "ENLIGHTEN",
          "correct": "inform"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Would a lazy person be full of INITIATIVE?",
          "word": "INITIATIVE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a person who is LAX about his appearance probably look sloppy?",
          "word": "LAX",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are RETORTS usually polite?",
          "word": "RETORT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a dog be SHACKLED to a tree?",
          "word": "SHACKLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a TRANSACTION involve money?",
          "word": "TRANSACT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is your face part of your ATTIRE?",
          "word": "ATTIRE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a COMPELLING movie be dull?",
          "word": "COMPEL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is torture meant to cause EXCRUCIATING pain?",
          "word": "EXCRUCIATING",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a FINITE number of objects be counted?",
          "word": "FINITE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it FUTILE to try to change the past?",
          "word": "FUTILE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can only one person be MUTINOUS?",
          "word": "MUTINOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an A+ a SUPERLATIVE grade?",
          "word": "SUPERLATIVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it easy to get into a good college with ATROCIOUS grades in high school?",
          "word": "ATROCIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could dirt be used as CAMOUFLAGE?",
          "word": "CAMOUFLAGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would an ENLIGHTENED person be superstitious?",
          "word": "ENLIGHTEN",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "She called the meeting on her own INITIATIVE.",
          "word": "INITIATIVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She accused the babysitter of being LAX about getting the children to bed on time.",
          "word": "LAX",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bill RETORTED that he could beat Jim at chess any day.",
          "word": "RETORT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They lived in a small SHACKLE at the edge of town.",
          "word": "SHACKLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The movie star TRANSACTS in a new film this week.",
          "word": "TRANSACT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "What strange ATTIRE people wore to the costume party!",
          "word": "ATTIRE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He COMPELLED us that we stop talking, but we refused.",
          "word": "COMPEL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A sudden EXCRUCIATING pain in the side was the first sign that his appendix had burst.",
          "word": "EXCRUCIATING",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He has a FINITE amount of money; he could spend it forever and not run out.",
          "word": "FINITE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "This plan is rather FUTILE; I really think we can accomplish something with it.",
          "word": "FUTILE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The captain led a MUTINY against the brutal general.",
          "word": "MUTINOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "That was the worst movie I've seen in years; it was almost SUPERLATIVE.",
          "word": "SUPERLATIVE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He is an ATROCIOUS mayor; he hasn't done anything to make this a better city.",
          "word": "ATROCIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her heavy makeup CAMOUFLAGED the scars on her face.",
          "word": "CAMOUFLAGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They wanted to ENLIGHTEN people about the poor conditions in the prison.",
          "word": "ENLIGHTEN",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "INITIATIVE",
          "answers": [
            "beginning",
            "hope",
            "readiness"
          ],
          "word": "INITIATIVE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LAX",
          "answers": [
            "evil",
            "careless",
            "loose"
          ],
          "word": "LAX",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RETORT",
          "answers": [
            "reconsider",
            "respond",
            "reply"
          ],
          "word": "RETORT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHACKLE",
          "answers": [
            "glove",
            "chain",
            "handcuff"
          ],
          "word": "SHACKLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TRANSACT",
          "answers": [
            "negotiate",
            "win",
            "trade"
          ],
          "word": "TRANSACT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ATTIRE",
          "answers": [
            "dress",
            "sleep",
            "clothes"
          ],
          "word": "ATTIRE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMPEL",
          "answers": [
            "desire",
            "command",
            "push"
          ],
          "word": "COMPEL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXCRUCIATING",
          "answers": [
            "painful",
            "irritating",
            "torturous"
          ],
          "word": "EXCRUCIATING",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FINITE",
          "answers": [
            "limited",
            "tiny",
            "ending"
          ],
          "word": "FINITE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FUTILE",
          "answers": [
            "pointless",
            "nameless",
            "worthless"
          ],
          "word": "FUTILE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MUTINOUS",
          "answers": [
            "unruly",
            "rebellious",
            "miserable"
          ],
          "word": "MUTINOUS",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUPERLATIVE",
          "answers": [
            "great",
            "best",
            "impossible"
          ],
          "word": "SUPERLATIVE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ATROCIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "disgraceful",
            "unpleasant",
            "wicked"
          ],
          "word": "ATROCIOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CAMOUFLAGE",
          "answers": [
            "pretend",
            "hide",
            "lose"
          ],
          "word": "CAMOUFLAGE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENLIGHTEN",
          "answers": [
            "enjoy",
            "teach",
            "reveal"
          ],
          "word": "ENLIGHTEN",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "INITIATIVE": {
        "word": "INITIATIVE",
        "phonetic": "(i-nish'-ÔøΩtiv)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a first step, introductory action \nTo INITIATE something is to begin it, to set it in motion. An INITIATIVE is the first step or move designed to start a series of events. To do something \"on your own INITIATIVE\" means that you take this first step without being told to. To \"have the INITIATIVE\" means that you are in a position to take the first step. \nINITIATIVE is also used for the readiness and the ability to INITIATE actions or projects, particularly if they are difficult or dangerous. \n\"He was a man of great INITIATIVE. He saw what needed to be done and did it.\" \nOther forms of the word: INITIATE, v."
      },
      "LAX": {
        "word": "LAX",
        "phonetic": "(laks)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "not strict, loose, careless, negligent \nSomeone or something that is LAX is not strict or severe enough, is careless or negligent. \n\"He was very LAX about doing his homework on time.\" \n\"He got away with it because the rules were LAX.\" \nSometimes LAX is used in the sense of _loose_, \"not firm or tense.\" \n\"He had a very LAX handshake.\" \nThe noun from LAX is LAXITY. \n\"She blamed the increase in teenage crime on the LAXITY of modern parents.\" \nOther forms of the word: LAXITY, n."
      },
      "RETORT": {
        "word": "RETORT",
        "phonetic": "(ri-tort')",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a reply, sharp answer \nA RETORT is a sharp or witty answer to something that has just been said. \n\"He gave a quick RETORT to the fellow's insult.\" \n\"She couldn't think of a RETORT strong enough to show how angry she was.\" \n\"His clever RETORTS made people laugh, but also got him into trouble.\" \nRETORT is also a verb. \n\"'It's none of your business,' Jack RETORTED.\" \n\"He RETORTED that she had no one to blame but herself.\""
      },
      "SHACKLE": {
        "word": "SHACKLE",
        "phonetic": "(shak'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a chain, iron ring \nSHACKLES are _chains_ or _iron rings_ that are put around a person's arms or legs to keep him from moving. \n\"They kept the prisoner in SHACKLES.\" \nWhen SHACKLE is used as a verb, it means \"to put SHACKLES on,\" to _chain_. \n\"The convict was SHACKLED to a large post.\" \nSHACKLE is also used in a broader sense for anything that prevents freedom of thought, action, or progress. \n\"Unless you can throw off the SHACKLES of your ignorance you will never be successful.\" \nUsage: SHACKLE is usually used in the plural."
      },
      "TRANSACT": {
        "word": "TRANSACT",
        "phonetic": "(tran-sakt'",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to carry out, conduct \nTRANSACT means to _carry on_ or _do_. The word is usually used about business. \n\"They TRANSACTED all their business in the morning.\" \n\"It is impossible to TRANSACT business with a fool.\" \nTRANSACTION is the noun from TRANSACT. A TRANSACTION is a business deal. \n\"Many of the company's TRANSACTIONS are with foreign firms.\" \nIn the Pretest, _change_ is often chosen as the meaning of TRANSACT, perhaps because TRANSACT looks like _transform_, which means to _change_."
      },
      "ATTIRE": {
        "word": "ATTIRE",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩtl-ÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "clothing, clothes, dress \nATTIRE is another word for _clothing_, especially fancy or splendid clothing \n\"They were dressed in their best holiday ATTIRE.\" \n\"His dirty jersey and ragged pants were not proper ATTIRE for the restaurant.\" \nATTIRE is also a verb, meaning to _clothe_ or _dress_. \n\"For her wedding, she was ATTIRED all in white.\" \n_Appearance_ is often chosen as the meaning of ATTIRE. Your clothing is part of your appearance, but ATTIRE only has to do with your clothing, not your entire appearance. \nUsage: ATTIRE is a literary word, and would be used more often in writing than in speech."
      },
      "COMPEL": {
        "word": "COMPEL",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩm-pel')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to force \nTo COMPEL means to _force_. The word suggests strong pressure or authority being used on a person to do something. \n\"The blinding rain COMPELLED us to stop driving and pull over to the side of the road.\" \n\"His serious illness COMPELLED him to resign from his job.\" \n\"She felt COMPELLED to warn him of the danger involved in the experiment.\" \n\"Her brilliant play COMPELLED the crowd's attention.\" \nCOMPELLING is the adjective from COMPEL and means \"demanding attention, respect, or admiration.\" \n\"There are COMPELLING reasons why you must agree to the plan immediately.\" \n\"The novel was so COMPELLING that I was unable to put it down until I finished it.\" \nOther forms of the word: COMPELLING, adj."
      },
      "EXCRUCIATING": {
        "word": "EXCRUCIATING",
        "phonetic": "{ik-skrU'-shE-At-ing)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "agonizing, extremely painful \nEXCRUCIATING is related to the word _crucify_. EXCRUCIATING means _almost unbearably painful_, as if someone were driving nails through you. \n\"The pain from his broken shoulder was EXCRUCIATING for a couple of days until the bones began to heal.\" \n\"She suffered EXCRUCIATING embarrassment whenever she had to stand up and recite in front of the class.\" \n\"Sometimes I think nothing is more EXCRUCIATING than a toothache.\""
      },
      "FINITE": {
        "word": "FINITE",
        "phonetic": "(fl'-nlt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "limited, having boundaries \nFINITE comes from the same Latin word as _finish_ and _final_. All have to do with _ends_ or _ending_. FINITE means \"having an end,\" _limited_. \n\"We cannot keep paying them forever; we have only a FINITE amount of money.\" \nNote that this does not mean we have a small amount of money. It simply means that we don't have an unlimited amount of money. \n\"We should be able to find him; it's a big city, but the number of people in it is still FINITE.\" \nThe opposite of FINITE is INFINITE, _endless_, _unlimited_. See _in-2_ under Prefixes. \n\"We can do anything we want; the possibilities are INFINITE.\" \n\"Some people believe that the universe is INFINITE; others believe it is FINITE.\""
      },
      "FUTILE": {
        "word": "FUTILE",
        "phonetic": "(fyU'-tÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "useless, ineffective, fruitless \nFUTILE means _of no use_, _in vain_. An action or plan that is FUTILE cannot have the result that is hoped for. \n\"He made a FUTILE attempt to push the car by himself, then gave up.\" \n\"Realizing it was FUTILE to fight any longer, the enemy surrendered.\" \n\"It is FUTILE to argue with him. He never changes his mind.\" \nThe noun from FUTILE is FUTILITY, which means _uselessness_. \n\"Despite the FUTILITY of our actions, we kept trying to unlock the door.\" \n\"I explained to him the FUTILITY of trying to start a fire with wet matches.\" \nOther forms of the word: FUTILITY, n."
      },
      "MUTINOUS": {
        "word": "MUTINOUS",
        "phonetic": "(myU'-tÔøΩnÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "rebellious, ready to revolt, difficult to control \nA MUTINY is a rebellion or revolt against people in authority. The word is particularly applied to soldiers or sailors who turn against their officers. MUTINOUS is the adjective from MUTINY. See _-ous_ under Suffixes. Someone who is MUTINOUS is rebelling, or is ready to rebel, against the orders of his superiors. \n\"The soldiers became MUTINOUS over the rotten food they were forced to eat.\" \nMUTINOUS is also used in a broader sense to mean \"difficult to control,\" _unruly_. \n\"The teacher found it impossible to get the MUTINOUS child to sit still and stop pestering everyone.\" \nOther forms of the word: MUTINY, n."
      },
      "SUPERLATIVE": {
        "word": "SUPERLATIVE",
        "phonetic": "(sU-per'-1ÔøΩ-tiv)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "supreme, excellent \nSee _super-_ under Prefixes. Something which is SUPERLATIVE is of the highest quality; it is extremely great or excellent. \n\"It was a SUPERLATIVE dinner. It may have been the best I have ever had.\" \n\"Her SUPERLATIVE paintings have won many prizes.\" \n\"We thought it had been a SUPERLATIVE achievement to finish the job on time.\""
      },
      "ATROCIOUS": {
        "word": "ATROCIOUS",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩtrO'-shÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "terrible, dreadful, wicked, cruel \nATROCIOUS means _extremely wicked_ or _barbaric_. \n\"Everyone was shocked by the ATROCIOUS crime.\" \n\"The company treated its workers ATROCIOUSLY—the conditions in the factory were almost inhuman.\" \nIn a slightly different sense, ATROCIOUS also means _extremely bad_, _awful_. \n\"The movie was simply ATROCIOUS—I left after ten minutes.\" \n\"He made an ATROCIOUS error that cost the company millions.\" \nThe most commonly selected incorrect answer is _remarkable_. This may be due to confusion with the word _precocious_. _Precocious_ means \"having a talent which usually appears in an older person.\" A _precocious_ child would be remarkable; he wouldn't usually be ATROCIOUS. \nOther forms of the word: ATROCITY, n."
      },
      "CAMOUFLAGE": {
        "word": "CAMOUFLAGE",
        "phonetic": "(kam'-ÔøΩflahzh)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to disguise, mask, conceal \nCAMOUFLAGE is both a verb and a noun. In the military, CAMOUFLAGE is the use of paint, tree branches, netting, or other materials to give a false appearance to something like a tank or a gun position. Thus, to CAMOUFLAGE something is to disguise it in order to hide it or to deceive someone. \n\"The color of many animals is a natural CAMOUFLAGE that keeps larger animals from seeing them.\" \n\"His constant smile CAMOUFLAGED his real feelings.\""
      },
      "ENLIGHTEN": {
        "word": "ENLIGHTEN",
        "phonetic": "(in-llt'-ÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to inform, instruct \nThe original meaning of ENLIGHTEN was \"to supply with light.\" Now the word is only used in the sense \"to give knowledge\"—that is, to free someone from the \"darkness\" of misunderstanding or ignorance. \n\"I know nothing about his background. Could you ENLIGHTEN me?\" \n\"We tried to ENLIGHTEN him as to the nature of the problem, but he wouldn't listen.\" \nSomeone who is ENLIGHTENED is free from ignorance and superstition. \n\"The boss took a very ENLIGHTENED approach in dealing with his workers. He treated them as equals and never threatened them.\" \nThe most commonly selected incorrect answer is _amuse_, possibly because the _light_ part of ENLIGHTEN is thought to mean _not serious_. \nOther forms of the word: ENLIGHTENED, adj. ENLIGHTENMENT, n."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "4.12",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Knew the ARISTOCRACY.",
          "answers": [
            "church",
            "nobility",
            "magicians",
            "peasants",
            "businessmen"
          ],
          "word": "ARISTOCRACY",
          "correct": "nobility"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Strange LUSTER.",
          "answers": [
            "appearance",
            "shape",
            "smoothness",
            "warmth",
            "brightness"
          ],
          "word": "LUSTER",
          "correct": "brightness"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Who will SUPERINTEND them?",
          "answers": [
            "manage",
            "protect",
            "expect",
            "obey",
            "improve"
          ],
          "word": "SUPERINTEND",
          "correct": "manage"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Great ZEAL.",
          "answers": [
            "pity",
            "confidence",
            "eagerness",
            "importance",
            "hope"
          ],
          "word": "ZEAL",
          "correct": "eagerness"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHIRK responsibility.",
          "answers": [
            "seek",
            "laugh at",
            "avoid",
            "lose",
            "hate"
          ],
          "word": "SHIRK",
          "correct": "avoid"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Unusual COMPASSION.",
          "answers": [
            "game",
            "payment",
            "pity",
            "sickness",
            "pride"
          ],
          "word": "COMPASSION",
          "correct": "pity"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Inclined to RAMBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "return",
            "shake",
            "fall",
            "rush",
            "wander"
          ],
          "word": "RAMBLE",
          "correct": "wander"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Surprised by the STENCH.",
          "answers": [
            "mess",
            "stink",
            "dust",
            "noise",
            "heat"
          ],
          "word": "STENCH",
          "correct": "stink"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Great REMORSE.",
          "answers": [
            "ability",
            "pleasure",
            "hatred",
            "regret",
            "anger"
          ],
          "word": "REMORSE",
          "correct": "regret"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "New FORMAT.",
          "answers": [
            "covering",
            "arrangement",
            "contents",
            "idea",
            "requirement"
          ],
          "word": "FORMAT",
          "correct": "arrangement"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Inaccurate CHRONOLOGY.",
          "answers": [
            "measurement",
            "time order",
            "land survey",
            "color chart",
            "clock"
          ],
          "word": "CHRONOLOGY",
          "correct": "time order"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was FEASIBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "laughable",
            "visible",
            "difficult",
            "necessary",
            "possible"
          ],
          "word": "FEASIBLE",
          "correct": "possible"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His INTELLECT.",
          "answers": [
            "belief",
            "speech",
            "feelings",
            "mind",
            "memory"
          ],
          "word": "INTELLECT",
          "correct": "mind"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We will PREVAIL.",
          "answers": [
            "help",
            "continue",
            "triumph",
            "increase",
            "finish"
          ],
          "word": "PREVAIL",
          "correct": "triumph"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Very SHREWD.",
          "answers": [
            "foolish",
            "unpleasant",
            "unhappy",
            "clever",
            "handsome"
          ],
          "word": "SHREWD",
          "correct": "clever"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Would a duke belong to the ARISTOCRACY?",
          "word": "ARISTOCRACY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does polishing spoons give them LUSTER?",
          "word": "LUSTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a school SUPERINTENDENT be in charge of schools?",
          "word": "SUPERINTEND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a ZEALOUS worker likely to be fired?",
          "word": "ZEAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a SHIRKER a good person to work with?",
          "word": "SHIRK",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are COMPASSIONATE people likely to feel sorry for those who are not as lucky as they are?",
          "word": "COMPASSION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are speakers who RAMBLE usually interesting to listen to?",
          "word": "RAMBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do roses have a STENCH?",
          "word": "STENCH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should a person feel REMORSE for stealing money?",
          "word": "REMORSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do magazines have different FORMATS?",
          "word": "FORMAT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there a CHRONOLOGY to the events of your life?",
          "word": "CHRONOLOGY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it FEASIBLE to play football and read at the same time?",
          "word": "FEASIBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you use your INTELLECT when you take a test?",
          "word": "INTELLECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does the better team always PREVAIL?",
          "word": "PREVAIL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are only evil people SHREWD?",
          "word": "SHREWD",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He started out as a poor farmer, but when he died he was a member of the ARISTOCRACY.",
          "word": "ARISTOCRACY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His drunken behavior took away from the LUSTER of the event.",
          "word": "LUSTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Dave SUPERINTENDED to go to the party, but he just couldn't make it.",
          "word": "SUPERINTEND",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her ZEAL for doing good works made everyone admire her.",
          "word": "ZEAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He tried to SHIRK the blame for the disaster, but we wouldn't let him.",
          "word": "SHIRK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He had a COMPASSION for tennis. He would play it all day if he could.",
          "word": "COMPASSION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She RAMBLED quickly and directly to her destination.",
          "word": "RAMBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The STENCH of garlic on his breath was overwhelming.",
          "word": "STENCH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone felt genuine REMORSE and satisfaction when we finally won the championship.",
          "word": "REMORSE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When the new editor took over, he changed the FORMAT of the newspaper.",
          "word": "FORMAT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She used the dates at the top to arrange the letters in CHRONOLOGICAL order.",
          "word": "CHRONOLOGY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She was a very FEASIBLE woman; she inherited a lot of money when she was young.",
          "word": "FEASIBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The president called in several great INTELLECTS to advise him.",
          "word": "INTELLECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We PREVAILED on him to say a few words to the class.",
          "word": "PREVAIL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SHREWDLY hinted that if we didn't want the house, there were plenty of other people who did.",
          "word": "SHREWD",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "ARISTOCRACY",
          "answers": [
            "nobility",
            "populace",
            "upper class"
          ],
          "word": "ARISTOCRACY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LUSTER",
          "answers": [
            "light",
            "happiness",
            "glory"
          ],
          "word": "LUSTER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUPERINTEND",
          "answers": [
            "supervise",
            "oversee",
            "help"
          ],
          "word": "SUPERINTEND",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ZEAL",
          "answers": [
            "enthusiasm",
            "devotion",
            "interest"
          ],
          "word": "ZEAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHIRK",
          "answers": [
            "avoid",
            "dodge",
            "enjoy"
          ],
          "word": "SHIRK",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMPASSION",
          "answers": [
            "knowledge",
            "sympathy",
            "understanding"
          ],
          "word": "COMPASSION",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RAMBLE",
          "answers": [
            "disappear",
            "roam",
            "stray"
          ],
          "word": "RAMBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STENCH",
          "answers": [
            "taste",
            "smell",
            "odor"
          ],
          "word": "STENCH",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REMORSE",
          "answers": [
            "guilt",
            "fear",
            "sorrow"
          ],
          "word": "REMORSE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FORMAT",
          "answers": [
            "appearance",
            "arrangement",
            "explanation"
          ],
          "word": "FORMAT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CHRONOLOGY",
          "answers": [
            "series",
            "time",
            "memory"
          ],
          "word": "CHRONOLOGY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FEASIBLE",
          "answers": [
            "reliable",
            "possible",
            "suitable"
          ],
          "word": "FEASIBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTELLECT",
          "answers": [
            "cleverness",
            "logic",
            "anger"
          ],
          "word": "INTELLECT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PREVAIL",
          "answers": [
            "persuade",
            "decide",
            "win"
          ],
          "word": "PREVAIL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHREWD",
          "answers": [
            "holy",
            "tricky",
            "smart"
          ],
          "word": "SHREWD",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "ARISTOCRACY": {
        "word": "ARISTOCRACY",
        "phonetic": "(ar-ÔøΩstok'-rÔøΩsE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "the nobility, upper class \nARISTOCRACY comes from Greek words meaning \"rule by the best.\" The basic meaning of ARISTOCRACY is \"a form of government in which the best people rule.\" In common use the word refers to the highest social class of a country, the noble families who are accustomed to ruling and having power. \n\"As members of the ARISTOCRACY, the noblemen were entitled to many things that the common people could not have.\" \n\"The United States has never had an ARISTOCRACY or ruling class.\" \nOther forms of the word: ARISTOCRAT, n. ARISTOCRATIC, adj."
      },
      "LUSTER": {
        "word": "LUSTER",
        "phonetic": "(luhs'-tar)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "brightness, sheen; brilliance, glory \nLUSTER is the soft glow of light reflected off a polished surface. \n\"She rubbed the table with a special oil to increase its LUSTER.\" \nFrom this, LUSTER has come to mean _brightness_ in the sense of _glory_, _brilliance_, _distinction_. \n\"The mere presence of the famous woman added LUSTER to the occasion.\" \n\"This act of heroism added further LUSTER to his already great reputation.\" \nOther forms of the word: LUSTROUS, adj."
      },
      "SUPERINTEND": {
        "word": "SUPERINTEND",
        "phonetic": "(sU-pÔøΩr-in-tend'",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to manage, oversee, look after \nTo SUPERINTEND something is to have charge of it, to supervise the management of it. \n\"He was chosen to SUPERINTEND the running of the store.\" \n\"There was only one person to SUPERINTEND the entire building.\" \nA SUPERINTENDENT is a person who manages something like a building or a school. \n\"If your heat goes off, call the building's SUPERINTENDENT immediately.\" \nOther forms of the word: SUPERINTENDENT, n."
      },
      "ZEAL": {
        "word": "ZEAL",
        "phonetic": "(zEI)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "eagerness, passion, enthusiasm \nZEAL is eager devotion to a cause, religion, idea, or the like. \n\"Despite the ZEAL of his supporters he lost the election.\" \n\"His ZEAL for teaching young children is unmatched.\" \n\"In his ZEAL to improve humanity he sometimes goes too far and offends people.\" \nSomeone who feels a great deal of ZEAL for a cause or goal is ZEALOUS. \n\"Jane is a ZEALOUS defender of the rights of poor people.\" \n\"The policemen were ZEALOUS in enforcing the new law.\" \nOther forms of the word: ZEALOT, n. ZEALOUS, adj."
      },
      "SHIRK": {
        "word": "SHIRK",
        "phonetic": "(sherk)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to avoid, dodge \nSHIRK means \"to try to escape from doing\" something, usually because of laziness, fear, or simple dislike of the work to be done. \n\"He would like to SHIRK his homework, but he knows he has to do it.\" \n\"I cannot SHIRK the responsibility for my mistake.\" \nA person who is lazy and tries to avoid doing a fair share of the work is called a SHIRKER. \n\"SHIRKERS always try to get somebody else to do their work for them.\" \nOther forms of the word: SHIRKER, n."
      },
      "COMPASSION": {
        "word": "COMPASSION",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩm-pash'-:m)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "pity, sympathy \nCOMPASSION is a feeling of pity. If you have COMPASSION, you understand and share in the suffering or pain which someone else feels. \n\"She had COMPASSION for suffering animals, so people brought her their sick and unwanted cats and dogs.\" \n\"He gave the beggar a quarter, not out of COMPASSION, but simply to get rid of him.\" \nSomeone who feels COMPASSION is COMPASSIONATE. \n\"William gave Sally a COMPASSIONATE glance when her mother scolded her for being late again.\" \nOther forms of the word: COMPASSIONATE, adj."
      },
      "RAMBLE": {
        "word": "RAMBLE",
        "phonetic": "(ram'-bÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to wander, roam \nTo RAMBLE is to wander about, to go from place to place, without any special aim. \n\"They RAMBLED across the countryside, stopping whenever they liked.\" \nThe word is often applied to talking and writing that goes on and on without any point. \n\"He had a tendency to RAMBLE when he talked. He just couldn't stick to the subject.\" \n\"She RAMBLED on about her garden until everyone had fallen asleep.\""
      },
      "STENCH": {
        "word": "STENCH",
        "phonetic": "(stench)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a stink, foul odor \nA STENCH is a strong, foul odor, like the odor of something rotting. \n\"The meat created quite a STENCH after it was left out in the hot sun all day.\" \n\"No one could stand the STENCH of the tobacco he used in his pipe.\""
      },
      "REMORSE": {
        "word": "REMORSE",
        "phonetic": "(ri-mors')",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "regret, repentance \nREMORSE is deep, bitter guilt and sorrow for having done wrong. It comes from a Latin word meaning \"to bite again\" and suggests a guilty feeling that is gnawing away at your conscience. \n\"I immediately felt REMORSE for having yelled at her.\" \n\"The criminal showed no REMORSE for the murder.\" \n\"Their REMORSE didn't seem genuine. I don't think they're a bit sorry.\" \nOther forms of the word: REMORSEFUL, adj. REMORSELESS, adj."
      },
      "FORMAT": {
        "word": "FORMAT",
        "phonetic": "(for'-mat)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "arrangement \nFORMAT is related to the word _form_. The FORMAT is the general physical arrangement of something, particularly of a book or magazine. \n\"They changed the FORMAT of the magazine so that it was bigger and had more pictures.\" \n\"They hoped the new FORMAT of the books would make them easier to read.\" \nThe word can also be used about other kinds of arrangements, like that of a television show. \n\"The idea behind the show is good, but the FORMAT is all wrong.\""
      },
      "CHRONOLOGY": {
        "word": "CHRONOLOGY",
        "phonetic": "(krÔøΩnol'-ÔøΩjE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "time order \nThe _chron_ part of CHRONOLOGY means _time_. It is found in the word _chronograph_ (a stop watch), as well as in the words _chronic_ and _chronicle_. A CHRONOLOGY is the order in which a particular series of events occurred. \n\"The detective tried to establish the CHRONOLOGY of the events that led up to the murder.\" \nA CHRONOLOGY is also a table or list which organizes things according to the time at which they occurred. Finally, CHRONOLOGY is the science that tries to establish accurate dates for past events. \nCHRONOLOGICAL is the adjective from CHRONOLOGY. To put things \"in CHRONOLOGICAL order\" is to arrange them in the order of their time. \n\"He listed Shakespeare's plays in CHRONOLOGICAL order.\" \nOther forms of the word: CHRONOLOGICAL, adj."
      },
      "FEASIBLE": {
        "word": "FEASIBLE",
        "phonetic": "(fE'-zÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "possible, practicable; likely; suitable Something which is FEASIBLE is able to be done, is possible. \n\"It was hardly a FEASIBLE plan, considering the costs involved.\" \n\"The most FEASIBLE solution is not necessarily the fairest one.\" \nFEASIBLE is also sometimes used to mean _logical_ or _likely_. \n\"His excuse seemed FEASIBLE enough.\" \nThe word can also mean \"capable of being dealt with successfully,\" _suitable_. \n\"They chose the most FEASIBLE route they could find for the new road.\" \n\"Is sunlight a FEASIBLE source of energy?\" \nOther forms of the word: FEASIBILITY, n."
      },
      "INTELLECT": {
        "word": "INTELLECT",
        "phonetic": "(in'-tÔøΩlekt)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "mind, understanding, reasoning \nINTELLECT is related to the word _intelligent_. The INTELLECT is the reasoning power of the mind, as opposed to its feelings and instincts. \n\"He has a great INTELLECT, but he's not a very pleasant person to know.\" \n\"My INTELLECT tells me that this is the right decision, but I wish it could be otherwise.\" \nINTELLECT is also used to mean \"a person with great reasoning powers.\" \n\"The finest INTELLECTS in the country were present at the conference.\" \nINTELLECTUAL is an adjective formed from INTELLECT. It means \"having to do with the INTELLECT.\" \n\"He preferred INTELLECTUAL pursuits, such as reading and chess, to sports.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTELLECTUAL, adj., n."
      },
      "PREVAIL": {
        "word": "PREVAIL",
        "phonetic": "(pri-vAI')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to win, triumph; to be widespread; to persuade \nTo PREVAIL _over_ or _against_ means to _win_ or _gain victory_. \n\"We PREVAILED over our enemies.\" \nSometimes the word is used without _over_ or _against_. \n\" 'Justice will PREVAIL' means that justice will finally win out.\" \nPREVAIL can also mean \"to be common or widespread.\" \n\"After weeks of rioting, a feeling of calm now PREVAILS in the city.\" \nTo PREVAIL _on_ or _upon_ someone is to persuade him, often with some difficulty. \n\"We finally PREVAILED upon him to tell us the secret.\" \n\"She PREVAILED on her father to let her use the car.\" \nOther forms of the word: PREVAILING, adj. PREVALENT, adj."
      },
      "SHREWD": {
        "word": "SHREWD",
        "phonetic": "(shrUd)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "clever, keen, astute \nA SHREWD person has a great deal of cleverness and sound judgment, especially in practical matters. \n\"He's a SHREWD judge of talent. He rarely makes a mistake about actors.\" \n\"Several SHREWD businessmen bought all the land before oil was discovered there.\" \nSHREWD often contains a sense of trickiness in its meaning. \n\"The SHREWD salesman knew just how to get people to buy the worthless stock.\" \nPeople often think SHREWD means _unpleasant_, possibly because SHREWD is often used in a negative way about people who are tricky or dishonest. SHREWD might also be confused with the word _shrew_, which means \"a bad-tempered woman.\""
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "ARISTOCRACY",
        "ELAPSE",
        "FINITE",
        "NULLIFY",
        "SHACKLE",
        "ATROCIOUS",
        "ENLIGHTEN",
        "FORMAT",
        "PLACID",
        "SUPERINTEND",
        "CAMOUFLAGE",
        "EXCRUCIATING",
        "MONOTONOUS",
        "PREVAIL",
        "UNCANNY",
        "CANINE",
        "FEASIBLE",
        "MUTINOUS",
        "RAMBLE",
        "VIVID",
        "COMPASSION",
        "ASCEND",
        "ELUDE",
        "INTERSPERSE",
        "RETORT",
        "SUPERLATIVE",
        "ATTIRE",
        "FACSIMILE",
        "LAX",
        "SHIRK",
        "TRANSACT",
        "CHRONOLOGY",
        "FUTILE",
        "LUSTER",
        "SHREWD",
        "UPHOLD",
        "COMPEL",
        "INITIATIVE",
        "OUTLANDISH",
        "STENCH",
        "ZEAL",
        "CONSEQUENCE",
        "INTELLECT",
        "REMORSE",
        "STRICKEN"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "The number of problems is large but",
          "part2": "; I'm sure we can solve them all.",
          "answer": "finite"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They covered the guns with tree branches in order to",
          "part2": "them from the enemy.",
          "answer": "camouflage"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The sailors were angry about the conditions, but they weren't",
          "part2": "; they still obeyed their captain.",
          "answer": "mutinous"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It's",
          "part2": "how he can do such a good imitation of his father's voice on the phone.",
          "answer": "uncanny"
        },
        {
          "part1": "To show off his knowledge, he took down the sign which said \"Beware of the dog\" and replaced it with one which said \"Beware of the",
          "part2": ".\"",
          "answer": "canine"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He was usually quite",
          "part2": ", except when someone insulted his school. Then he would get so angry people had to restrain him.",
          "answer": "placid"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "of the show was simple: the host sat and talked with his guests.",
          "answer": "format"
        },
        {
          "part1": "After a long match, Smith finally",
          "part2": "over Jones.",
          "answer": "prevailed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Susan felt a great deal of",
          "part2": "for her sister, because she had once had the same problems.",
          "answer": "compassion"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The most",
          "part2": "solution to the problem will be the one that costs least.",
          "answer": "feasible"
        },
        {
          "part1": "You didn't have to be rich to be a member of the",
          "part2": "; you just had to be born of noble parents.",
          "answer": "aristocracy"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The prisoner broke his",
          "part2": "with a rock and tried to escape.",
          "answer": "shackles"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The students asked the teacher to",
          "part2": "them as to the meaning of that word.",
          "answer": "enlighten"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She turned and twisted trying to find some position which would ease the",
          "part2": "pain in her back.",
          "answer": "excruciating"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The decision to award Jim the prize was",
          "part2": "when they found out that he hadn't obeyed the rules.",
          "answer": "nullified"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Several years",
          "part2": "before I saw my friend again.",
          "answer": "elapsed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The characters in the novel were so",
          "part2": "that we thought of them as real people.",
          "answer": "vivid"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Because the man was known to be cruel and vicious, it was easy to believe that he was guilty of the",
          "part2": "crime.",
          "answer": "atrocious"
        },
        {
          "part1": "To make sure that nothing went wrong he",
          "part2": "every phase of the project himself.",
          "answer": "superintended"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The dog was trained to keep the sheep from",
          "part2": "too far away.",
          "answer": "rambling"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It was a very",
          "part2": "speech. He just said the same thing over and over again in slightly different ways.",
          "answer": "monotonous"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The thieves were able to",
          "part2": "the police by using clever disguises.",
          "answer": "elude"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The coach was impressed by the",
          "part2": "Tim showed in practice; he was certainly the most enthusiastic player on the field.",
          "answer": "zeal"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We cleaned the freezer after it broke down, but we couldn't get rid of the",
          "part2": "left by food that had rotted.",
          "answer": "stench"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The difficult problem presented quite a challenge to his",
          "part2": ", but he was finally able to solve it.",
          "answer": "intellect"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We have to",
          "part2": "some business at the bank; then we'll be free for the rest of the day.",
          "answer": "transact"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He wore his usual",
          "part2": "—a brown suit with a white shirt and a plaid tie.",
          "answer": "attire"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His attempt to stop them from arguing was",
          "part2": "; he might just as well have tried to keep the sun from coming up in the morning.",
          "answer": "futile"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The submarine began to",
          "part2": "from the ocean floor.",
          "answer": "ascend"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She",
          "part2": "several tiny angels among the decorations already on the Christmas tree.",
          "answer": "interspersed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her improved grades were the",
          "part2": "of better study habits.",
          "answer": "consequence"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The principal",
          "part2": "the teacher's right to keep a student after school, saying it was necessary for good discipline.",
          "answer": "upheld"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Although she was",
          "part2": "with terror, she managed to call for help.",
          "answer": "stricken"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Some people are not content with the way things are, but they lack the",
          "part2": "to try to change them.",
          "answer": "initiative"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Dave couldn't think of any clever",
          "part2": "to the man's remark.",
          "answer": "retort"
        },
        {
          "part1": "This is a very dangerous experiment; we cannot afford to be",
          "part2": "about following the rules for safety.",
          "answer": "lax"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "of his reputation was dimmed somewhat by the evidence that he had lied.",
          "answer": "luster"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He felt no",
          "part2": "for having committed the crime. He was only sorry that he got caught.",
          "answer": "remorse"
        },
        {
          "part1": "So much has happened that it is difficult to remember the exact",
          "part2": "of events.",
          "answer": "chronology"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "investor knew just when to buy stock and just when to sell it.",
          "answer": "shrewd"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Hunger",
          "part2": "us to stop and look for a place to buy some food.",
          "answer": "compelled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The actor won the Academy Award for his",
          "part2": "performance.",
          "answer": "superlative"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He said the most",
          "part2": "things just so people would notice him.",
          "answer": "outlandish"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The talented student produced a very good",
          "part2": "of the Rembrandt painting.",
          "answer": "facsimile"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He didn't want to",
          "part2": "his duty, but he was just too busy to do it.",
          "answer": "shirk"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
]